Thank you for your call, Lorraine.
And before the commercial break,
Roz has an important message. Roz?
What? Can't come to the mic?
Well, what she wanted to say was...
Tomorrow, on Amber Edwards'
''Bookchat'',
sociologist Lamont Myman
discusses his book,
''Violence in the Workplace -
Why Co-Workers Kill''.
Something which becomes
more and more relevant.
We'll be right back.
Open up, you piece of tin!
- Roz!
- What are you doing here?
And you? Shouldn't you wait
till after the show before exiting?
- l have a little urge. Damn it!
- What is the matter?
l have got to have chocolate!
lt's kind of a celebration.
At 1 1 :07 am, l finished
one of those magazine diets.
''Seven days
to a healthier, calmer you.''
Come on, Roz!
l'm doing this for your own good.
Wait!
Something came out!
Damn! Chocolate-covered raisins.
l'd like to meet the idiot
who came up with these.
Take a grape, let it shrivel
into a disgusting little wart
and cover it
with perfectly good chocolate.
What the hell!
l'll suck the chocolate off.
Be sure to save what's left
to make some wine!
l see those years of finishing school
paid off.
Mon frère, we're in luck.
(High-pitched electronic beep)
Meadow Wood Properties still has
one share left in the mini-mall.
- We should buy it. Give me five, Bro.
- l told you l'm not interested.
lt's a 1 2%%% return.
We've a chance to make a real killing.
You and Maris are wallowing in money
like a couple of yuppie hogs.
This has nothing to do with Maris.
This is my money.
- And mine.
- And yours.
Show some understanding. Maris
uses her money to emasculate him.
This is his attempt to stop feeling
like a financial eunuch
and regain some shred of his
former manhood - such as it was.
Well?
- 1 2%%%?
- Net.
lf you're unhappy, at the end
of the year l'll buy you out.
- OK, l'm in.
- Thank you, Frasier.
Thank you, Roz.
That ''financial eunuch'' bit was great.
Well, look what l had to work with.
Hey, check this out! 25 cents off on
a pack of Butterbuds imitation butter.
My! l can taste that scampi now!
Well?
(Martin wolf whistles)
Daphne, very nice!
- Thank you.
l'd be more flattered if l didn't know
how hard up you both are.
l'm going out with Derek,
but l can't choose a fragrance.
l've got it pinned down to these two.
Heather: ''fresh and bouncy
as a spring morning''.
Or Forbidden: ''your passport
to erotic realms of pleasure''.
- How many times have you been out?
- lt's our third date.
Forbidden.
So what if it's our third date?
Well, sexual mores
being what they are in America,
the third date is usually
when two healthy adults
decide whether or not to...
- ...take it to the next level.
- What kind of randy custom is that?
(Doorbell)
First date, second date,
let's pitch our knickers!
lt may be the third date for you,
but it takes more than three dinners
to get bangers and mash with me.
- Hello, Dr Crane.
- Hello, Daphne.
- You look even lovelier than usual.
- Thank you.
ls that... Forbidden?
ln every sense of the word.
l'll scrub my neck
with unscented soap.
You Americans have
an unhealthy obsession with sex.
l'm sorry we can't all be as chaste
and restrained as the Royal family!
- Good one, Dad!
- l've been saving it!
Frasier, good news.
l spoke to my broker.
Meadow Wood Properties have leased
85%%% of the mini-mall.
lnstead of 1 2%%%,
they're projecting a 1 5%%% return.
Fantastic! Let's go celebrate
at an exclusive boîte.
Yes, but the question is,
what boîte?
- Charise?
- Too noisy.
- Alsace?
- Too bright.
- Papillon?
- Too crowded.
We've run out of boîtes.
A city this size
and only three boîtes.
How do we live?
- l'm going to Duke's. How about you?
- Looking for a place to eat.
Come and have a beer with me.
- At Duke's?
- Yeah.
- Us?
- With you?
- Am l speaking Swahili? Yeah!
You two, at Duke's, with me,
a beer, if you want! Gee!
Good God, do you believe that?
No. No one in the family
has ever been invited to Duke's.
Not even Mother. Though at times
she could be quite the old rummy.
Why, after 30 years,
is he suddenly inviting us there?
- Cheerio!
- Daphne!
Has Dad said anything to you
about us and Duke's?
- Has he been planning this?
- You mean, behind your backs?
- Precisely.
- No! What a couple of wallies!
l have never met a family that's
so uncomfortable with each other.
Could it be he just wants
a pint with his sons?
No. Duke's is where Dad goes
to escape the stresses
and strains of everyday life.
ln other words, us.
Well, you could sit here
analysing why he invited you
and fritter the night away,
or - here's a thought -
you could just go
and find out for yourselves.
For a lay person, she has a way
of cutting through the crap.
Oh, my God! lt's a roomful of Dads!
- There he is!
- Oh, look at him holding court.
No wonder he likes it here.
They're hanging on his every word.
l've never seen him have such fun
without a remote control.
Frasier, Niles!
l'm glad you could make it.
Meet some guys
l was on the force with.
Meet my boys. This is Frasier.
He's on the radio.
This is Marty's kid,
the guy on the radio!
Hey, Frasier, Joe Herman,
nice to meet you. Check this out:
''l'm listening.''
lt's like a recording of myself.
- Dad.
- What?
Oh, this is my other son, Niles.
He's a psychiatrist, too.
- He married money!
- All right!
Duke, l want you to meet my boys.
This is Frasier
and this is Niles.
How are you? How about a couple
of Duke's specials for you?
- What would those be?
- Boilermakers.
Shot of whisky. Beer back.
We've been drinking those all night.
Time to switch to sherry.
Two boilermakers, please.
Marty's been telling us about you
since you were kids.
- Dad!
- l'll tell you, Frasier,
we felt terrible when we heard
your wife was screwing around.
- What was her name again?
- Lilith!
Hey, it was a slow night, all right?
All right, everybody, settle down.
l want to make a toast.
For 30 years, Duke's has been
my home away from home.
l look around
and l see a lot of friends.
l'm going to miss you.
l'm going to miss this joint, too.
May there be a place in hell
for those SOBs
who are tearing it down
to build a mini-mall!
Those snivelling, rat-faced bastards
from Meadow Wood Properties!
To Duke's!
Two more!
- Did you talk to your lawyer.
- Yes. He's examined the contract.
The general partner won't consider
moving the site.
The deal's going through.
We could have Duke's
declared a historical landmark.
No. They tore down Seattle's first
Pony Express office to build it.
- Damn!
- Here you go, guys.
One cappuccino, one latte
and these are on me.
- This guilt is driving me crazy.
- lt should. You earn more than me.
- Duke's was his life.
- There's nothing we can do about it.
Look at it this way:
we're doing Dad a service,
stopping him from drinking.
And the other policemen as well.
Maybe it's a community service.
Men with guns will have
one less place to liquor up.
There's always Roz's place.
What do you say about me
when l'm not around?
l won't feel better till l tell Dad.
Oh, no.
lt's like a woman who has one crazy
night and cheats on her boyfriend.
Her only reason to confess
is to make herself feel better.
So the best thing she can do
is to keep her mouth shut.
Unless her boyfriend walks in,
because he's flown home instead
of driving like he said he would,
in which case, he's the liar,
so why should she feel bad?
Thank you, Roz, for that
purely theoretical example.
l agree. lf we tell him now, it'll
hurt him. We've got to keep it quiet.
- l don't think it can be done.
- Of course it can!
You can look Dad in the eye,
knowing you have destroyed
his sanctuary?
You can live with that?
You forget. l married Lilith.
l can live with anything.
(Electronic buzz)
You buy into an investment group,
Eddie. You don't know.
- Dad, what are you doing up?
- l reached out and Eddie wasn't there.
You need a woman, Dad.
Tell me about it.
Oh, you turned the sign on.
That was nice of Duke
to give it to me.
You hold a glass of beer
in front of it, it turns green.
Dad...
Niles and l invested in the company
that's tearing down Duke's.
We tried to get out of it,
but we couldn't.
Yell at me, Dad, will you?
Hit me with your cane.
Just don't stand there.
Let me see if l've got this right.
ln the last year, you give
my chair away, you lose my dog
and now you demolish my bar.
Next l'll find out you're the one
who shot me in the hip!
- l have an alibi for that one.
- You have one for everything.
lt wasn't on purpose.
l'm part of an investment group.
You watched me and my friends
get all weepy and didn't say anything.
What did you want us to say?
''Fellas, here's something ironic...''
Why didn't you at least tell me?
l don't know, l...
l guess...
Maybe it was because,
when you invited me to Duke's,
it felt like we were getting closer.
lt was a momentous step.
- lt was a beer!
- Not to me.
lt was validation.
Finally, l was one of the guys
you wanted to hang out with.
l didn't want to spoil that.
l'd have asked you before
but l just figured it was the kinda place
you'd look down your nose at.
Well, you're probably right.
Anyway, l'm sorry.
- Maybe l spent too much time there.
- What do you mean?
When you were growing up.
lf l'd spent less time at Duke's
and more with you,
l wouldn't have a son
who puts so much stock in one beer.
You know, l was having
a pretty good time at Duke's.
Till l found l was responsible for
wiping it off the face of the planet.
l liked having you there, too, son.
Thanks, Dad.
Do you mind? lt's driving me crazy.
lt looks like hell.
Know what? We got a few hours
before the wrecking ball comes.
- How about you and l go down there?
- To Duke's?
- Yeah.
- Now?
- You and me?
- Not this again!
- Yeah. All right, great.
Just you, me and Charlie Ballantine.
Meet you right back here in a minute.
Oh, good evening, Daphne.
Or should l say good morning?
- How was your date with Derek?
- We had a wonderful time.
We went to dinner,
then to the symphony,
then we took a lovely moonlight stroll
through the park.
He's the perfect gentleman.
Apparently in England,
it's the fourth date.
(# ''Danny Boy'')
# l'll be here
# ln sunshine or in shadow
# Oh, Danny Boy, oh, Danny Boy
# l love you so #
That's good.
lt reminds me of old Micky Dougan.
One 4th July,
we were on mounted patrol
in a big parade down Broad Street.
lt was a scorcher.
Must have been 1 00%F.
l'm sitting on a thousand pounds
of hot, sweaty horse.
l must have been complaining
because, as we ride by Duke's,
Micky says, ''lf you want a beer
so bad, get one!''
So l ride through the front door,
up to the bar and order a beer.
Duke plays it cool and says,
''What'll your friend have?''
l say, ''Nothing, he's driving.''
- l've told you that one before, haven't l?
- Yeah.
Oh, what a place!
- Another beer, Dad?
- Sure, why not?
Sun's up.
l look around this place
in the golden early morning light...
lt's still a dump.
l'm going to miss it, though.
l know what it is
to have a neighbourhood bar.
l remember the last time l walked
out of my old watering hole in Boston.
lt was a strangely emotional day.
lt's the people, l guess.
Saying goodbye to a lot of people.
Saying goodbye to this place
doesn't mean you can't see
your buddies as much as ever.
Yeah, it does.
Yeah, you're right.
But that's life. You move on.
Only a fool tries to fight it.
- What are you doing?
- Stopping the demolition. And you?
- Saying goodbye.
- You may not have to.
l intend to stand here
and face down the bulldozers.
No need. l've talked to Dad.
He forgives us.
- Sure, Son. Don't worry. lt's OK.
- ls it really? l think not!
Today it's Duke's,
but tomorrow it's Mo's
and the day after,
it's Ernie's Taproom.
l'm not just here for you, Dad.
l'm doing this for every little guy
who's found solace after a hard day
by bellying up at his local bar.
l'll show faceless, corporate America
they can't just
shove the little guy aside.
Even when l'm
that faceless, corporate America.
l'm here to fight the good fight,
to show those rat-faced heathens
there's still some fury
in the heart of John Q Public.
On the other hand, who am l
to stand in the way of progress?
# Hey baby, l hear the blues are calling
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# Quite stylish!
# And maybe l seem a bit confused
Well, maybe, but l got you pegged
# But l don't know what to do with those
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# They're calling again #
Good night everybody!