(Woman) 'lt's not that l don't like him.
'But he's gotten so attached.
'l mean, roses every day
after two dates! '
Maggie, first thing you have to do
is sit Gavin down
for a nice long conversation.
Tell him frankly that,
though he wants to go at one speed,
you need to go at another.
Tell him you're not rejecting him,
you are fond of him, but...
l wonder what Roz, my non-PhD-holding
producer, thinks you should do.
Any guy who's that clingy after two
dates has a major insecurity problem.
l say, ''Dump him. Now.
And don't look back.''
(Maggie )
'lt's so good to hear that, Roz.
'That's what l wanted to do, but l felt
so guilty. Thanks so much. Bye.'
That takes us to a commercial.
This, for those who have forgotten,
is the Dr Frasier Crane Show.
l confirmed your dinner reservation
for three.
At your father's request,
that's at Chez Shrimp.
Two letters to sign - a card for
Clarence, the guard, we're all signing,
and a notice on the KACL bowling team
that l'll file in the trash.
Oh, wonderful. Another card.
l, as resident wit,
will have to be clever.
At least l've got another KACL
birthday bash to look forward to.
l can just taste that frozen cake now
and hear wild applause as an adult
snuffs out a handful of tiny candles.
- What are you grousing about?
- Oh, nothing.
(Card plays tune )
Yes, the pageantry never stops.
(Martin) Mr Fancy Pants.
- He's got to buy a German car.
- lt's not my fault we broke down.
lf you'd bought American,
they could fix it here.
l always buy American so you can go
to the nearest garage.
l could break down alone
in the middle of Alaska!
A thought to raise all our spirits.
This traffic is murder. We could walk,
but humidity may ruin my loafers.
Does calfskin pucker?
Yes, that's why on humid farms,
the calf is the most made fun of
of all the animals.
Don't be snide.
We'll be here for a while.
Let's try and make
pleasant conversation.
We are a family.
lt shouldn't be that hard.
Have you been driving long?
- Not really.
- Got any good stories?
Ever hear of a woman
having a baby in a cab?
- lt's a classic.
- Why? Did that happen in this cab?
- lt's about to.
- You're pregnant?
Yes. Ow!
Don't panic.
lt may be false labour.
My waters just broke.
l'm in a puddle of water.
Calfskin!
- Closest hospital is First Methodist.
- We'll never make it. Pull over!
- Try to park facing downhill.
- Niles!
- l can't have my baby here.
- There's no need to be concerned.
We are trained medical professionals.
Niles, help her!
- Hurry!
- l know.
The other door!
Oh, for goodness sake!
ls anybody there? Come in!
lt's most important to breathe deeply.
Do as l do.
- Do you feel faint or short of breath?
- Yes, both of those.
- (Man) 'Hello? Go ahead.'
- Yes, l'm calling from cab No 804.
This is an emergency.
Your driver just went into labour.
We're at the corner
of 1 4th and Sycamore.
- We need an ambulance now.
- (Man) 'OK.'
- lt hurts.
- lt's natural.
- No, you're squeezing my hand.
- l only did this once in medical school.
l remember lots of blood and a lino
floor hurtling toward my forehead.
- You fainted?
- Switch places and see how you do!
Good God, Niles!
l'll do this!
- The baby's really coming now!
- When he does come, l'll catch him.
Just continue with your breathing.
Don't feel guilty
for having a baby in a cab.
Nothing to be ashamed of. Many great
Americans have been born this way.
Cab Calloway comes to mind.
l'm a psychiatrist. l specialise
in the head, not the lower body.
lt's less messy that way.
Not that your lower portion is messy.
lt's beautiful. Not that l'm looking!
- ls the pain that bad?
- No, you're driving me crazy!
Move it out, come on!
- You a doctor, too?
- No, a retired cop.
Well what took you so long?
lt's really hurting.
Everything's going to be just fine.
l've delivered a few babies,
and some are older than you are now.
Frasier will hold your hand,
Niles will look out for an ambulance
and l'll help your beautiful baby out.
OK?
- OK.
- Are there any questions?
Should our meter still be running?
(Daphne ) Hello? Are you back yet?
Well, go on, turn your heads.
OK. So l guess
you've had some excitement tonight.
No, l haven't!
Your father made it sound exciting
on the phone: delivering a baby in a taxi.
l see that not as excitement
but as my duty to use the skills
l honed in medical school.
Yes, Niles ran to a falafel stand
for a pot of hot water.
l can't get over the feeling of being
there when a person's life begins.
One minute, it's a blob inside some
lady, next minute, it's a person.
Blob - person.
The miracle of birth
summed up in one poetic phrase.
l bet you have fond memories
of your son's birth.
Oh, yes, of course.
The first time l held him in my arms
as a newborn,
it was as if everything else
simply melted away.
There was just a father, a son
and the distant sound of Lilith saying,
''lf you come near me again, Frasier,
l'll drop you with a deer rifle!''
At least now fathers
see their sons being born.
ln my day, they stuck us
in the waiting room,
smoking and reading Life magazine.
l remember what l was reading
when Niles was born.
lt was about Mickey Mantle.
Talk about life
setting you up for a fall.
- l'm turning in.
- Night, Dad.
l wonder what dreams l'll have
after this talk about childbearing.
Probably the one
where my mother says,
''Daphne, you're 50 and you've
never given me grandchildren.''
So l say, ''That was my choice.
l was thinking of my career.''
''But did you ever think of me?''
''Mother, l don't want
to start this again. Just drop it!''
But will she drop it?
''Oh, shut up, Mother!''
l wonder how many more people
she's got in there.
- Sherry, Niles?
- No, thank you.
- Something on your mind?
- Actually, yes.
For months, l've noticed my thoughts
drifting to the same subject -
will l ever be a father?
There are pros and cons.
But, watching that birth,
l realised it's something l really want.
l think.
lt's natural to have
parental stirrings.
l wake up nights thinking about it.
- Have you talked to Maris?
- Not yet.
l like to know what l want
before Maris tells me.
l'm just not sure
l'm ready for fatherhood.
No one is ever sure. These days,
teenagers who want to become parents
are given a sack of flour to keep
for a week, as if it were a baby.
- You're kidding?
- No. They hold it, they care for it.
lt gives a good idea
of the responsibility of parenthood.
What could be better than hands-on
experience? Might be worth a try!
- l wasn't...
- Why not? Maris is away.
l'm desperate to resolve the issue.
Where do you keep the flour?
ln the kitchen.
The cabinet next to the sink.
Yes, here it is. ''Extra-refined.''
lt's taking after its old man already.
No, that's the sugar.
We're going to do this right.
Now, here is the flour.
''Bleached, 100% fat free, best
when kept in an airtight container.''
This one's taking after its mother.
Hello. May l join you?
Or should l say, ''May we?''
Mais oui. So you're continuing
with our little baby experiment?
Yes. And it's been
quite a learning experience.
Not easy, though!
l take him everywhere,
get up for 2:00 am feedings,
the whole exhausting nine yards.
What a beautiful baby!
How old is he?
- Eight weeks.
- Great age, isn't it?
Niles? l can't help noticing
that your child has a little boo-boo.
lt's nothing.
l was playing him some Brahms.
Never too early to ingrain them.
l must have begun conducting
with a chopstick
and l accidentally ran him through.
What young parent
doesn't tell that story?
The scuffs were the fault
of my new houseman, Ngee.
- What did Ghee do?
- No, it's Ngee.
- Ghee.
- No, no. Ngee.
Oh, who cares? What did he do?
He'd just given my car a shine,
when l sat the baby on the roof
and down it went onto the driveway.
Would you watch him while l order?
(Roz) Hey, Frase. This seat taken?
Well, actually...
No.
Clarence is doing better.
l just dropped his card off.
- Clarence?
- The guard.
Oh, down at the station.
Good. l didn't know he was sick.
You signed his ''get well'' card.
That wasn't a birthday card?
No, he's in hospital
having a kidney transplant.
Oh, my God!
l thought it was his birthday.
l wrote, ''You're not getting older,
just closer to death.''
How could you think
it was his birthday?
l didn't recognise the traditional
card for a sick man - a giant bunny.
- Has he read it yet?
- No, he was asleep.
l'll look so callous.
We've got to get that card back!
How can you be leaving?
l asked you to baby-sit!
l have no time for your insanity!
l have to go steal a ''get well'' card
from a kidney patient.
(Daphne ) What does that say ''Geb...''?
No, it's ''Get''.
''Get well soon. Love, Andrea.''
Just copy it down
and move on to the next name.
We have to transfer all the names
on to the new card.
l want to get it back tonight.
So you snuck into his room
and stole his card?
l did not sneak in. Luckily, he was
in extreme pain and heavily sedated.
You should have found out
who this Clarence was.
You never pay attention
to the little people.
Yes, why don't we invite
the commoners
to drag me to the square
and stone me.
(Doorbell)
That must be Niles.
He's taking me to the hospital.
- Hello, Niles.
- Hello, Frasier.
- What are you doing with that?
- Forging a parent-child bond.
That's a relief. l was afraid
it might be something stupid.
l don't wear it in public. But l want
a true picture of parenthood.
- And?
- lt's driving me batty.
Feedings every two hours,
constantly monitoring where he is.
You can get obsessed with worry.
Last night, l dreamt
my flour sack was abducted
and the kidnappers
started sending me muffins in the mail.
On the plus side, l've learnt a lot.
lf l ever go through the real thing,
l'll make a wonderful parent.
Niles, what has happened
to your child?
l was practising my t'ai chi
and l accidentally kicked him
into the reflecting pool.
Then l brought him inside
and left him by the hearth to dry.
He caught on fire?
lt was not that careless.
A real child would have cried
before it burst into flames.
(Alarm beeps)
Ah! Time for his nap!
- Turn him over if he starts fussing.
- No.
- l'm role-playing, Dad.
- Try the role of a sane person.
So, any closer to making
a decision about fatherhood?
No. One minute, l think
l could never stand the stress,
the next, l'm daydreaming
about taking my son to the museum
or listening to his first ''Für Elise''
and l swear there are tears in my eyes.
(Eddie growls)
Oh, dear... Eddie!
(Australian accent)
That dingo's got your baby.
Oh, God! Eddie, Dad!
Don't worry.
l'll clean up that mess.
For God's sake, calm down! l think
it's time you realised something.
That is not a person.
lt's a bag of flour.
lt's easy to tell the difference.
People don't have recipes
on their backs.
This is stupid!
We're talking about having a baby here.
You make that decision in your gut,
not intellectually.
What is your gut feeling?
- l'm not sure.
- You'd better be.
Nothing can prepare you
for having a kid.
lt's hard. Full of surprises.
Maybe your kid
won't want piano lessons.
- He might like baseball.
- Don't even say that.
Just trust yourself.
You'll know if it's right or not.
l'm finished, if you're ready
to take me to the hospital.
l wonder if this experiment
wasn't just a way of convincing myself
l'm ready for something,
when l know l'm not.
- What do you mean?
- l want to have a baby.
But l just don't want it enough.
Oh... That's the hardest thing
l've ever had to admit.
- Why do you say that?
- Because it's so selfish.
l'm the right age,
l have the money, the energy.
lt's only selfish to have babies
for the wrong reasons.
People should find out
if they're ready.
Anyway, feeling this way now
doesn't mean things can't change
in a few years.
Perhaps you're right.
Maris and l will be over 40 then.
Maybe we should look into
getting some of her eggs frozen.
Oh, l suspect they're only
a few degrees away from that now.
Who is this Clarence fellow?
Some guy down at the station.
(Music plays)
Dr Crane! lt's Clarence!
Were you in there looking for me?
- As a matter of fact, l was.
- They changed my room.
This is so sweet of you.
Clarence is such a fixture, the
station isn't the same without him.
You find the time to come here
while the rest of those bums at
the station don't even send me a card.
Actually, Clarence,
there's an explanation for that.
(Patient) Make the music stop!
You see, the others at the station
don't know you the way l do.
Well, listen,
you get yourself well.
l miss seeing you
every time l walk by the...
...place you tend to be.
Niles!
What are you doing?
Looking at these babies, wondering
if l made the right decision.
- Niles...
- Look at them!
They're healthy, beautiful, lovable...
Flammable.
Maybe l'm more ready
for parenthood than l thought.
- Hey, what are you guys doing here?
- Arleen! And this must be...
Yes, little Nathan.
l'm so glad l ran into you.
We both want to thank you guys again.
Would one of you like to hold him?
Yes, l would.
Oh, he's beautiful.
Yes, why shouldn't you cry?
Everything's so new to you...
So much life to live...
- No, you've got his leg bent back.
- Oh, God!
l'm sorry.
Well, see you, guys.
Say ''hi'' to your dad for me.
- Perhaps l made the right decision.
- l'd say so. Ready to go?
(Baby murmurs)
# Hey baby, l hear the blues are calling
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# Mercy!
# And maybe l seem a bit confused
Well, maybe, but l got you pegged
# But l don't know what to do with those
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# They're calling again #
Good night!