Oh, good morning, Dr. Crane.
Not a morning person, are we?
Well, never you mind. I am.
Can't very well be a good health care provider if you're not up with the cock.
I've already taken your father for his morning constitutional.
Such a remarkable man - thirty years on the police force.
I can understand why you'd want him to live here,
although not many sons would do that,
not without getting paid for it.
Anyway, coffee's made, and I took the liberty of doing a shop.
They don't serve much tripe in Seattle, do they?
And you are...?
Daphne. Daphne Moon.
I moved in yesterday.
- You hired me to take care of your father.
- Of course
Of course. You'll have to forgive me, I'm not quite myself until I've shaved and showered.
Oh, yes
I completely understand about one's morning ablutions.
- I, for instance, can't stand myself 'til I floss all that gunk out of my teeth...
- Miss Moon!
For future reference, if you could just keep your ablutions on a need-to know basis?
Thank you
Now, my coffee.
The half 'n half's curdled, and the garbage disposal's jammed.
Good morning to you too, dad.
Morning was two hours ago.
And close that barn door, we got a lady in the house now.
Hey, this isn't my coffee.
Where's my finely-ground Kenya blend from Starbucks?
That's it.
Daphne put an eggshell and some allspice in it.
Didn't that just dress it up?
I like it. Gives it a zing.
Now, come on, sit down. Your breakfast is ready.
Oh, no, dad, dad, look, all I ever have is a bran muffin, and a touch of yogurt.
Ah, girlie food.
Besides, I already fixed your breakfast.
Now, I made you "Eggs in a nest".
Ah yes, the Crane family specialty.
Fried eggs swimming in fat,
served in a delightfully hollowed-out piece of white bread.
I can almost hear my left ventricle slamming shut as I speak.
- You want cheese on that?
- No
I'd like to leave some blood flow for the clot to go swiftly to my brain.
Can't have my coffee, can't have my breakfast.
Oh dear god, it wasn't a dream.
I'll get him for this.
And his little dog, too.
Where's my paper? Who's stole my paper?
Mrs. Everly, you old bat, I know it's you!
Yoo-hoo? It's right here, we brought it in for you.
Sorry, sorry.
Oh, wait a minute, this...
where's the rubber band? This paper has been read.
Well, don't worry, we won't tell you what's in it.
That is not the point.
Dad, dad? Come and sit down please, would you?
You're going to give a speech, aren't you?
Oh, that's right, I forgot, you're psychic.
Yes, but I think anyone could feel this one coming on.
Let us get something clear.
I am not a morning person.
I have to ease into my day slowly.
First I have my coffee
sans eggshells or anything else one tends to pick out of the garbage.
Then I have a low-fat, high-fiber breakfast.
Finally I sit down and read a crisp, new newspaper.
If I am robbed of the richness of my morning routine, I cannot function.
My radio show suffers,
and like ripples in a pond, so do the many listeners that rely on my advice,
to help them through their troubled lives.
I'm sorry if this may sound priggish,
but have grown comfortable with this part of myself.
It is the magic that is me.
Get used to it.
I know the is a stressful time,
and this is new for all of us,
but I'm sure that soon we'll all be getting along swimmingly.
- Ooh, six more weeks of winter, I see.
- Oh, dear.
Down Eddie, down.
I said down.
Good boy Eddie, just get down.
Good good good good good, Eddie get down.
GET DOWN!
Dad, dad, I can't read my paper, Eddie's staring at me.
Why, you do make quite a picture in the morning.
- Just ignore him.
- I'm trying to.
I'm talking to the dog.
Don't even think about it!
You're listening to Dr. Frasier Crane.
Our topic today is...
intrusion.
Those who encroach on our sense of personal space.
The neighbor who plays his stereo too loud.
The person who sits next to you in the movie theater when there are fifty other vacant seats.
Now let's return to our calls,
and let me remind you once more, that our topic today is intrusion.
since so many of you seem to be forgetting that.
Dr. Crane, we have Leonard from Everett, on line two.
Hello Leonard, I'm listening.
Oh, hi, Dr. Crane.
Ah, I'm a little nervous, but ah...
well, here goes.
Several years ago I became afraid of large, open spaces.
Like, if I went to the mall, I'd break out in a cold sweat.
I'd get so scared that I'd have to run home.
Yes Leonard, and your comments on intrusion?
Nothing.
Just that, now I'm afraid to go outside at all.
I haven't seen another person in eight months.
Well Leonard, it sounds like you may have a very serious condition known as agoraphobia.
But you're not alone.
But I am alone, Dr. Crane.
Listen Leonard, I'm afraid your problem is too difficult to deal with in the time we have remaining,
so if you stay on the line, someone will give you the name of a qualified therapist.
Well, that's all the time we have for today.
You've been listening to Dr. Frasier Crane, KACL 780.
Stay tuned for the news.
Then next up, Bob "Bulldog" Briscoe and the Gonzo Sports Show.
I never miss it.
Yeah, right.
You want your messages?
Oh, listen Roz, just hang on to them. I think I'll stay in here for a while.
Today more that most, I feel an overwhelming need for solitude.
I've got a fascinating book here, a confortable chair...
and a soundproof booth.
Hiya, doc, How're they hangin'?
Bulldog, what are you doing here?
We lost transmitter link power in Studio C.
I gotta do my show from here.
Hey, where the hell's my Cosell tape? Somebody stole my Cosell tape!
THIS STINKS! THIS IS TOTAL B.S.! THIS... Oh, here it is.
Let me just get out of your way.
Oh, by the way doc,
doc, I heard what you said to that kid who fantasizes about killing his parents?
You know what I would have told him?
Sports.
You go out there, break some heads
That'll turn him around.
Yes. If only Jeffrey Dahmer had picked up a squash racquet.
Hey, where the hell's my Lasorda tape? THIS IS TOT... ah, got it.
Hold on a second, I have to ask you something.
Gary? I broke up with him three weeks ago.
The sex was okay, but he was kinda limited.
No, no.
No, it wasn't that Gary was bad in bed.
I mean, he knew where all the parts were.
Unfortunately, most of them were his.
Yes, totally passionless, it was like he was thinking of someone else.
I know I was.
Somebody's here, I gotta go.
Alright? Talk to you later.
Bye Mom.
That was your mother?
Yeah, why?
You talk to your mother like that?
Well, we're both adults.
We talk about everything.
Well, isn't that healthy.
What, you don't talk to your dad like that?
Oh, hardly. We hardly speak at all.
Really?
Ah yes, well you know, we're just not really...
very similar people
In fact, my brother and I are a lot more like my mother.
You know, if it wasn't biologically impossible
I'd swear that dad was dropped in a basket on our doorstep.
Hey sweetcakes, you seen my engineer?
I think someone's talking to you, Frasier.
Come on, come on, come on!
Yes, he called and he'll be right here.
So do you want to go across the street and have one of those expensive coffee drinks?
Maybe some other time.
Right now, I'd like to continue my quest for solitude.
I'll go somewhere my father, Mary Poppins and the hound from hell can't find me.
I think maybe I'll just go sit under the shade of a tree and read in a quiet park.
Hello.
Hello?
Dad?
Daphne?
Eddie?
Could it be?
Toreador
Don't spit on the floor.
Use the cuspidor-a
What do you think it's for-a?
...so the elephant says, "He's with me."
Oh, Dr. Crane, you're home.
We just got back from your father's physical therapy.
Oh, glory be. Oh, happy day.
Not that I'm not delighted to see the two of you,
it's just that I'm in the middle of a very exciting chapter.
Ooh, I understand.
So why don't I pop into the kitchen and brew you up a nice pot of tea?
No, I just poured myself a glass of wine, thank you.
I see.
Whatcha reading?
Oh dad, you wouldn't find it very interesting.
I might. Any good?
Well, I haven't formed an opinion yet.
Oddly enough, I'm having a little trouble getting into it.
Thick.
Dad will you...
Listen, I don't want to offend, but...
if you wouldn't mind, could you just
leave me alone, let me read my book?
No problem.
What are you doing?
I'm leaving you alone.
Well, it's very annoying!
Ah, what's your problem?
You've been sucking a lemon all week.
All right, all right, I'll tell you what my problem is,
I can't get a moment's peace alone in my own house.
Well, forgive me.
When you invited me to move in I didn't realise
I had to stay chained to the radiator in my room.
Perhaps only evenings.
I heard that!
Well, of course you heard it, you're never out of earshot!
Ah, you know, you've always been like this.
You were always a fussy little kid,
and it's gotten worse ever since.
You and your precious morning routine.
You gotta have your coffee,
you gotta have your quiet,
you gotta have this, you gotta have that.
Well, aren't you the little hothouse orchid.
Hey, hey-hey-hey!
I don't have to sit here and listen to that!
Ah, if you want everything so perfect,
why don't you go live in a bubble?
Oh right, oh well, right now it sounds very inviting!
Finally, a little peace and quiet around here.
Hello there, Frasier.
Oh, what fresh hell is this?
That's a nice way to greet your brother.
Café latte, per piachere.
I'm sorry, Niles,
It's just I've been trying to read this book
and it seems no matter where I alight I get interrupted.
Oh, "The Holotropic Mind" by Stanislav Grolf.
I love his conclusion that a change in breathing patterns can induce alternate states of consciousness.
Great. Now you've ruined the ending!
I'm sorry, that was inconsiderate.
Mille Grazie.
So, how's father?
Father?
You mean the man who's driving me crazy?
The man who makes me dread the sight of my very doorstep?
The man who just drove me out of my own home?
And how's work?
Niles, I don't know what I'm going to do.
Dad and I had another fight.
I'm afraid if we stay under the same roof together
we'll do irreparable harm to the relationship we have as it is.
Well, what are the alternatives?
Well, if I didn't fell so guilty I'd,
I'd do what I should have done in the first place:
just move dad and Daphne into their own appartment.
Oh, for goodness sake, Frasier.
It hasn't been that long, you have to give it a chance.
And you might remember why you moved him in in the first place.
Refresh me.
You wanted to get closer to dad.
I still do.
There isn't anything I'd like more,
but he makes it impossible.
I can't read my book, I can't have my coffee,
I can't have any peace in my own home.
So what you're saying is, you want to be closer to dad,
but you don't actually want him around.
Ask yourself Frasier, have you tried to sit down and talk to him
I mean, really talk to him?
Well, I...
Maybe I haven't done my best.
I guess I owe that to the old man, don't I?
Well, ah...
Thanks for the chat, Niles. You're a good brother,
and a credit to the psychiatric profession.
You're a good brother too.
Daphne?
What are my things doing here?
My leather wing chair? My Kusami lamp?
We're putting them in the storage room, in the basement.
There was no room for them in the study once we got my furniture in.
We discussed it last night, remember?
Of course, of course.
I was just on my way to ask that peculiar little man from building services
to give me a hand moving them.
Oh, yes, Kyle. Well, give him my regards.
Oh yeah, Remind me again
which one of Kyle's eyes is really looking at me?
The brown one.
Daphne left your dinner in the fridge, if you're hungry.
Well thanks, but I'm not.
Ah... Dad, I'm sorry about the blow-up earlier.
Ah, forget about it. I already have.
You know, I guess there's no secret that these's been a lot of tension between us,
and I think maybe one of the reasons is that we never have a chance to sit down and talk.
And I... I thought we might have a conversation.
Right now?
Yes, I think now would be a good time.
Later would be better.
It doesn't have to be a long, drawn-out conversation,
I'm talking about three minutes of you life.
Well, I hope it is only three minutes,
'cause my program's coming on.
Well, alright.
If it'll make you any happier I will get the egg-timer and I will set it for three minutes.
So, what do you want to talk about?
Well, the idea is for us to have a normal, honest conversation
just like two normal people without getting on each other's nerves.
Ready? Go
This is stupid.
One second? That's our personal best?
Let us see if we can beat it.
Ready? Go
So how about those Seahawks?
No sports.
- All right. No opera.
- Agreed.
Ready? Go
This is your idea, you say something first.
Alright, alright. I'll, I'll tell you something about myself,
that, ah, that you don't know.
Ah, six months ago,
when Lilith and I were really on the rocks, ah,
there was a time of depression I went through that was so terrible
I actually climbed out on a ledge and wondered if life was worth living. I...
And then I thought of Frederick.
And you didn't jump, huh?
Good, dad.
Wow. I never knew that.
Well, that's the point of this whole experiment.
To tell one another something that we don't know about each other.
Something vulnerable. Now it's your turn.
Okay.
Well, about two months ago,
I was in the basement, going through some old pictures of your mother and me...
and all of the sudden something flew up in my eye.
And, when I was trying to get it out,
I realised I could turn my eyelid inside out, the way kids do at camp.
That's it? You call that vulnerable?
It hurt.
Oh well...
I'm not talking about that kind of pain,
I'm talking about your emotions, your soul.
Some sort of painful, gut- wrenching experience.
Other than this one?
Oh, God! Always the flip answer.
Well, this whole thing's stupid.
Well, not to me.
Oh, how should I expect anything out of you?
You are the most cold, intractable, unapproachable, distant,
stubborn, cold man I've ever known!
You said "cold" twice, Mr. Egghead.
Egghead? Egghead?
You said "egghead" twice, too.
Oh, you are so infuriating!
Oh, you're no day at the beach either.
You know what you are?
I'll tell you later, it's time for my program.
Dad, I don't think you see how serious this is.
Oh, will you give it a rest?
Look. We're not getting alone, and it's not getting any better.
I'm not sure how to say this, but ah...
I ah, I'm afraid I'm gonna have to...
I know what you're trying to say.
"You want what's best for both of us."
You want to get me out of here, then you can have your own space,
and I'll have my own space, and we can put an end to all this bickering.
Well, yes.
I guess it wasn't so hard to say after all.
Except for one thing. I'm not going.
What?
Look, you want us to forge some great father-son relationship,
to make some connection.
Well, that kind of thing takes a couple of years, not a couple of days, doesn't it?
You're the shrink.
Couple of years, huh?
Ah, it'll go by before you know it.
Either that, or it'll seem like eternity.
I'm willing to give it a shot if you are.
Okay
Great. How about you and me having a beer together?
Wow. You know, in all these years you've never asked me that.
I'd love to have a beer with you, dad.
Well then, you better haul ass, 'cause the store closes in ten minutes.
Right.