Hello Doug, this is Dr. Frasier Crane.
I'm listening.
Yeah, it's about my mother.
She's getting on now and she doesn't have much of a life.
And... I mean, she doesn't want to do anything
or go anywhere and she literally hangs around the house all day.
I mean, it's very frustrating...
I'm sorry, can we just go back a second?
You said you mother literally hangs around the house.
Well, I suppose it's a pet peeve of mine
but what you mean to say is that
she figuratively "hangs around" the house.
To... to literally hang around the house
you'd have to be a bat or spider monkey.
Now, back to your problem?
Do you mind if we stop while I tell you my pet peeve?
Not a all.
I hate it when intellectual pinheads
with superiority complexes...
...nit-pick your grammar when they come to you for help.
That's what I got a problem with!
I think what he means is,
that is a thing with which he has a problem.
Now it's time for a station break
and we'll be right back after a word from our friends at
"Pizza, Pizza, Pizza."
Hey, do you want to know my pet peeve?
It's when you're in a department store and the clerk
is right in the middle of helping you and the phone rings.
So he starts taking care of them.
And you're left standing there going...
"Excuse me, but all I did was come
all the way down here in person...
...whilst some joker is sitting at home
in his underwear getting first rate service!"
Don't you hate that?
Actually, I do most of my shopping by phone.
You know Roz, this conversation with Doug
has got me thinking about my father.
He doesn't do much of anything either.
He just sits around most of the time watching TV
and doing the occasional crossword puzzle.
What does your mother do?
She's the attorney general of Wisconsin.
- No, really!
- Really!
Well, I guess that helps fill her day.
Yeah, quote mom, "Crime never stops -
even in the dairy state!"
Well, I don't think public office is for dad,
but maybe I could find him a hobby or something. Any suggestions?
Well, in her spare time my mom likes to water ski a little.
She hikes, oil paints... oh, she likes archaeology.
She's on a dig in Honduras right now.
Yeah, maybe I could get him a wood burning set.
Is dad still asleep?
Yes, he's napping with the dog. Eddie's little legs are going like mad.
I think he's dreaming about chasing rabbits.
I can't explain your father's twitching!
Well, I'm just about done with this thing.
I think your dad's going to love it.
Yeah, Me, too.
I was walking through the hobby shop and saw this
thing and it was like, "Eureka!" I said to myself...
I actually said "Eureka!"
Ah, yes. There are a million stories in the naked city.
Now if we could just find a naked one.
Dr. Crane, you naughty boy.
Peeking in on other people's privacy.
Oh Daphne, really.
I mean, if people were so concerned about
their precious privacy...
they wouldn't leave their blinds open at that certain angle...
where you can see the mirror over the mantle
that reflects down the hall to the water bed in the back room!
I think I hear your father coming.
Stand in front of it, we'll make this a little surprise.
- Hi, guys.
- Dad.
- How was your nap?
Great, I had the strangest dream.
I dreamt this beautiful woman with bad
breath was licking my face.
Hey, where did you just come from?
Dad, I got a surprise for you.
Hey, telescope, it's... it's a beaut.
What's the occasion?
Oh, no occasion, just thought you'd like it.
Wow, that's great, thanks.
You know, I saw in the news there's a bunch
of falcons nesting in the eaves of the Columbia Tower.
Maybe I can watch them from here.
Dad, dad, forget the falcons.
You can see what is going on in that
apartment building over there.
Hey, I've locked people up for that kind of behavior.
Oh come on, it's perfectly innocent -
just think of it as having like a...
a hundred more channels to watch.
Just look at them, people going about their lives.
There's an old couple watching the telly,
and just next door an attractive young woman is working at a computer...
while below her a burly man is using a beach
towel to sop up a large pool of blood.
- Oh my God.
- What?
Daddy!
No, that's tomato juice - you can see the can on the counter.
You’re right about that woman at the
computer though, she's a looker.
Ah, you see, there's a boy in all of us.
Well, let's see what else the Seattle skyline has to offer.
I say we make a strict rule, though:
if anybody starts doing anything nasty we move on. Agreed?
I said, agreed?
- Yeah!
Well, there's a lady over there with a telescope.
She's looking back at us.
What... What... What shall we do?
Hide!
I knew it, I knew it, every time we do
something bad I get caught!
Hi, how are you doing?
What are you doing?
She's waving at us, I'm waving back.
- Don't do that!
- Why not?
Hey wait, she's writing something down.
She's holding it up.
It says, "Hello there, stranger".
Hey Daphne, quick, get me that pad and pen.
Wait, wait, wait. What for?
I'm... I'm gonna answer.
Write down "My name is Martin."
Dad, dad you shouldn't encourage this person.
I don't really want people looking in on our lives.
I don't think I've made my bed today.
Is she writing anything else?
Yeah. "My name is Irene." Her name's Irene.
- Her name's Irene.
- Thank you.
Wait, she's writing something else.
“Is that Dr. Crane from the radio hiding in the back?”
It does not say that!
It does say that.
Hello.
”Her older son's an accountant in Falkland.”
He was the breech birth, right?
No, that's the Dennis in Boise.
Oh right, he's the one with the wife
that won't let him visit. I can't stand her.
Morning dad, Daphne.
Morning, Irene.
Hey Frasier, when you were a kid, what was the name
of that skin condition you had on your butt?
It's Pityorisis Rosea.
- How do you spell that?
- Why?
Irene and I are exchanging family histories.
Dad. I really don't think your girlfriend
needs to know about that.
She's not my girlfriend!
Oh, come on.
You two have been exchanging notes
now for the past three days.
If you were in the sixth grade you would be
sitting in a tree "K-I-S-S-I-N-G".
Here Daphne, let me borrow that pen.
What are you doing?
I'm going to help along your little
romance and possibly save a small forest.
I'm giving her our telephone number.
- No, no, no, no, no, don't do that!
- Why?
Well, she'll think I'm being too forward.
For God's sake, dad, you met peeping into her apartment.
- She's not going to call.
- You want to bet?
- Yeah, five bucks.
- Okay.
- Well, are you going to answer?
- You get it
Dad, it's for you!
Hello. No, no, this is Frasier. Hi. I'm fine.
Well, it gets a little flaky when the weather's dry.
Tell her I'm not home.
Dad, she knows you're home -
she's looking at you through the telescope.
Come on, you're just a little nervous.
Hello?
Hi.
Yeah, it's nice hearing yours.
Can you hold on a minute?
Would you two get out of here?
- I'm getting a very good feeling about this.
- Really?
Hold it. You really think he's interested in her?
Yes, I think so.
Do you want to hear something cute, Dr. Crane?
I made him this rich gooey coffee cake this morning,
because you know what a sweet tooth he has.
And he wouldn't even take one bite because -
as he put it - "Women don't like a spare tire on a man."
That's so cute. Oh, it's funny, you know -
the twists and turns of fate.
If I had tried to set dad up with a woman
he would have rejected the idea out of hand...
but I go out get him this telescope for a hobby
and it kindles this romance. It's Kismet!
- Well?
- What?
- What happened?
We talked on the phone.
And? Was she nice, was she interesting? What did she say?
She said a lot of stuff.
So it would be safe to assume that
you two will be seeing each other?
Ah, she wanted to, but I said no.
No? Why?
She's not my type.
Oh, coffee cake! We got any butter round here?
You know Brewster Cale? The pompous twit
who is the president of our wine club?
Well, at our meeting the other night I convinced
some of my fellow psychiatrists to play a little prank on him.
When he thought he was tasting the Chateau Petrus,
he was in fact sipping a Forcas Dupres.
You see, we switched the labels.
What scamps you are!
There he was, proclaiming the Petrus to be the
superior wine and of course none of us could contain our laughter.
His face must have turned redder than a "Piechoné Logeavie".
Well of course, as so often happens,
rough house turns to tears.
At the end of the evening, Brewster tended his resignation.
That must have put a damper on the evening.
Well, not really. I'm the new president.
Kudos indeed.
Oh, oh, oh, is our dad and his lady friend still
playing telescope footsy? What was her name?
Irene. No, they've broken it off.
Already? I thought it was going so well.
Well it was, but then they spoke once and dad
said that she wasn't his type.
So, it's over - it's done!
He's completely cut her out of his life.
I just don't understand what would make him do that.
Oh, who knows why anybody does anything?
Remind me again what you do for a living?
You see the thing is, it was just one phone call.
I mean. How can anyone make a sound judgment about
another person on the basis of one phone call?
Remind me again what it is YOU do for a living?
Well anyway, I suppose it could be any number of
reasons. Fear of rejection, shyness...
Or maybe dad was telling the truth and
he just wasn't her type.
If only we knew someone who was...
I know! Maris's lovely Aunt Patrice is in town
visiting from Washington, D.C.
Oh, oh, oh, maybe we should set dad up with her.
No, Niles, I've met Aunt Patrice.
The woman is a loon.
Frasier, do this for me.
Every time Aunt Patrice comes to visit,
Maris makes all these plans
then she dives under the duvet with a two-week migraine
and I'm left holding the bag - literally and figuratively.
Oh, I don't think so, Niles.
I know dad, don't meddle.
Alright,
the least you could do is say hello to Aunt Patrice.
I'm not driving out to your house.
You don't have to. She's sitting out in the car.
You left her in the car?!
I cracked open a window.
Well, then she's fine.
No, no, no. Calm down son, listen to daddy.
It's just a bad dream. I promise you,
Senator Thurmond is not in your closet.
That's a good boy. Yes, okay you go back to bed now.
I love you too. Listen, I'll see you next
weekend. Okay, bye bye.
How's Freddie?
Oh, Frederick is fine. Oh, he sends his love.
He said to thank you for the toy gun you gave him.
At least what he can remember of it before
Lilith smashed it to bits with a croquet mallet.
Oh it's such a beautiful night.
The city is lit up like a jewel.
Oh look, there's Irene.
She's sitting in her window wearing a stunning
green dress. But her face, it's so sad.
Oh, oh, she's holding a note.
It says, "Martin, was it something I wrote?"
Will you cut it out? Irene is not
sitting in her window.
Oh alright dad, no she isn't, but she
might as well be, for god’s sakes.
That's gotta be what she's thinking!
Haven't you ever met a woman and then
decide she's not the one?
Yes, five years after I married her.
Hello there, Frasier.
Niles - I was specifically not expecting you.
Frasier, you remember Aunt Patrice.
Well, of course. Aunt Patrice, yes.
I don't recall really when we met but
I believe there was a lot of laughing and dancing.
My husband's funeral.
Yes... well, of course, the laughter was to hide our tears.
- Let me take your wrap.
- Thank you.
We were taking a drive and I thought,
"Why, we are just a couple of short ferry
rides from Frasier's," so...
we decided to pop over.
Niles, is this the charming gentleman
you were telling me about?
Oh, Patrice, you bloodhound.
You've treed another one!
Yes, this is my dad.
- How do you do, Patrice, I'm Martin Crane.
This is Daphne Moon.
- How do you do
- Nice to meet you.
- Please.
- Thank you!
So, what brings you to Seattle?
Well, I came to see Maris,
but the poor thing's taken to her bed again.
To this day I have no idea how tall she is.
Yes, so I've had Patrice all to myself
and we've had a great time, haven't we?
Well, if you call sitting in your waiting room
for four hours reading old magazines a great time,
well then yes - we had a laugh riot.
Now I know where Maris has he sense of humour.
Why don't I pop into the kitchen and gets
us all some refreshments?
A capital idea, and why don't Frasier
and I join you?
That'll give these kids some time
to get to know one another.
Niles, I distinctly told you not to bring her here.
I ran out of ways to entertain her.
We went to the arboretum, a fashion show,
a matinée of "La Cage Aux Folles" and we even spat
off the top of the Space Needle.
I'm sorry, I cracked.
Niles, that woman is certainly not dad's type.
You never know when love can bloom between
two people who seem so different on the surface.
Do you, Daphne?
To tell you the truth, I never thought opposites attract.
Neither do I, we are alike in so many ways.
Oh come on, Niles.
We can't leave dad out there alone with her any longer.
I'm sure they're doing just fine.
D’goo y’goo sp’geak g-sp’geak?
Oh Lord, I was afraid of this.
What?
D’goo y’goo sp’geak g-sp’geak?
Niles, I think she's having a stroke or something.
No, no dad. It's just G-speak.
Come again?
It's something Maris and Aunt Patrice
love to try out at parties.
Yes, you just speak a “g” in every syllable.
So you would be, "M’garg-tin Cr’gane."
Just say it with me, come on... M’garg-tin...
I don't think dad's interested.
Oh, b’ge ag sp’gort, Gniles.
What did she say?
She said, "Be a sport, Niles."
B’ge, agus, gesport, geda!
Dad, do you still have your billy club?
It’s in my top drawer.
Isn't it a hoot? You know,
it's all the rage in Washington.
Of course. You know who speaks it all the time?
G’George G’Step-gan-ogp-ogu-logs.
I found some pizza rolls in the back of the freezer,
but the expiration date was yesterday - are we game?
Er, that won't be necessary, Daphne.
We don't want to spoil our appetites for that
dinner we're about to leave for in twenty minutes.
Yeah, that's right, that dinner in... er... twenty minutes.
Oh Niles, I told you we shouldn't have just stopped by.
These people have plans.
How I envy them.
It was such a pleasure meeting you, Martin.
Likewise.
Oh, now, now, you can do better than that.
- I'll look forward to my next trip to Seattle.
- Great
Oh, and if you're ever in the Washington area -
I'm in the b’gook. Bye-bye.
What the hell was that?
I feel sorry for the poor thing.
I feel sorry for Niles.
That's who I'm talking about.
You know, I saw what you just did.
What did who do?
When Patrice went to hug you, you moved away.
Wouldn't you?
No, dad, no. You moved away from the window.
You didn't want Irene to see you with another woman.
You still care about her.
Hey, go chase yourself.
Dad, you do.
There's something stopping you from having
a relationship with this woman. Now, what is it?
- You're not going to let go of this thing, are you?
- No, I'm not!
Alright. Irene's middle name is Rose.
So? Rose is a nice name. Rose was mother's middle name.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Oh dad, you can't feel guilty about that.
Gee, mom's been gone for six years now.
Your feelings for Irene are totally
severed from your feelings for Mom.
You know, if she was here, if she could tell you,
she'd want you to get on with your life.
Okay, when I'm ready.
Thanks, Frasier. You know - I guess I don't say
it often enough but you're a good kid.
Well, thanks dad. You know, there's something
I don't say often enough...
There's nothing you don't say often enough.
Right, dad.
I couldn't help but overhear.
That was a very nice thing to say.
Yeah, he's a good kid.
The only strange part is -
I could have sworn Irene's middle name was Marie.
No, it isn't.
Well, I could go and check.
I still have all our notes in the trash.
Alright, alright... well,
I had to tell him something.
Look, I don't know why he just won't believe me
when I tell him that Irene just isn't my type.
You sure she isn't?
You're going to get on my back too?
No, but I was just wondering if the reason why things
didn't work out between you and Irene was, well...
What?
Well, maybe if you weren't just a little
self-conscious about your hip?
That's ridiculous.
Well, I'm glad to hear that, because you really
don't have anything to be self-conscious about, you know.
With that silvery mane, twinkling blue eyes
and whiskey voice. You're quite a package.
Yeah, I'm quite a catch.
You are. And you know as well as I do that history
is full of sexy limpers. For instance, Franklin Delano Roosevelt.
Of course he didn't limp so much as roll.
Oh, I know, Toulouse Lautrec.
Although he was rather a little person. Still,
he did rather well with the ladies.
Of course, they were all prostitutes.
But then again he was French and there's no explaining their taste.
What's your point?
I guess I don't have one.
It's just me running on the way I do.
But there is one last little thing:
I did notice that every time you went to the telescope
to see Irene - you hid your cane.
I just put it off to the side so
I wouldn't trip over the damn thing.
I knew there was a good reason.
It must feel awful silly when that cane trips you up.
Dad, dad, will you hurry up? She's going to be here any minute.
Alright, alright, Daphne. See if I've got this tie on right?
Just needs a minor adjustment.
What's all this hair on it?
The only way I can get the knot right is if I tie it on Eddie first.
Boy, it's a long time since I've been dating.
Have things changed much in the last forty years?
Well, the wardrobe’s a little different -
but your ultimate goal is still the same!
Dad, I'm glad you changed your mind about this.
Yeah, me too. Thanks for our little talk.
My pleasure.
- Now let's see, you got a hanky in there?
- Yep
- Terrific, alright. Have you got your keys?
- Yeah
You're not going to be out too late, are you?
- Frasier!
- Dad, I'm just busting your chops here.
- Oh, my God!
Will you two relax? A word to the wise, though:
if she asks you up to her place after dinner -
close the drapes!
Hi, Irene. Nice to finally meet you.