Listen to yourself, Bob!
You follow her to work, you eavesdrop on her calls, you open her mail
The minute you started doing these things, the relationship was over!
Thank you for your call.
Roz, I think we have time for one more?
Yes, Dr Crane.
On line four, we have Russell from Kirkland
Hello, Russell. This is Dr. Frasier Crane; I'm listening
Well, I've been feeling sort of, uh, you know, depressed lately.
My life's not going anywhere, er,
It's not that bad. It's just...
the same old apartment, same old job...
- sometimes it just
- Er, Russell, we're just about at the end of our hour.
Let me see if I can cut to the chase by using  myself as an example.
Six months ago, I was living in Boston.
My wife had left me, which was very painful.
Then she came back to me, which was excruciating.
On top of that, my practice had grown stagnant, and my social life consisted of...
hanging around a bar night after night.
You see, I was clinging to a life that wasn't working anymore
and I knew I had to do something, anything.
So, I ended the marriage once and for all,
packed up my things, and moved back here to my hometown of Seattle
Go Seahawks!
I took action, Russell.
And you can, too.
Move, change, do something,
if it's a mistake, do something else.
Will you do that, Russell?
Will you?
Russell...?
I think we lost him.
No, we cut to the news thirty seconds ago.
Oh, for crying out loud!
I finally bare my soul to all of Seattle,
and they're listening to Chopper Dave's "Rush-Hour Round-Up!"
Well, the rest of the show was pretty good.
It was a, a good show, wasn't it?
Here, your brother called.
Roz, in the trade we call that "avoidance".
Don't change the subject, tell me what you think.
Did I ever tell you what this little button does?
I am not a piece of Lalique.
I can handle criticism.
How was I today?
Let's see...
you dropped two commercials
you left a total of twenty-eight seconds of dead air,
you scrambled the station's call letters,
you spilled yogurt on the control board,
and you kept referring to Jerry,
with the identity crisis
as "Jeff".
- You say my brother called...
- Mmm, hmm
So I said to the gardener
"Yoshi, I do not want a Zen garden in my backyard.
If I want to rake gravel every ten minutes to maintain my inner harmony,
I'll move to Yokohama."
Well, this offends him, so he starts pulling up  Maris' prized Camellias by the handful.
Well, I coundn't stand for that,
so I marched right into the morning room and locked the door until he cooled down.
Tell me you would have handled it differently, Frasier.
Oh, I'm sorry, Niles
I didn't realise you'd stopped talking
You haven't heard a word I said.
Oh Niles, you're a psychiatrist
you know what it's like to listen to people prattling on endlessly about their mundane lives.
Touché
And on that subject, I heard your show today.
And?
You know what I think about pop psychiatry
Yes, I know what you think about everything.
When was the last time you had an unexpressed thought?
I'm having one now.
- You guys ready?
- Two café latte supremos
No, thank you
So, Frasier, How are you doing on your own?
I'm fine.
I love my new life.
I love the solitude.
I miss Frederick like the dickens, of course.
You know, he's quite a boy.
He's playing goalie on the peewee soccer team now.
Ha, he's a chip off the old block!
- You hated sports.
- So does he!
The fresh air's good for him.
Oh well, this has been fun, Frasier, but...
we have a problem, and that's why I thought we should talk.
Is it Dad?
Afraid so.
One of his buddies from the police force called this morning.
He went over to see him, and found him on the bathroom floor.
- Oh, my God!
- No, it's okay, he's fine.
What, his hip again?
Frasier, I don't think he can live alone anymore.
What can we do?
Well, I know this isn't going to be anyone's favourite solution,
but I took the liberty of checking out a few convalescent homes for him.
Oh Niles, a home? He's still a young man!
Well, you certainly can't take care of him
you're just getting your new life together.
Absolutely. Besides, we were never simpatico.
Of course, I can't take care of him.
Oh yes, yes, of course, of course...
Why?
Because dad doesn't get along with Maris.
Who does?
I thought you liked my Maris!
I do. I...
I like her from a distance.
You know, the way you like the sun.
Maris is like the sun.
Except without the warmth.
Well, then, we're agreed about what to do with dad.
"Golden Acres: We Care So You Don't Have To."
It says that?
Well, it might as well!
Alright, I'll make up the spare bedroom.
Oh, you're a good son, Frasier.
Two café supremos. Anything to eat?
No. I seem to have lost my appetite.
I'll have a large piece of cheesecake!
- Hi!
- We finally made it!
Ah, dad, dad, welcome to your new home!
Gee, you look great!
Don't B. S. me, I do not look great.
I spent Monday on the bathroom floor.
You can still se the tile marks on my face.
Gives you some idea about the ride over in the car.
Well, er, here we are...
Rest assured the refrigerator is stocked with your favourite beer, Ballantines.
- and we've got plenty of hot links and coleslaw...
- Mmm!
And I just rented a Charles Bronson movie for later!
Let's cut the "Welcome To Camp Crane" speech.
We all know why I'm here.
Your old man can't be left alone for ten minutes without falling on his ass
and Frasier got stuck with me.
Isn't that right?
- No, no!
I want you here! It'll give us a chance to get reacquainted!
That implies we were acquainted at one point.
Well, listen,
why don't I take dad's things into his new bachelor quarters
so you two scoundrels can plan some hijinks!
I think that wife of his is finally driving him nutso.
Yes, we Crane boys sure know how to marry.
Let me get you a beer, dad.
So, ah, what do you think of what I've done with the place, eh?
You know, every item has been carefully selected.
This lamp by Corbusier, the chair by Eames,
and this couch is an exact replica of the one Coco Chanel had in her Paris atelier.
Nothing matches.
Well, it's a , it's a style of decorating.
it's called "eclectic".
Well, the theory behind it is,
if you've got really fine pieces of furniture, it doesn't matter if they match
They will go together.
It's your money.
Dad, what do you think of the view?
Hey, that's the Space Needle there!
Oh, thanks for pointing that out.
Being born and raised here, I never would have known.
Delivery for Martin Crane.
- Oh, in here!
- Coming through!
Excuse me, excuse me, wait a minute
- Where d'you want it?
- Where's the TV?
- It's in that credenza.
- Point it at that thing.
What about this chair?
Ah, the chair? Here, let me get it out of your way.
Niles, Niles, Niles, be careful with that, that's a Wassily!
Oh, look, dad, as dear as I'm sure this, this peace is to you I,
I just don't think it goes with anything here!
I know, it's eclectic!
Niles, Niles, will you help me out here?
Ah, you're gonna have to run an extension cord over here so
I can plug in the vibrating part.
Oh yes, that will be the crowning touch.
Well, now that you two are settled in, I've got to run.
I'm late for my dysfunctional family seminar.
Dad, have you mentioned Eddie yet?
- Eddie?
- Ta-ta!
Oh, no, dad, no, no! Not Eddie!
But he's my best friend! Get me my beer, would you?
But he's weird!
He gives me the creeps! All he does is stare at me.
- Ah, it's just your imagination.
- No dad, no!
No, I'm sorry, but I am putting my foot down. Eddie is NOT moving in here.
Niles, there you are! I'm sorry I'm late
just as I was leaving, dad decided to cook lunch by the glow of a small kitchen fire!
Oh Niles, this last week with dad, it's, it's been a living hell!
When I'm there, I feel like my territory's being violated
when I'm not, I'm worried about what he's up to.
Look at me, look at me, I'm a nervous wreck!
I've got to do something to calm down. Double espresso, please!
Niles, you don't still have the brochures from those rest homes, do you?
Of course I do.
Don't forget, Maris is five years older than I am.
But you really think that's necessary?
I'm afraid I do.
I don't have my life anymore.
Tuesday night I gave up my tickets to the theatre, Wednesday it was the symphony...
That reminds me, weren't you going to the opera on Friday?
- Yes, here.
- Thank you.
Niles, you don't suppose there's a chance that you and Maris could...
Funny you should mention that.
Maris and I were just discussing this.
We feel we should do more to share the responsibility.
You mean you'd take him in?
Dear God, no!
But we would be willing to help you pay for a home care worker.
- A what?
You know, someone who cooks and cleans and can help dad with his physical theraphy.
These angels exist?
I know of an agency
let me arrange for them to send a few people over to meet with you.
Niles, I can't thank you enough!
I, I, I fell this overwhelming urge to hug you!
Remember what Mom always said:
"A handshake is as good as a hug."
Wise woman.
I have never been more impressed with a human being in my life!
Now what was wrong with that one?!
She was casing the joint.
"Casing the joint!"
She spent two years with Mother Teresa!
Well, if I were Mother Teresa, I'd check my jewellery box!
Oh, this is the last one. Can you please try to keep an open mind?
Oh! Hello - caught me with my hand in the biscuit tin!
I'm Daphne, Daphne Moon.
- Frasier Crane. Please come in.
- Thank you.
Eh, this is my father, Martin Crane. Dad, this is Daphne Moon.
Nice to meet you.
Oh, and who might this be?
That is Eddie.
I call him "Eddie Spaghetti".
Oh, he likes pasta?
No, he has worms.
Er, have a seat, Miss Moon.
Daphne. Thank you.
Oh, will you look at that. What a comfy chair!
It's like I always say,
start with a good piece and replace the rest when you can afford it.
Yes. Well, er,
perhaps you should start by telling us a little bit about yourself, Miss Moon.
Well, I'm originally from Manchester, England...
Oh really, did you hear that dad?
I'm three feet away. There's nothing wrong with my hearing.
I've only been in the U.S. for a few months,
but I have quite an extensive background in home care and physical therapy,
as you can see from my resume. I...
You were a policeman, weren't you?
Yeah - how'd you know?
I must confess - I'm a bit psychic.
It's nothing big, just little things I sense about people.
I mean, it's not like I can pick the lottery.
If I could, I wouldn't be talking to the likes of you two, now would I?
Yes. Perhaps I should describe the duties around here.
You would be responsible for...
Oh, wait a minute, I'm getting something on you...
You're a florist!
No, I'm a psychiatrist.
Well, it comes and goes.
Usually, it's strongest during my time of the month.
Oh, I guess I let a little secret put out there, didn't I?
It's safe with us.
Well, Miss Moon, I think we've learned just about all we need to know about you,
and a dash extra!
You're a dog, aren't you?
Well, we'll, er, we'll be calling you, Miss Moon.
Oh, why wait? You've got the job!
Oh, wonderful!
Er, excuse me, excuse me, aren't you just forgetting a little something here?
Don't you think we should talk about this in private?
Oh, of course you should, I completely understand.
I'll just pop into the loo.
You do have one, don't you?
- Yes.
- Oh, I love America...
Dad, what do you think you're doing?
You wanted me to pick one. I picked one.
But she's a kook! I don't like her!
Well, what difference does it make to you?
She's only gonna be here when you're not.
Then... what's my problem?
Daphne!
You've been retained.
Oh, wonderful!
I had a premonition.
Quelle surprise.
I'll move my things in tomorrow.
Oh, move in?
Oh, I'm sorry, there must be some misunderstanding. Er, This isn't a live-in position
Oh, dear. Well the lady at the agency...
The lady at the agency was wrong; this is just a part-time position.
I'm, I'm afraid it just won't work out.
Hold on there, Frasier, let's talk about this!
Dad, there's nothing to discuss!
You two should talk about this.
so I'll just pop back in here and enjoy some more of your African erotic art.
Daphne, Daphne, I think it would be best if you leave.
Oh well, alright then.
Don't be alarmed. We'll contact you.
If not by telephone then, er, through the toaster.
Dad, I'm not having another person living in this house!
Give me one good reason why not!
Well, for one thing, there's no room for her!
What about that room right across the hall from mine?
My study? You expect me to give up my study
the place where I read, where I do my most profound thinking?
Ah, use the can like the rest of the world!
You'll adjust!
I don't want to adjust! I've done enough adjusting!
I'm in a new city, I've got a new job, I'm separated from my little boy,
which in itself is enough to drive me nuts.
And now my father and his dog are living with me!
Well, that's enough on my plate, thank you.
The whole idea of getting somebody in here was to help ease my burden, not to add to it!
Oh, do you hear that, Eddie? We're a burden.
Oh dad, dad you're, you're twisting my words!
I meant burden in its most positive sense!
As in, "Gee, what a lovely burden?"
Something like that, yes!
Well, you're not the only one who got screwed here, you know.
Two years ago I'm sailing toward retirement and some punk robbing a convenience store puts a bullet in my hip.
Next thing you know, I'm trading in my golf clubs for one of these.
Well, I had plans too, you know!
And this may come as a shock to you, sonny boy, but one of them wasn't living with you.
I'm just trying to do the right thing, here.
I'm trying to be The Good Son.
Oh, don't worry, son.
After I'm gone you can live guilt-free,
knowing you've done right by your pop.
You think that's what this is about, guilt?
Isn't it?
Of course it is!
But the point is, I did it! I took you in!
And I've got news for you - I wanted to do it!
Because you're my father.
And how do you repay me?
Ever since you've moved in here it's been a snide comment about this or a smart little put-down about that.
Well, I've done my best to make a home here for you,
and once, just once, would it have killed you to say "thank you?"
One lousy "thank you?"
Come on, Eddie, it's past your dinner time.
I'm going out.
They have got to move the bathroom closer to the studio!
We'll be right back after these messages.
Can't I put that on tape?!
What's eating you?
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's just this thing with my father and this, this person he wants to hire.
I thought I'd started my life with a clean slate.
I had a picture of what it was going to be like, and then,
I don't know...
Ever heard of Lupe Velez?
Who?
Lupe Velez - the movie star in the '30s.
Well, her career hit the skids,
so she decided she's make one final stab at immortality.
She figured if she couldn't be remembered for her movies,
she'd be remembered for the way she died.
And all Lupe wanted was to be remembered.
So, she plans this lavish suicide
flowers, candles, silk sheets, white satin gown, full hair and makeup, the works.
She takes the overdose of pills,
lays on the bed,
and imagines how beautiful she's going to look on the front page of tomorrow's newspaper.
Unfortunately,
the pills don't sit well with the Enchilada combo plate she sadly chose as her last meal.
She stumbles to the bathroom,
trips and goes head-first in the toilet,
and that's how they found her.
Is there a reason you're telling me this story?
Yes.
Even though things may not happen like we planned,
they can work out anyway.
Remind me again how it worked for Lupe,
last seen with her head in the toilet?
All she wanted was to be remembered.
Will you ever forget that story?
We're back.
Roz, who's our next caller?
We have Martin on line one.
He's having a problem with his son.
Hello, Martin. This is Dr. Frasier Crane; I'm listening.
I'm a first-time caller.
Welcome to the show. How can I help you?
I've just move in with my son and er,
it ain't working. There's a lot of tension between us.
I can imagine.
Why do you think that's so?
I guess I didn't see he had a whole new life planned for himself,
and I kinda got in the way.
Well, these things are a two-way street.
Perhaps your son wasn't sensitive enough to see how your life was changing.
You got that right! I've been telling him that since I got there!
I'm sure he appreciated your candour.
Well, maybe sometimes I oughta just learn how to keep my trap shut.
That's good advice for us all.
Anything else?
Yeah, I'm worried my son doesn't know that I really appreciate what he's doing for me.
Why don't you tell him?
Well, you know how it is with fathers and sons, it...
I have trouble saying that stuff.
Well, if it helps, I suspect your son already knows how you feel.
Is that all?
Yeah, that's it. Thank you, Dr. Crane.
My pleasure, Martin.
Did you hear what I said? I said "thank you!"
Yes, I heard.
Dr. Crane, we have Claire on line four.
She's having a problem getting over a relationship.
Hello, Claire. I'm listening.
I'm a, well, I'm a mess!
Eight months ago my boyfriend and I broke up,
and I just can't get over it.
The pain isn't going away. It's almost like I'm in mourning or something.
Claire, you are in mourning.
But you're not mourning the loss of your boyfriend...
You're mourning the loss of what you thought your life was going to be.
Let it go.
Things don't always work out how you planned;
that's not necessarily bad.
Things have a way or working out anyway.
Have you ever heard of Lupe Velez?