Dad, he's doing it again.
Must this dog stare at me all the time?
I don't know. Eddie - must ya?
Apparently he must.
What is so fascinating about me? What is it?
In you eyes is my head a large piece of kibble?
Am I some sort of canine enigma?
Think about it, get back to me.
Here we are, gents, dinner's up.
Can I give you a hand clearing up your papers?
No, you better let me.
I need to keep these in a particular order.
What is all this, anyway?
Oh, it's an old case of mine from the police force
the "Weeping Lotus" murder.
Dad, I can't believe you're still
trotting this old thing up.
He's been trying to solve this case for twenty years.
Yeah, and I'm not stopping until I do solve it.
You develop certain instincts
when you're a cop.
And my instinct tells me that
this case can be cracked.
There just must be one small thing
I keep overlooking.
There is - who the murderer was.
It's nice you still so dedicated.
It's a hobby.
Some guys build a boat in their garage,
I try to figure out who a maniac
would kill a hooker
and try to stuff her entire body
into a bowling bag.
It's relaxing!
- Hello, Niles.
- Sorry I'm late, Frasier.
Just as we were leaving,
Maris had a run-in with a rude directory assistance operator
and it shattered her calm.
Have you ever considered that maybe
Maris is a bit high strung?
Maybe she should see someone.
She's seen everyone, why do you think
she was calling directory assistance?
Evening, Dr. Crane.
Hello, Daphne. It's so good to see you again.
What an enchanting scent you're wearing.
Must be the ranch dressing.
Won't Mrs. Crane be coming?
No, I'm afraid not.
And please, no more of this "Doctor"
and "Mrs. Crane" formality.
To you, it's Niles and...
- Maris.
- Yes, Maris.
Glad you could join us, Niles.
Oh, I wouldn't have missed it.
Well, I guess the food's all ready:
why don't we just go ahead and start?
Well, enjoy.
Where are you going?
I thought I'd have mine in the kitchen.
Don't be ridiculous.
Yes, we can't have you eating
by yourself in the kitchen.
I'll join you.
No. We're all eating right here,
like a family, end of discussion.
Well, isn't this nice? Feels just like home.
- I'm famished.
- Me, too.
You boys still say a prayer before you eat?
- Oh, yes...
- Yeah...
We thank you, Lord, for the food we're about to eat.
You have blessed our table with your palm.
And thank you, Lord, for bringing this family together
and we also thank you for the other gifts
you have given to us.
And may we always be able to share
with those less fortunate...
OH, WILL YOU STOP STARING!
I wasn't staring!
Amen.
So Frasier, did you happen to read Derek Mann's column today?
You were mentioned.
No, I missed it.
Just as well, it wasn't flattering.
Well, I still would have liked to have seen it anyway.
Oh, why didn't you say so?
If I may ask, who's Derek Mann?
He writes that "Mann About Town" column for the Times.
The things that guys comes out with,
sometimes he's really funny...
what did he say about you?
"I hate Frasier Crane."
Oh, sorry.
That's it. "I hate Frasier Crane." That's it?
Oh, don't let it bother you.
Well, actually it doesn't, dad.
I knew when I chose a career in the public eye
that I'd be open to certain criticisms,
it's the price I pay for my celebrity.
Thank you, Niles, for bringing me the paper,
and thank you for highlighting it in yellow!
Now, who would like some wine?
Oh, I'll have some.
Daphne, the salad is exquisite.
Now why would he say that?
Must be the carrots, he always did like them.
Not the salad, Derek Mann.
I mean, why would he write a thing like that?
I've never done anything to him,
the attack is totally unwarranted.
I'm a healer, for God's sake.
Oh, for crying out loud!
Dad, I have every right to feel upset about this...
I will not enjoy my dinner until
this is where it belongs - in the trash.
Oh, oh, there was an article in there I wanted to save.
- On what?
- Nothing.
- Come on, I'm interested.
- Oh, let's drop it.
Why can't you tell me?
All right, it was all about Margaret Thatcher's secret
for growing prize-winning zinnias. Are you happy?
Not really.
All right, Lorraine. Now, calm down and try and listen to
what I'm going to say to you. Will you do that?
Okay.
All right, good girl. Now your problem...
Oh my gosh, another call waiting - someone else
trying to get through.
Do you mind if I take It?
No, no. Go right ahead.
Well, certainly a very interesting situation
she's got herself into.
Don't you think so, Roz?
- Yes.
- Okay, I'm back.
All right, Lorraine. Now listen very carefully to what
I'm going to tell you. Your problem seems...
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll be right back.
For someone who's got so many problems she certainly is popular.
Okay, go ahead Dr. Crane. I'm here. Oh,
I don't believe it - another call.
Hold it there, Lorraine.
The reason why you want to take that other call
is the same reason that you want to change career
and break up with your boyfriend.
You're obsessed with what you think you're missing.
The better offer, the call on the other line.
Well, you've got to take one call at a time from now on.
Fully explore and experience each one in its turn
and you'll be a stronger person for it.
Do you follow me, Lorraine?
Okay, I'm back!
Thank you for your call.
Well, we've only got two minutes left,
so I would like to end today's program on a personal note.
As some of you may know, yesterday I was mentioned
in Derek Mann's "Mann About Town" column.
He said, and I quote, "I Hate Frasier Crane"...
"I Hate Frasier Crane".
What trenchant criticism.
Move aside Voltaire, step back in the shadows H.L. Mencken,
there's a new kid in town.
One can only wonder how many hours Derek Mann sat
in the glow of his computer screen before...
...before his trembling fingers sprang to life
and pecked out this chef t'ouerve: "I Hate Frasier Crane."
A lesser critic would have wasted our time
by presenting a well thought-out, point by point,
constructive critique of this show.
No, not our Mr. Mann.
So dear listeners, when Mr. Mann's column arrives on your doorstep -
read it, enjoy it, but above all, treasure it.
For one day this man will be joining the Pantheon of the immortals.
And if we're lucky...
it'll be one day soon.
I'm Dr. Frasier Crane.
Frasier, how funny running into you here.
I'm always here.
Yes well, you weren't here twenty minutes ago:
have you seen today's "Times"?
No.
Lucky for you I saved you this copy.
Take a look at Derek Mann's column.
You know, this is the second time in as many days
that you have given me a paper.
Have you ever considered getting yourself a route?
Hello, I don't believe we've met.
Yes, we have, Niles, three or four times. Roz Doyle.
Oh, of course. It was at the... it was during the...
well, I'm far too successful to feel awkward.
Where did we meet?
The radio station.
Ah, I'll take your word for it. Nice to see you again.
Aparently Mr. Mann heard your program yesterday.
So I see.
"Yesterday afternoon, Dr. Frasier Crane got on my case
for not given him a point by point criticism of his radio show.
Well, he asked for it, so here goes."
Oh my god, his entire column is about your show.
Not very flattering either.
Towards the end he even attacks your
"dimwitted sidekick call screener."
That's me!
Oh, now I remember you!
"It's hard to say what I hate most about Crane's show...
his pompous, sanctimonious style, his constant self-congratulatory
references to his own life, or his voice:
a mock-sympathetic tone so sickly sweet one wonders
if the man graduated from medical school or from some mind-controlling cult."
It's continued on twelve.
I've read enough!
Can I get you folks anything?
How can the man thing something like that?
It's my job, I'm a waiter.
We don't want anything, thank you.
Listen Frasier, I know this stinks,
but in a couple of days it'll blow over.
Oh, perhaps you're right.
As angry as it makes me, to retaliate would be to stoop to his level.
So the best response is no response at all.
"Pompous and sanctimonious," am I?
Well, this Mann character can't even write
grammatical sentences!
Every five words there's another one of his precious "dot, dot, dots."
Must be because he likes making all those dots
with the crayon he writes this drivel with!
Dr. Crane, on line two we have Stewart who's
having a problem with delayed gratification.
Well, he's just going to have to wait!
I don't know who this Derek Mann think he is,
but if he thinks he can hide behind his newspaper like
some sniveling schoolchild cowering behind a tree,
then I say let's expose this Derek Mann for what he is:
not a man at all, but half a man!
Now what line did you say Stewart was on?
He hang up.
Well, I'm leaving all sorts of bodies in my wake today.
Let's see who's on line five.
Hello, this is Dr. Frasier Crane - I'm listening.
Good, because I was listening too.
And you are?
Derek Mann.
I see.
Look, nobody calls me half a man -
especially some Ivy League Twit.
So what do you say we settle this like men?
Are you implying that you want to fight me?
I'm not implying it, I'm saying it.
Fight, as in a fist fight?
No, I thought we might throw pies at each other!
So are you up to it, or aren't you man enough?
We'll be right back after these messages.
And we're back.
Well, we have a suprise caller on the line: Derek Mann.
So what's it going to be, Crane,
are you going to fight me or not?
Oh, you can't be serious.
Just like I figured, you're a chicken.
No, I just don't think that civilized
people behave that way.
You know, Roz, perhaps our listeners
have an opinion about that subject?
Who do we have on the line?
Well, lines one through eight are people
who think you're chicken.
You're chicken, Crane. Admit it!
I am not chicken!
We are mature thinking people, not cavemen!
Alright, if you want a fight so bad,
I'll give you a fight!
You just name the time and place!
Kinsley square, right outside your office,
by the old statue. Noon tomorrow. Don't back out!
I won't!
Don't you back out either because I know where your office is too,
and I know where you live, and I'll track you down!
Now who else out there wants a piece of me?!
Having a look at that old murder case again?
Yeah, I've dug out the old crime scene photos.
Well, don't be a greedy guts - let's have a look.
Her name was Helen.
Yeah, it was.
Ah, you must have seen it on some of the papers
I've had lying around here.
No, I just got this feeling when I touched the picture.
You're putting me on.
She had a lot of men in her life.
No kidding: she was a hooker!
No, I mean she had four brothers.
That's amazing.
She did have four brothers. What else are you getting?
Well, come on, tell me more.
I can't just turn it on and off like a faucet.
Give it a try, will you? Please.
What else are you getting?
Nothing.
No, wait, I see a man.
Yeah?
A well-dressed man.
- He's wearing wing tips and a trench coat.
- Yeah? Yeah?
He's getting off an elevator...
he's walking down a long hallway...
she doesn't know he's coming...
he's opening the door...
Hello, everyone.
Sometimes I get my signals crossed.
What's going on?
Well - unless you killed a hooker when
you were twelve - nothing much!
We heard your show today.
I just loved the way you handled that Derek Mann.
Ah. You made your old man proud.
Yet the best part was when he challenged you
to a fight and you stood right up to him.
Yes I did, didn't I?
Boy, I can't wait to see that.
Well, I'm not actually going to go through with it, dad.
What are you talking about?
Well, I already won our little war of words.
What would I stand to benefit by actually
going through with a fist fight?
Frasier, maybe I'm misunderstanding something here...
he challenged you and you're backing down?
Well, mature people are supposed to use their
intellect to settle their differences.
A man doesn't just turn his tail and run -
that's not the way I brought you up.
Are you encouraging me to fight?
Damn right I am - you gave the guy your word.
Yes, but I didn't even know what I was saying -
I hadn't even had lunch yet.
I might have known this would have happened.
It's Billy Kreizel all over again.
What did you say?
Something about Billy Kreizel, I believe.
I can't believe you're dragging that up -
that was thirty years ago.
Who's this Billy Kreizel?
Oh, he was this kid in fifth grade that used to torment me!
So one day Frasier made fun of Billy's crewcut.
Well, he started it by making fun of the
elbow patches on my blazer!
Well, the point is, they were supposed to meet
for a fight after school.
Only "Patches" here didn't show up!
I had a clarinet lesson!
You don't need to remind me of that!
Billy's old man was a cop, too.
Boy, the guys rode me about that excuse of yours for years.
Every time I couldn't make it out for a drink they say,
"What's the matter? You got a clarinet lesson?"
Couldn't you met Billy after the clarinet lesson?
Daphne, would you please excuse us for a moment!
Of course.
I have a feeling I'm going to be
excused quite a lot in the house.
Dad, I am sorry if I embarrassed you for not
fighting Billy Kreizel thirty years ago.
But the situation is not the same now.
It's exactly the same.
I am an adult now, I've been to medical school,
I hold a certain position in this city...
I do not settle my differences with brawling.
The man challenged you, you accepted.
Dad, I can't believe this.
You won't be happy until I come home with a black eye.
I just want you to do what you said you were going to do.
You know, you can talk about your medical school,
your intellect, your place in the city, but you know what?
It's all one big clarinet lesson...
I can't even look at you.
So, I step out of the shower, I look out the window
and I notice the garbage man looking right in at me.
So I say, "Did you get a good look?"
And he says, "Not completely, turn around."
The he smiled, and he's missing a tooth,
and that's when the romance went right out of it for me.
Roz, why are you telling me this story?
I'm trying to get your mind of the fact that in five minutes
you're going to walk out that square and get your clock cleaned.
Well, did it ever occurred to you that
I might actually win this fight?
Your shoe's untied.
If you fell for that one, you're going down
and you're going down hard.
Frasier, there's quite a crowd forming out there.
Secretaries with bag lunches, business men,
children with balloons...
All that's missing is a mariachi band.
They're setting up.
Well, I better go find a great place in the crowd.
I'll be off to the left, Frasier, if you tear
his ear off and want to throw it to a beautiful señorita.
Frasier, as your brother and as your friend -
why are you doing this?
- It's Billy Kreizel.
- Where?
He's not here, Niles.
It's just that I ran away from him when I was ten.
I remember.
You know, and I've been running ever since.
Well, this is where it stops.
I'm not running anymore.
What is it that makes us Crane boys such targets?
Chalk it up to randon violence!
Hey, there.
Dad? What are you doing here?
Look son, I said a couple of things
last night that maybe went over the line.
Look dad, if you were worried that you talked me
into something that I wasn't ready to do...
you're, you're wrong. You can relax.
I doing this for myself.
Good.
So. Who told you that I was going through with it, anyway?
Oh, let's just say a father knows certain things about his son.
Good news, I parked in front of a broken meter.
We're getting a freebie.
Well, good luck, Dr. Crane, with the fight.
Thank you, Daphne.
Any psychic predictions on the outcome?
Actually, yes. But don't worry. I'm frequently wrong.
Frasier, Frasier, come here,
there's something I want you to see.
There, the man standing to the left of the statue...
I recognize his picture from the newspaper,
that's Derek Mann.
He's gigantic!
My God, you could show a movie on his back.
You sure you want to go through with this?
- Yes, yes I am.
- Good.
Now, you'll be fine.
Just remember this is a street fight
and not a boxing match.
So fight dirty and throw the first punch!
I found that a swift knee to the groin
usually does the trick.
If you have any doubts, check with the fellow
in Manchester named Nigel Tavers.
Well, if we want an unobstructed view...
Look, I prefer if you guys stay here.
You'll only make me nervous.
Whatever you want.
- Well, wish me luck.
- Go
They've got a mariachi band out there!
Yes. I have to get their card,
I need someone for our summer barbaque.
Oh look, they're starting to fight.
Nah, they're just circling, sizing each other up.
Come on, Frasier. If you're gonna have it,
get him first.
- Is that the police?
- Yeah, what are they doing here?
They're breaking it up! Just when they were getting started.
Alright, alright, I'm coming along peacefully -
just let me get my jacket.
Relax, I'm not arresting you.
But I'm warning you that in this town
we don't settle our differences with street fights...
no matter who you are.
Well thank you, officer, you'll have no more trouble from me.
Okay.
Dad, dad, did you see me?
Look at me. Look. My hands are trembling,
my chest is pounding,
my mouth is all dry, my knees are like jello...
God, I feel great!
You did good.
Yeah. I was out there. I was raring to go, you saw that...
right? I was ready.
I know you were. You would have kicked his but!
From here to Tacoma.
I say we celebrate! Everyone, a round of victory lattes on me.
Thanks Harry, I owe you one.
No problem, Marty.
You cut it pretty close, though.
Another minutes and Frasier would have been in sidewalk.
Give me a break, I missing my lunch for this.
You can stand without a few lunches.
Say, some of the guys are getting together later
down at Duke's for a bear. Why don't you come along?
Yeah, maybe I will. And you know why I will?
'Cause the Crane boys don't take clarinet lessons anymore.
What the hell are you talking about?
Oh that's right, you weren't in my precinct.