No, i've never had a serious boyfriend.
No one's really been interested.
Men can be such pigs.
People did try to fix me up.
In manchester, me mum was steering
me towards the butcher's son.
Pasty little thing, didn't fancy him.
I suppose i like my gents
more on the manly side.
Was that a little swan you made?
No, it was a b-52.
Dr jennings rang.
Dad skipped his physical again!
No wonder he didn't want me
to go with him.
You know dad's aversion to doctors.
Why didn't you take him?
I had my "fear of abandonment"
workshop. I've already skipped twice.
Wait till your father gets here.
I'll give him a piece of my mind.
If only we knew
when he was about to arrive.
Hey!
How you doing, boy?
I'm glad to see you, too.
- How was your exam?
- Pretty routine.
- Ekg?
- Perfect.
- Blood pressure?
- Textbook.
Full blood panel?
I told them to take two -
they're small.
Oh, let's give a look.
Oh, look at this!
A nice big band-aid!
Nice try.
What'd you do that for?
Dr jennings' office said
you hadn't shown up today.
Why do you avoid the doctor?
Because i feel fine.
And i don't like dr jennings.
He's got a model of a colon on his desk.
He keeps his tongue depressors in it.
All right, dad.
Why don't you see my doctor?
- She's one of the finest in seattle.
- She? No, no, no way.
If a doctor's
going to have me bend over,
i want to look through
my legs and see wing tips.
Women have been poked and prodded
by male doctors for centuries.
I say it's high time
you gents went to a woman doctor.
See how you like waiting all naked
and helpless and goose-bumpy.
Niles, recommend someone.
Niles!
I'm sorry,
my mind was somewhere else.
Oh, i know who you should see!
Dr gary newman!
He's very successful. I saw
a lichtenstein hanging in his office.
A lichtenstein? He sounds perfect.
Ok. I'll make an appointment.
Just hang on a second.
I will escort you personally.
- Wonderful, i can't wait.
- Stop grumbling. It won't be so bad.
Unless you have to parade
around the office
in one of those gowns
where your bum peaks through.
What's dr newman's number?
Niles... niles!
Sorry, i must have drifted off again.
My appointment was meant to be
half an hour ago. Let's get out of here.
Relax. Read a magazine.
Here, take the cosmo quiz.
"Are your nipples sensitive?"
Do it quietly.
It's not an oral exam.
You haven't seen the second question.
Did you keep your patients waiting?
Just the compulsives.
It was part of their therapy.
Relax, i'll take care of it.
My father had an appointment
30 minutes ago.
The doctor's running late.
You'll be first when he gets in.
Where's he coming from, spokane?
From lake chelan.
Lake chelan? Ooh!
This guy must be terrific.
- So?
- He'll be here any minute.
I was just struck by
one of life's little ironies,
i remember you taking me to the doctor
and here i am taking you.
Like when i took you
for your first tetanus shot.
I was scared.
I remember you holding my hand.
You bent over, dropped your drawers.
You took your mind off the shot by
reciting the names of puccini's operas.
Right then,
i knew you'd never be a cop.
I'm serious, let's go!
I'll check if there's someone
substituting for him.
What are you here for?
Oh, lately, i've been having
this overall sluggish feeling.
It's hard even getting out of bed,
not to mention the cold weather.
It's really making my joints hurt.
I've started to notice
flaking spots on my skin.
What about you?
I have sensitive nipples.
The doctor won't be able
to make your appointment today.
Great! These big shot doctors
keep you waiting for an hour
and then they don't even show up.
Played a little slow on the golf course?
Arrogant jerk!
Dad, dad, dad. Dr newman is dead.
He died an hour ago.
I'm sure he was a good man.
He walks down his walkway,
he picks up his newspaper,
and bang,
he drops dead of a heart attack.
I pick up my newspaper every day,
and "the sunday times" is very heavy.
Well, these things happen.
How can you say that?
He wasn't old! He was my age!
What can i say? I don't think
about these things like you do.
Maybe it's because
you're 41 and i'm not.
Don't you ever think about dying?
Well, not me dying. But you know
what i have thought of lately?
I've been dating this older guy
and what if... you know...
we were in bed and he dropped dead?
It's a possibility.
Sometimes he starts breathing funny.
I don't know if he's having
a good time or if i've overexcited him.
Someone has
a very high opinion of herself.
Everybody's good at something.
Why is it that every time we talk,
we end up talking about your sex life?
Because i have one.
Thank you for coming.
- Hello.
- Hello, dr crane.
I was in the middle of my workout,
but i can always pump iron later.
I'll just fix us a snack.
"Pump iron" (!)
Niles, you don't even
pump your own gas.
All right.
What's this about getting
your affairs in order?
Dr newman dying so young
threw me for a loop.
I realised i hadn't made the
proper provisions for my own death.
Here we go.
- Allow me.
- Thanks.
I've prepared copies for you,
the location and numbers of my bank
accounts, my safety deposit keys,
the number for my attorney...
niles, what are you doing?
Oh, give me that!
I loosened it for him.
Now, my personal possessions.
This is for family only.
Please stay. I'll come to you later.
Dad, niles, put your names
on these stickers
and place them on the objects
you would like bequeathed to you.
I'm not putting my name on your stuff!
What if i die tomorrow?
You will argue over that african mask.
It'll never happen.
Niles, you can have it.
I don't want it.
Don't look at me. I throw a towel
over it when you're not home.
Ok, fine.
Well, now we come
to the issue of... my remains.
- Oh, jeez!
- It's all here in this easy-to-read binder.
This is taking it too far!
Look at this!
Burial... casket... caterers?
- Who are you using?
- Michaelson's.
They're very good.
- Bowtie pasta...
- and the asparagus tips...
excuse me! Excuse me!
Are we done?
There is just one more duck
to put in the row.
I've discovered that most
unexpected deaths occur in the home.
Daphne, this is where you come in,
the actual finding of the body.
Oh, save the best part for me, eh?
That's all right.
As a health-care provider,
i've had my share of patients die on me.
That's a comfort.
Maybe we should drop the subject.
This has made me feel better.
I can handle my mortality better now.
Enough about death!
Let's celebrate life
with this chateau certan '75!
No, not the '75.
That's too good for the likes of us.
Perhaps a beaujolais nouveau
would be more appropriate.
Eddie?
Oh, there you are. Come on, boy.
Frasier, what are you
still doing up?
Frasier!
Dad, please, shh.
I'm trying to listen to my heartbeat.
It's amazing, it can pump 1,800
gallons of blood each and every day
but just a tiny tear in the tiniest artery,
and poof you're gone.
I thought you were ok about this.
So did i.
What is the matter with me?
I thought that putting my affairs in order
would help me
to deal with this, but it hasn't.
I can't seem to get over the feeling
that something could happen to me.
Jeez, i'd miss so much.
I'd never get to see my son
hit his first home run.
That'd be a terrible thing
for a father to miss.
Tell me about it.
Look, let me tell you something.
There was this time, a while back,
seven or eight of us
were on this drug bust.
We went through the front door
and the first guy took one, he died.
When you're a cop,
you've got to handle things like that,
but i just couldn't get over it.
Every time i had to go
in a dark building, i froze.
I knew if i kept being afraid,
i'd never be able to do my job.
- So what did you do?
- I forced myself to forget it.
Next time i came to one of those doors,
i went right through it!
The fact that i got shot in the hip
was purely coincidental.
You were this close
to helping me.
Just because some doctor dies
doesn't mean you will.
Yeah, but he was just like me,
highly educated, sophisticated.
I saw his picture in a medical journal.
He even looked like me.
Same determined chin, sweater vest,
ever so slightly receding hairline.
You don't know his medical history.
Actually, you're onto
something there, dad. Yeah...
he could've had high blood pressure,
popped pills, drank like a fish.
Yeah, could be anything.
I'll find out what caused
his heart attack.
Then i can disassociate
myself from him.
There must be some explanation.
That's great, dad.
I feel better now.
You've got something
on your bathrobe.
"Niles".
The vultures are circling.
Come on, eddie.
hello.
I called earlier. Someone said
mrs newman would be here.
Please, come in. I'm allen freedman.
Gary was my cousin.
Dr frasier crane. My condolences.
I didn't know
mrs newman had company.
- It's shivah.
- Excuse me?
It's the jewish version of a wake.
Oh, yes, of course.
- I didn't realise gary was jewish.
- You're kidding?
We did spend a lot of time together.
Never on friday nights, of course.
This is a bad time.
Jill would love to know you came.
She's right over there.
- She looks busy. Well, i can wait.
- Will you excuse me?
May i help you?
Oh, this is a mirror. I thought maybe
you were having an unveiling later.
You're not jewish, are you?
No, no, my ex-wife is, though,
and thus my son is, which makes me
sort of, well... no, i'm not jewish.
We always cover mirrors at a shivah
so those grieving don't have to be
concerned with their appearances.
Well, you look very nice.
Oh, thank you.
It's been driving me crazy.
- I'm bobbie, gary's aunt.
- Dr frasier crane. My sympathies.
The doctor with the radio show?
- Did you know gary well?
- Oh, well. Yes, i did.
There was so much more
i wanted to know about the man.
I don't know... eh...
how was his health before he died?
- Excellent, he was never sick.
- Heart disease?
- High blood pressure or cholesterol?
- No.
I'm sorry,
i'm asking too many questions.
We doctors are always looking
for the answers.
- Oh, gail!
- Aunt bobbie!
I know, i know.
I'd like you to meet a friend of gary's,
dr frasier crane.
Dr crane? From the radio?
Yes. I'm sorry for your loss.
I love your show!
Oh, i'm sorry. When i went to pick up
this linzer torte, i thought of gary and...
so gary liked fattening desserts?
Oh, no. If he knew
i brought this here, he'd kill me.
Gary was a health fanatic.
A vegetarian.
We played basketball every sunday.
So he was sedentary all week
and then burning up
the court on sundays?
No, he played four times a week
if he wasn't at the gym working out.
- Gary was in phenomenal shape.
- Didn't smoke, never touched coffee.
He had less than 10% body fat.
My goodness, has anybody
checked to see if he's really dead?
I'm... i'm sure they did check.
Those people are very thorough.
Oh, my, is that kugel? Excuse me.
Mrs newman. I'm dr frasier crane.
I was a friend of your husband's.
- Dr crane! From...
- yes, the radio.
- Gary never mentioned you.
- Well, we weren't actually friends.
He had an office
in my brother's building.
You took the time to come here!
His own partner
stayed only 15 minutes.
Well, there is a reason
i came to talk to you.
- Which is?
- It's about gary.
- About how he...
- yes?
I'm sorry i bothered you.
I just came to offer my sympathies.
No, wait, um...
dr crane...
i listen to you all the time and...
well, maybe you could help me.
What would you tell
someone who called in
and said they can't get over
why someone died?
I keep running this over and over
in my mind
and i just can't understand
how someone like gary,
who did everything right,
can just die.
I can't make any sense of it.
Mrs newman...
i know you'd like me to come up with
an answer to this whole thing,
but i don't have one.
Someone who consumes
cigarettes and burgers can live to be 83
and then someone who takes care
of himself can die at 41.
It's unfair.
Well, there's no explanation for it.
Believe me, i've checked.
But i suppose the best we can do
is live for the little joys and surprises
that life affords us.
You can't spend your life
being obsessed with death.
You're not jewish, are you?
No, i'm not, but...
well, thank you
for letting me be here today.
Thank you for coming, dr crane.
Oh, dr crane!
It was very nice what you said
about living life for the little
joys and surprises it can give us.
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- If only i believed it myself.
- Excuse me.
Um, this is clearly
the most inappropriate thing
i've ever done in my life,
but i was watching you
and i don't know if i'll ever
get the chance to see you again...
and something about you
tells me i'd like to.
If you'd like to get together
sometime, give me a call.
# Baby, i hear the blues a-calling
# tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# mercy!
# Maybe i seem i bit confused
# well, maybe... but i got you pegged!
# But i don't know what to do with those
# tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# they're calling again #
frasier has left the building.