Cappuccino, half-caf, non-fat milk,
enough foam
to be aesthetically pleasing.
- But it mustn't leave a moustache.
- Cinnamon or chocolate?
This is so complicated. Um, cinnamon.
- And you?
- I'll have the...
- look, it's daphne!
- Daphne!
Oh, hello! Thought you might be here.
Please, sit.
- I just stopped in for a bag of beans.
- Oh, well...
- can i help?
- Two pounds of...
Kenya blend.
- You remembered.
- What about my order?
Most people find it too intense.
I like something that holds its body
on me tongue.
We've spilt something. If you could...
would you like something robust,
if it didn't come on too strong?
If it was a little bit sweet
i might like it.
- Want to come try my special blend?
- I'd love to.
Oh, nothing for me, thanks!
That man is hitting on our daphne.
How does she stand it?
Apropos of nothing,
how are things with you and maris?
Are you implying my concern
for daphne is less than pure?
- You tell me.
- That's your shortcoming.
You're always suspicious.
You should have faith in people.
What's he doing?
- Bagging her beans.
- Oh!
I'm so excited.
Eric's taking me to hear his band.
It's not me night off,
but i'll switch if that's ok.
Isn't he lovely?
I have a nickname for him.
Eric the red. It favours him, doesn't it?
He looks like a viking.
- Well...
- well, ta-ta.
Oh, look at me. I forgot me beans.
Earth to daphne.
How could she like him? He has
community college written all over him.
Niles, this infatuation with daphne
is getting out of hand.
I didn't mind when it was flirtation,
but i can't help thinking that there's...
this is symptomatic of something
wrong between you and maris.
- Is it?
- I can't lie.
The truth is,
maris and i are in a bit of a rut.
We seem to have lapsed
into grey, numbing blandness.
That's perfectly normal
in a relationship of some years.
Try spicing things up a bit.
You mean, boudoir-wise?
- For starters, yeah.
- How?
Well...
the two of you could, uh...
well, you could...
it's you and maris, so you could...
i'm stumped.
How are you?
You wanna know?
Or are you making conversation?
If you wanna know, i'll tell you.
I was making conversation.
- Actually, i need advice.
- About what?
A subject in which
you're well versed: Sex.
How can i help you?
What do you do when the romance
goes out of a relationship?
I get dressed and go home.
Let's assume that you are capable
of a long-term relationship.
- How would you keep things cooking?
- Once a boyfriend took me to a bar.
We pretended we were strangers
picking each other up. That was hot.
You used fantasy, role-playing?
We had so much fun we tried it again.
Next time, he got so into it
he went home with another woman.
- I'm sorry.
- She was gorgeous.
One more drink
i'd have gone home with her.
Women need to see
the men they make love to
as exciting, romantic figures.
If you want to keep her interested,
create a fantasy for an evening.
Personally, i think you'd make
a very sexy gladiator.
- This is not for me. It's for niles.
- In that case, make it a gladiola.
Niles! Niles!
I'm sorry, but something horrible
has happened. Maris kicked me out.
Dear god, why? What for?
- Oh, my!
- What's going on out there? Niles?
Hello, dad.
- I don't want to know.
- Wait.
There's a reasonable explanation.
All right, but i reserve the right
to say "stop" at any time.
My plan was to leave
a treasure map downstairs for maris
with clues to lead her
to my whereabouts.
Then i'd hide in the linen closet
and wait for her to find me.
Dressed like that?
Actually, no. At the time,
i was wearing only my eye patch.
But is it still an eye patch
if you wear it on your...
stop!
There i was - ooh - with my little
plastic knife between my teeth.
Suddenly the closet door opened,
and i found myself
face to face with the maid.
She screamed - what i gather were
unflattering things - in guatemalan.
Maris stumbled upon the scene
and ordered me out of the house.
I barely had time to grab my pantaloons
and buckle my swash.
Dad! Dad, it's not funny.
Where did you get that stupid idea?
Frasier?
All i suggested was role-playing. You
came up with pirates of the caribbean.
- I've really bungled it, haven't i?
- These things happen.
Why don't you stay here now,
and tomorrow you'll sort things out?
What if we don't?
They could use an extra busboy
at the jolly roger.
I'll never be able to face the maid again.
I don't think it's your face
she'll remember.
Come on, niles.
Everybody has an embarrassing story.
Did i tell you about getting
locked out, in my underwear?
- Every thanksgiving.
- Don't worry,
i won't be telling that story this year.
Canadian goose down pillow,
egyptian cotton sheet,
- and a vicuna throw for if you're chilly.
- Perfect.
The service would've done you boys
the world of good.
- Good night!
- Good night.
Maris and i have had difficulties before,
but nothing this serious.
I feel terrible having her mad at me.
I wish i knew how to cry.
- Don't be embarrassed on my account.
- No, it's not that.
I just don't cry. It's not in my nature.
When maris' uncle died,
i shut my hand in a door,
just to make a decent show
at the funeral.
You're a complex little pirate,
aren't you?
- Well, good night, niles.
- Good night.
Thank you, eric.
I had a wonderful time.
Me, too.
- Well, good night.
- Good night.
We've only had a few dates
but i'm exhibiting
the three signs of love.
I can't stop thinking about him.
I can't eat
and i bought myself all new underwear.
We got to get her a girlfriend to talk to.
I called maris.
She's in arizona for the weekend.
- Why?
- She's flown to her favourite spa
to contemplate our marriage -
from a mud bath.
It'll be good for her.
Eric thinks the earth is grounding.
Eric, eric! Must everything
always be about eric?!
I suggest when maris returns
you have intensive couples therapy...
oh, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
She just needs to know you love her.
Buy her flowers. Fix a romantic dinner.
- That'll make any woman forgive you.
- That will work?
If it didn't, you wouldn't be here.
I'm willing to try, but our cook
walked out in sympathy with maris.
I could help you.
I have a late date with eric...
...ca, an elderly aunt erica,
...but i could have everything ready
by the time mrs crane arrives.
Well, thank you, daphne.
What does mrs crane like to eat?
You have free rein.
Bear in mind she can't have
shellfish, poultry, red meat, nitrates,
wheat, starch, sulphites, msg or dairy.
- Did i say nuts?
- Oh, i think that's implied.
Come in and warm yourself by the fire.
- How did you get so wet?
- One of your trees blew down.
- I had to walk the last 100 yards.
- Oh.
I must say, you have a beautiful home.
Thank you. It was in maris' family
for four generations.
When i was an intern i drove through
these hills, never dreaming i'd live here.
Then one afternoon, there was maris,
looking so helpless,
banging on the electric gates
with her little fists.
- They'd locked her in?
- No, no, that was much later.
This time she had been
at an antique mart.
Bought a rare bell jar once owned by
sylvia plath. The gates failed to open.
Naturally, i offered my assistance.
Our hands touched,
there was a sudden spark of electricity,
and, as if by magic, the gates parted.
- We took it as a sign.
- You were meant to be together.
Yes. We were married
just three short years later.
Look at this. It's beautiful.
It's a glockenspiel. We bought it
on our honeymoon in zurich.
I brought it down from the attic
to remind maris of better times.
It used to play beautiful music -
now it doesn't. How's that for irony?
Let's get you dry clothes, so you can
make dinner
and get home for your date.
Daphne?
- What is it?
- Nothing.
No, no. I'm a psychiatrist -
i can read the signs.
I'm sorry. I didn't want to spoil
your reunion with mrs crane,
but... eric broke up with me.
- He did?
- Yes.
He said he couldn't
commit to me and his music.
He had to stay focussed.
I know it was an excuse.
I've heard his music.
- He must have another girl.
- Oh... oh, oh, oh!
He's a fool. If he can't appreciate you,
you're better off without him.
Right now, i'm not so sure,
but thank you, dr crane.
Niles crane. Oh, maris!
Where... where are you?
What d'you mean
you can't come home?
It's not that bad a storm.
Oh, maris,
i really think you should come home.
No, of course. I don't want you
travelling if it's not safe.
Yes, i understand. See you tomorrow.
Well... seems like it's just the two of us.
You mean,
mrs crane won't be coming?
Oh my, there goes the electricity!
What do we do now?
The storm's really bad.
You shouldn't drive.
You just spend the night there.
Good night, daphne.
- You told her to spend the night?
- What's the problem?
- You know how niles feels about her.
- Relax, it's just a little crush.
Yes, niles is harmless. He'd never try
anything with maris around.
Maris is in arizona.
- I got to get daphne out of there!
- Why?
It's a recipe for disaster. All alone
in a gothic mansion on a rainy night.
It only lacks someone shouting
"heathcliff!" across the moors.
- Wait!
- You're not coming.
- Yes, i am.
- No, you're not.
- Oh, dr crane, you play beautifully.
- Thank you.
I found this in the guest room.
I hope it's all right.
I thought you'd put on maris' clothes.
Something bulky
from her wool collection.
She's quite a bit smaller than me.
This was all i could find that fit.
- Should i go look for something else?
- No... yes.
No, oh, no...
Ooh!
No. As long as it's big enough.
And... warm enough. And...
...silky enough. And...
i have to make a phone call.
'Hello, this is dr frasier crane.
'I'm listening.'
'Frasier, frasier?
'I'm having a little crisis here.
Actually a large crisis.
'It's no time to screen calls. Damn! '
- This is stupid.
- No.
- Nothing will happen between them.
- What if it does?
He's my brother, and he loves his wife.
Their marriage
isn't everyone's cup of tea,
but on some twisted, bizarre level
it works for them.
If niles hurts his marriage, he'd suffer.
I won't let him suffer.
You'll miss the roosevelt.
I let you come
if you agreed not to give directions.
It's just faster.
- Roosevelt will add ten minutes.
- In rain, it's faster.
- Spatial relationships change in rain?
- There's better traction.
If you had all-weather tyres
like i told you...
- come on!
- You had to buy some german thing...
we'd better make this last.
It's all that's left of the wood.
Don't worry.
If this runs out, there's an antique
sideboard that i think is reproduction.
Oh, it's eric, isn't it?
Don't know why i'm being so silly.
We weren't together long enough
for anything to happen.
Powerful feelings can come
from the promise of what might happen.
Anticipation makes all the little hairs
on your neck stand on end.
- Dr crane!
- Yes?
- We're losing the fire.
- No, we're not.
It's burning
with the heat of a thousand suns!
It's down to its last embers!
Well, then, i'll put some wood on it.
You flooded it.
You cannot flood a fuel-injected engine.
This is maddening. We're so close
to the house, i can see the gargoyles.
- If we'd taken roosevelt...
- we'd be stuck there.
- You made a mistake.
- That is it!
Call the auto club, i'll make a dash for it.
You should take the shortcut
by the side of the fountain.
Same to you!
I suppose i just fall in love too fast.
The minute i feel that spark
i give my heart away.
Daphne,
stop being so hard on yourself.
What you see as a fault
is also your greatest gift -
to be so open and warm and loving.
You're so kind, dr crane.
I'm glad we ended up like this tonight.
So am i.
It's just so nice to be with a man
you feel so comfortable with.
I feel very close to you.
I feel very close to you too, daphne.
It's easy being someone
you feel close to,
when you feel close to someone
who's so... close.
Dr crane,
your glockenspiel has sprung to life.
Oh, the clock!
My god, it hasn't run like this in years!
Maris will be delighted!
Maris!
You really love her, don't you?
You know, i do.
Love's a funny thing, isn't it?
Sometimes it's exciting, passionate.
Sometimes it's something else.
Something comfortable and familiar.
That newly exfoliated little face
staring at you
across the breakfast table.
Sharing a laugh when seeing someone
wearing white after labour day.
I hope some day,
some man will feel that way about me.
Oh! Daphne, don't worry.
You are a very special person.
Some day a man worthy of you
will come along.
Just as soon as the gods create him.
That's the loveliest thing
anyone's ever said to me.
Thank you. You're a good friend.
Stop!!!
Frasier!
- Have you gone mad? You'll regret it.
- What are you talking about?
The two of you alone.
The fire, the candlelight, the nightie!
Dr crane,
you didn't think dr crane and i...
dr crane! You have some nerve
to imply your brother
would do anything so deplorable!!
He just made a beautiful speech
about how much he loves his wife.
How he cherishes
her excruciating little face.
And how they laugh at white people.
- That didn't sound right.
- Close enough.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to suggest...
i wasn't implying...
then what was it
you wanted us to stop doing?
I wanted you to stop... uh...
standing in silence!
A night like this calls for music!
Daphne, wine for all of us.
Niles, join me at the piano, please.
- You sure everything's all right?
- Absolutely.
Frasier,
my glockenspiel is working again.
# Tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# mercy!
# Maybe i seem a bit confused
well, maybe, but i got you pegged
# but i don't know what to do with those
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# they're calling again #
frasier has left the building.