Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Shared by http://DJJ.HOME.SAPO.PT/
lt's 4:25, and this is Dr Frasier Crane.
- Who's our next caller?
- Hank has trouble with his neighbours.
Hello, Hank, l'm listening.
- 'Am l on?'
- Yes, you're on the air.
'Hello, am l on?'
Hank, listen. Turn down your radio
and just talk into your phone.
'Hello?'
You won't be able to hear yourself.
We're on a seven-second delay.
'Hello, can you hear me?'
For crying out loud! Thank you, Hank.
People, turn off your damn radios!
Ah, no, l mean just those of you
who are calling in!
Who's our next caller?
Marco has relationship problems.
Hello, Marco, l'm listening.
'l started seeing this woman
two years ago.
'l think it was two years.
lt was around Thanksgiving...
'Yeah,
the leaves were off the trees and...'
Close enough.
What is your problem?
'lt's not really my problem,
it's more like her problem.
- 'She's pressing me for a commitment.'
- What's holding you back?
'l want to keep my options open,
in case somebody better comes along.'
"Somebody better comes along."
"Somebody better comes along!"
Marco, do you hear yourself?
'No, l turned my radio off
after you blasted that other guy.'
Listen, l suggest you give
your motives a thorough examination,
and if you can't commit,
it's best for both of you to break it off.
- 'Yeah?'
- Yeah! Thank you for your call.
Tell me, what is it with guys like that?
Hey, Roz, you've been
around the block a few times.
Ever run into a guy like Marco?
Oh, they're all Marcos.
You can't swing
a dead cat without hitting a Marco.
lf that was so,
no one would be having a relationship.
Well, l'm not,
my sister's not, none of my friends are.
l've seen the future. lts name is Marco.
What do you think, Seattle?
Are there any non-Marcos out there,
or is Roz destined to live a life
of hopeless, loveless spinsterhood?
Back after this.
Gee, l just love it
when you include me in your show.
This is weird.
lt's not even Halloween yet.
Do we have to do this now?
Yes, if we want a picture
for the Christmas card.
Why can't we just do
what my wife and l did -
put Frasier and Niles, in matching
sweaters, on the old Packard.
Well, this year we're going to be
a little more artistic.
Where is Frasier? l could use help.
He's still napping.
My grandfather used to nap every day.
- He lived to be 93.
- Really?
He'd lie there on the sofa,
and you couldn't wake him.
Grammy would say,
"He might as well be a dead man."
Then, one day, we couldn't wake him.
He really was a dead man.
Poor Grammy. For weeks, she kept
insisting: "'E's napping, 'e's napping."
OK, l'm going to turn it on.
Oh, it's lovely!
# Deck the halls with boughs of holly
# Fa-la-la-la-la, la-la-la-la
# 'Tis the season to be jolly
# Don we now our gay apparel
# Fa-la-la-la-la, la-la-la-la... #
Excuse me, excuse me.
Exactly how long have l been asleep?
Good, you're up.
Now we can get this picture taken.
- What picture?
- The picture for the Christmas card.
Oh, right.
The theme is Santa's workshop.
Put on your little elf hats.
l'm not putting this on my head!
l'm a respected professional!
But if you don't, it'll look stupid!
The ship has already sailed on that one.
- Put the hat on!
- You can't tell me what to do.
l am telling you.
You can no longer sit me
on top of some stupid old Packard!
Boys, please, don't fight!
Are you forgetting what day it is?
lt's October 21!
- Can we just get the picture taken?
- l've got it all set.
15 seconds, gents.
Oh wait, where's Eddie?
ln the bathroom,
getting a drink. Eddie!
Well, l can always pray
there's a postal strike.
That's it for today.
This is Dr Frasier Crane saying,
"Go out there
and make it a great evening, Seattle."
Hey, there's a fan
in the hall who'd like your autograph.
Oh, God, save me
from my adoring fans.
Oh! But not from the adorable ones.
Hello. You wanted an autograph?
Uh, how should l make this out?
You disgust me, you parasitic fraud!
That's certainly different
from the usual "Best Regards".
For once you'll face the consequences
of hanging up on callers!
What consequences?
l'm Marco's girlfriend...
Excuse me, ex-girlfriend, thanks to you.
The Marco who didn't want to commit?
You damned radio shrinks.
You couldn't just tell him to stick with it!
That doesn't get big ratings. No!
"Get on with your life and ruin hers."
- That's entertainment.
- Hold on. Did you listen to the show?
- No, but Marco told me what you said.
- Oh, he did, did he?
Did he mention he only stayed
with you to keep his options open?
He said he only stayed with you
until somebody better came along.
- He said that?
- To most of Seattle.
Apparently, you're the only one
who missed it.
So,
it wasn't that he didn't want to commit.
He just didn't want to commit to me.
l'm sorry l had to tell you,
but at least now you know the truth.
Oh, no...
Don't...don't cry.
Look, you're...
You're in a place of business here.
Boy, l can really pick 'em, can't l?
Don't go there.
Look, this is not your fault.
You're a terrifically attractive young
woman, maybe a bit overemotional...
Oh, yes, there, there, shh.
- Listen, can l get you something?
- Mm-mm.
- A drink of water?
- No.
M & M's?
Plain or peanut?
- Whichever you like.
- Peanut.
God, l should have seen this coming.
He almost had a coronary,
when l brought a toothbrush over
to keep at his apartment.
- Thank you. You want one?
- Uh, no, thanks. Have a seat.
Listen, if he was that resistant,
why did you stay with him?
l had a lot invested in it.
Why settle for someone
who isn't madly in love with you?
Right now
l'm not sure there are any men
who are capable of falling madly in love.
There are.
Men and women
are basically the same.
We both need to be loved
and to love someone,
we both want to feel
that we matter to someone.
Making a commitment
to another human being
is the ultimate expression
of our humanity.
Wow.
Your wife is really lucky.
Well, l'm...
sure she'd say the same thing.
Especially now
that our marriage is over.
Maybe l will have one of those M & M's.
Oh, boy...
Why are relationships always so hard?
- Hey! You like the yellow ones too?
- People tell you they're the same.
- But they're not!
- No!
Relationships don't have to be hard.
l heard of a documented case where
a man and a woman met, got along,
and actually lived happily ever after.
l don't mind the happily-ever-after-part.
lt's the dating part.
lf l have to tell one more stranger
the story of my life
over Northern ltalian cuisine,
l'll choke on a breadstick!
l know. Maybe we could just
exchange résumés over appetisers.
- l usually say goodbye over appetisers.
- At least you're not stuck with the bill.
You haven't dated much lately,
have you?
No. l usually end up
in restaurants alone.
l can't do that.
l even turn on the TV at home
so it feels
like there's someone else there.
ls that what you'll be doing tonight?
Well, unless l just keep eating M & M's,
which is a distinct possibility.
Soft and supple, yet strong right down
to the beautiful almond-shaped nails.
- You really see all that in my hand?
- Mm-hm.
l'm late for work.
Wait. What are we doing tonight?
"Antonio's", "Le Cigare Volant"?
- Why don't we just stay in?
- That's a great idea!
l'll send Dad and Daphne to the movies.
l'll cook for you. Be at my place at 8:00.
l won't make it till 8:30. l must change.
No! Don't ever change.
l like you just the way you are.
Come on, l'm a little out of practice!
l'll see you later, OK?
Bye.
l'll dispense with
the usual adolescent teasing.
Who was that babe-o-rama?
You remind me of Bob Hope
when he dresses up as the Fonz.
- Her name is Catherine.
- How long have you known her?
- Three days.
- Have you two...?
- No. As if it's any of your business.
- But you're...?
Yes, soon!
- We are talking about...?
- Of course we are!
- Sex, right?
- Yes!
So... How did you two meet?
She came down to the radio station
to chew me out.
- You're kidding.
- No. Her boyfriend called the show.
l advised him to break up with her.
Frasier, where are your ethics?
You can't date someone
who's involved with your patient.
Marco is not a patient, he's a caller.
There's a huge difference.
l talked to him days before l met her.
Rationalisation, the last refuge of a...
l am not rationalising!
There is nothing wrong here!
As long as your conscience is clear.
Mine wouldn't be.
Well, frankly, l don't care
about your conscience.
l don't need your approval.
l don't need you for anything.
My car's in the shop.
l need a ride home tonight.
No problem.
l've got news for you,
Marco's on line two.
Marco?
The guy you got out of the
way so you could keep his girlfriend.
- Ten seconds.
- l'm not talking to him.
There's no way l'm talking to him!
Three, two...
Hi, we're back.
Roz, whom do we have on the line?
We have Marco on line two.
- Who's this on line three?
- Todd.
Oops, we lost Todd.
But lucky for you,
we still have Marco on line two.
Thank you, Roz.
- Hello, Marco.
- 'Hi, Dr Crane.
'l spoke to you and l took your advice -
l broke up with my girlfriend.'
Well, what can l say but
"Bravo, Marco"?
- Who's next?
- 'Wait!
'You haven't heard my problem.
She's already dating someone else.'
- lt makes me nuts.
- What makes you think that?
'The other night, l couldn't get her
on the phone. So l drove by her house,
'and l saw her outside
talking to some guy in a black BMW.'
Did you, er,
get a good look at the guy?
'No, it was too dark.
l think l made a big mistake, Doc.
'Should l ask her to take me back?'
No! l mean, what l mean is...
No. Marco, you don't want
your ex-girlfriend back -
you don't want
anybody else to have her.
- 'Well, l...'
- No, it's called "jealousy".
You must stop spying on her
and get on with your life.
Borrow a page from my book:
move to a new city. A new state.
Find out why
everyone's talking about Pittsburgh!
We'll be right back
after these messages.
What?
- 'Thanks for picking me up.'
- No problem.
Just a few miles out of my way.
At rush hour.
But l didn't mind, really. Gave me
a chance to listen to your show.
l see.
l just have one question for you.
Can you tell me
that your advice to Marco
was based on his best interests,
and not on your own?
That's an interesting question, Niles,
and l don't care.
l'm in love, and l don't care.
Catherine is mine now.
l'm in and Marco's out.
- You're insane!
- Perhaps, but you just ran a stop sign.
- Now we're in the intersection!
- Oh!
l tell you, Niles,
l haven't felt this way in ages.
There's an excitement about this.
l...l feel tingly.
- What does your stomach say?
- My stomach?
You know what l'm talking about.
Whenever you approached
a breach of ethics, you'd get queasy.
At least l didn't get
spontaneous nosebleeds.
Remember when we lifted
that dollar from Mom's purse,
we left a gruesome
trail back to the tree house that day.
But, you see, you've proved my point.
l'm not the least bit queasy, l'm fine.
My head, my heart,
my gastrointestinal system, all shout,
"lt's OK!"
Niles, is this a new car?
Yes, a patient of mine
got me a huge break on a lease.
Frasier, do you have a handkerchief?
Mm, that was the best
Salmon Marseille l've ever had.
You should try
my Salmon "Enchanted Evening".
- Tell me you didn't say that.
- Oh, it was just the Lafite talking.
Lafite, don't fail me now!
Oh, stop, stop!
So...have you ever
made love in the kitchen?
Well, the, uh...dishes are done.
Oh! Mm!
'Ewww!'
'What?'
l'm sorry,
l'm suddenly feeling a little queasy. l...
Maybe l'm just not a kitchen person.
Well, uh...
Maybe you're just...
a little too warm, huh?
- Yeah?
- Oh, yeah.
Yeah, that's it.
- You look awfully warm too.
- Oh, l am! Yes.
- Oh, my God!
- Oh! Oh!
Ooh!
l'm sorry.
Would you mind
if we moved to the sofa?
l won't be outperformed
by a Barcalounger.
Oh... Oh!
This is better.
Oh, yes. Mm...
Mm...
Ewww!
Ah...
What? Was l kneeling on you?
l need some fresh air. Are you OK?
l'm fine.
Oh, damn, it wasn't the fish!
There's a bug going round.
- lt's not a bug.
- What is it, then?
lt's us.
Every time we touch and kiss,
l get queasy.
The thought of making love to me
makes you sick to your stomach?
Yes, but don't take it personally.
lt's... lt's not you, it's me.
Every time l come close
to breaching my ethics, l get sick.
What?
Marco called and said
he wanted to get back with you.
- l told him not to.
- So?
Maybe l told him that not because
it was good for him but good for me.
Oh, Frasier!
Who cares?
l care. Any psychiatrist worth his salt
would care.
That's why we don't get involved
with our patients. Or their girlfriends.
- Do you want to break up with me?
- l don't want to.
l have to. lf l don't,
l'll throw up all over your shoes.
l can't believe this is happening.
How can this be so easy for you?
Easy? This is killing me!
l want to carry you
to that Eames classic
and show you why it's
the best-engineered chair in the world!
- Why don't you, then?
- l told you, l can't!
Oh! And nothing l can say
will change your mind?
l'm sorry.
Well, thank you, Dr Crane!
First you screw things up with Marco
and now you're dumping me!
God, and to think
l was going to have sex with you!
And it was going to be hot.
Oh, like you've never had before!
l'm talking steamy,
sweat dripping down your back,
neighbours pounding on the walls.
lllegal in 48 states kind of sex!
But, hey. You're OK.
You won't be alone tonight.
No, you've got your ethics!
Oh!
Oh, by the way,
The fish was dry.
Oh, that was a cheap shot!
How l envy you, Eddie.
The biggest questions you face are:
"Who's going to walk me?
Who's going to feed me?"
l won't know that kind of joy
for another 40 years.
# Baby, l hear the blues a-calling
Tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# Quite stylish
# Maybe l seem a bit confused
Well, maybe, but l got you pegged!
# But l don't know what do with those
Tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# They're calling again #
Good night, Seattle, we love you!
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
www.tvsubtitles.net