- Good show today, Roz.
- Yeah.
- Say, why all the catalogues?
- I need to buy a present.
Tiffany, Cartier, Neiman Marcus...
- Anything look good to you here?
- Well, let's see.
Who could we be shopping for?
Perhaps a honey-voiced
radio therapist
whose birthday's
just around the corner?
No, this present is not for you.
It's for your brother.
Oh, all right, Roz, listen,
don't be coy.
I think it's very smart,
your fishing for hints like this.
You want to avoid a misstep
like you made last year.
What misstep?
You said you loved Pagliacci.
Yes, the opera, not the little
porcelain crying clown figurine.
Look, Niles pulled some strings
and got Alice on a list
for a really good preschool
so I thought I'd get him
a thank-you gift.
That's why I was asking for your
stupid opinion in the first place.
- But forget it.
- All right, fine.
- I'll figure it out for myself.
- Have it your own way. Fine.
But I tell you what, don't get him
a porcelain Pagliacci.
He already has one.
- Hi, Dad.
- Hey, Fras.
You'll never guess who I just saw.
I went over for a cup of coffee
with Hank.
You remember Hank?
He's the security guard who works
at Weston's Jewellery Store.
Anyway, we were in his booth,
just shooting the breeze and looking
at the surveillance monitors,
and who do I see buying
an engagement ring but Donny.
As in Daphne and Donny.
Donny?
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
Engagement rings is Tina's counter.
We use the zoom lens on her.
- Dad, I'm shocked.
- Oh, no, it's just innocent fun.
She only dresses that way because
she knows we're looking at her.
I mean about Daphne and Donny.
I didn't realize they were this serious.
- They spend all that time together.
- This is gonna crush Niles.
- Yeah, I know.
- Do you think we should tell him?
No, it's none of our business.
We do not tell Niles
and we definitely do not tell Daphne.
- Tell Daphne what?
- Nothing.
- It's bad news, isn't it?
- No, it's not bad news.
Is it about my mum? Did they find
something during her physical?
They did, didn't they?
I have to call her.
No, Daphne, no, no, no.
There is absolutely no news.
And even if there were,
it's not up to us to tell you about it.
Who should tell me, then?
Head surgeon?
Our family minister?
- No!
The mortician? God, I've gotta pack.
I hope I'm not too late.
I just saw Donny
buying you an engagement ring.
That is the news.
Really?
I don't believe it.
I'm gonna get married.
God, I'm so excited.
I'm gonna be a missus.
Mrs. Donny Douglas.
Mrs. Donald Ronald Douglas.
Oh, God!
Yes, well, I guess we're
gonna have to prepare Niles now.
- He's on his way over here.
- Yeah, well, don't tell him here.
I don't want him going to pieces
in front of Daphne.
Yes, I guess I can tell him
at the restaurant.
Well, just don't take him
to one of those fancy wine bistros
that you guys love.
News like this calls for
hard liquor in big glasses.
Wherever it is, I just think
it's best that Niles hear it from me
- and not from Daphne.
- Hear what from Daphne?
I'll tell you at the restaurant.
No, I don't wanna wait
till we get to the bistro.
- You're just gonna have to wait.
- And you're not going to any bistro.
Well, fine. If you won't tell me,
then I'll just ask Daphne myself.
Niles, wait. The truth is...
- Daphne's...
- Mother is dying.
- Dear God.
- Yes, tragic, isn't it?
Yes.
She's gonna need all the support
that we can give her.
Evening, Dr. Crane.
Come on, Niles,
we don't wanna lose our table.
- Did you hear the news?
- I just did. What can I say?
I've thought about this day
ever since I was a little girl.
I'm sure you have.
It's even better
than I thought it would be.
I can already picture the big day.
Beautiful flowers everywhere,
a sea of smiling faces.
I suppose everyone
will want to have their picture taken
with the lady of the hour.
You know, maybe Daphne
could use a little quiet time.
No, who could be quiet? I'm so happy.
Donny's gonna ask me to marry him.
- What?
- Now, come the big day,
you'll all sit right up front
with my family
because that's
what you are to me. Family.
Well, that's what you are
to us too, Daph.
Oh, I am so thrilled for you.
Oh, thank you. Thank you, all.
I'm sorry, son.
- You wanna talk?
- No.
Frasier, if you wouldn't mind,
I'm gonna cancel dinner.
- I need to be alone.
- Of course, Niles.
Look, if you need me, call.
Poor kid.
He'll be all right, Dad.
You know, Niles is a lot stronger
than we give him credit for.
Hello?
Hold the elevator. I'll be right there.
Hang in there, son, he's on his way.
Yes?
This came while you were in session.
It's from a Roz Doyle.
She wanted to thank you
for a favour that you did.
- I'll be off now.
- All right. Good night, Mrs. Woodson.
Come in, Mrs. Woodson.
I'm afraid it's me, Dr. Crane.
Daphne. What are you doing here?
I know I should've called first,
but I need to talk to you.
It's sort of a private matter
and I hoped we could talk here.
Well, it's not really appropriate for me
to act as your therapist,
but if it's just advice
from a friend that you need,
I'm happy to lend an ear.
What's on your mind?
Well...
I don't think I can marry Donny.
I think there's someone else
I'm meant to be with.
Who is it?
- It's Mrs...
- Oh, for God's sake, go home!
Sorry for that interruption.
Anyway, this man
you're meant to be with, who is he?
I'm afraid I can't say.
Yes, you can.
We're the only ones here.
Are you sure you won't laugh at me?
How could you think
I would laugh at you?
Most people would if I told them
I'd seen the love of my life
in a psychic vision.
Well, most people are... What?
You know how I have these
psychic flashes from time to time.
Well, I had one last night.
You had a vision about
the love of your life. Okay.
Well, tell me about it. Here.
And, Daphne,
omit nothing.
All right.
I was straightening up the living room
when I had a sudden flash
of a wedding ceremony
for Donny and me.
Oh, it was lovely.
The church was packed
to the rafters.
Me mum was there
in a peach silk looking very smart,
me brothers in their suits...
I may have led you
in the wrong direction
with the omit-nothing business.
Feel free to skip ahead.
Right.
Well, my father had just
walked me up to the altar
and I was standing there
facing Donny.
He looked quite natty.
Black tuxedo, tails, very slender.
We're skipping.
Well, then the vicar
began the ceremony.
He asked if anyone had a reason
why we shouldn't wed
and that's when this...
Well, this person stood up
and said that he did.
He said that
he was the true love of my life,
though he'd never had the courage
to say so.
I feel so awkward telling you all this.
Don't. I think I know
who this person is.
- You do?
- Yes.
Well, I don't see how you could.
I couldn't tell myself.
He was standing in the shadows
and I couldn't see his face.
All I could make out was that
he was wearing a red bow tie.
I don't have
a clue why anyone would wear
such a thing to a wedding.
Heavens, I can't believe I'm talking
about my visions to a psychiatrist.
Your brother would think I was daft.
Well, Frasier's never really shared
my mystical, spiritual bent.
This does mean I'm gonna have
to turn down Donny's proposal.
- You don't think that would be crazy?
- Not at all.
Then you really believe
in psychic visions too?
I do.
Thank you, Dr. Crane.
That means a lot to me.
Of course, if I can't marry Donny,
I can't very well go on dating him.
- That would just be leading him on.
- That's very true.
I don't know how
I'm gonna break it off with him.
Well, do you wanna write a letter?
I have stationery and a fax machine.
No. I have to tell him to his face.
I do hate to let him go, though.
I know it's hard,
but it's the only ethical thing to do.
You're right.
Now I see why people come to you.
You always point them
in the right direction.
Well, I'd be a poor excuse
for a psychiatrist if I didn't.
- Hello, Dad.
- Hey, Fras.
What's Eddie doing?
Every time this cooking show
comes on,
he rolls over and watches it
upside-down.
He likes all the pouring they do.
He thinks it's funny the way
the food goes up instead of down.
- Evening.
- Hey, Daph.
Donny called,
said he'd be here about 8.
Do you think he'll pop
the question tonight?
I hope not.
What's the matter?
I've decided to break up
with him tonight.
What? You wanted
to marry him yesterday.
Well, you know how I have
these visions from time to time.
- And don't tell Dr. Crane. Well...
- Don't tell me what?
- Nothing.
- It's my car again, isn't it?
It's not your bloody car.
She's breaking up with Donny
because of some vision.
I asked you not to mention that.
What vision?
I know you'll make fun of me.
But I had a vision that
I'm meant to be with another man.
- Who?
- I couldn't see his face.
I don't know anything about him.
He was just wearing a red bow tie.
You're seriously gonna dump Donny
because of some psychic vision?
Don't you think that's a little unwise?
Well, your brother didn't think so.
- Niles knows about this?
- Yes.
He helped me to see that ending
things with Donny was my only choice.
Unlike you,
he believes in my visions.
He knows I have a gift.
Yes. He's been trying to unwrap it
for six years.
That'll be Donny.
What do you think
about all this vision stuff?
There's some psychological reason
that she's having second thoughts.
It's got nothing to do
with an apparition in a red bow tie.
Niles, you jackass,
will you take that thing off?
I admit it's a departure for me,
but I'm feeling a bit kicky today.
Yes, I know.
Daphne told us you encouraged her to
follow her vision and to dump Donny.
I'm astonished at your lack of integrity.
Now, will you take that damn thing off?
What did you hope
to accomplish with that?
I was simply trying to nudge Daphne
into the realisation
that I am the man in her vision.
Niles.
All right. But why else
would she come to me?
Surely, you of all people realise
that there is some psychological basis
for these visions of hers.
It represents a fear of some kind.
A fear of intimacy,
a fear of commitment,
a fear of the Windsor knot.
Who knows?
- Wasn't that Donny at the door?
- No, no, just Niles, Daphne.
You know, we were just discussing
these visions of yours.
Look, I'm in no mood to be mocked.
I'm not mocking you, Daphne.
And I'm not trying to influence you
in any way either.
It's just that I was wondering...
Have these psychic warnings
ever come to you before?
Say, at a critical juncture
in a relationship.
No.
Well, actually, yes.
Once when my first boyfriend
proposed,
I had a vision telling me
there was someone better waiting,
which there was, Clyde.
But you dumped Clyde.
Look, I don't have time
for this right now.
Oh, yes,
no fear of commitment there.
Well, it's just as possible that she
knew those men were wrong for her.
- Isn't that right, Dad?
- Leave me out of this.
- I'm just looking for my TV Guide.
- Well, I could use a little support here.
Well, maybe that's why I said
to leave me out of it.
I'm sorry, Niles.
I want you to be happy,
but I'm with your brother on this.
Niles, the fact is, you don't know
what causes these visions.
And yet you still advised her
to walk away
from a wonderful relationship.
It doesn't make you
much of a psychiatrist.
That's your opinion.
Yes, well, here's a second opinion.
It doesn't make you
much of a friend.
You sure you didn't throw it away
with the recycling?
Are you actually looking
for your TV Guide?
Well, I have to plan my weekend.
You really do have the world
on a string, don't you, Dad?
Look, Daphne, I have been thinking
about our talk this afternoon.
I'm not sure I gave you
the best advice I could have.
Perhaps what you call a vision
is really a fear,
a fear of commitment, say.
That would explain
why these visions
come to you
when your relationships turn serious.
Mind you, I can't tell you that I think
Donny is the right person for you,
but I wouldn't want you to end things
with him for the wrong reasons.
- Do you understand?
- Yeah.
You're just like your brother after all.
This afternoon you were just
humouring me, weren't you?
- No, Daphne.
- Look at the idiot from Manchester.
She thinks she has visions.
No, no. I'm saying that I think
there are psychological issues here
that you just don't entirely appreciate.
Well, how could I?
I'm just some nut who believes in fate.
Well, I've always followed my vision
and your pity's not gonna change that.
That'll be Donny.
Could one of you get the door?
Well, you've seen me do it
enough times.
You just turn the handle and pull.
- Hello, Donny.
- Hi, Frasier.
- Hey.
- Is Daphne ready?
- She'll be out in a minute.
- That's good. Great.
- What's that you're drinking there?
- Sherry.
Yeah, I'll have one.
So how's business?
Well, actually,
I've cut down on my caseload
because I wanna spend more time
with Daphne.
Don't tell her this, but I've book us
on an Alaskan vacation next month.
I hear it's one of the few places left
where you can feel completely alone.
You like that feeling, huh?
- Donny.
- Oh, hi, honey.
- You look really great.
- You too.
Shall we be on our way, then?
Well, actually,
I've got something on my mind
that I'd kind of like to talk about first.
- Oh, well, we'll just get out of here.
- No, no, no, it's...
I'd like you to stay here for this.
If it wasn't for all of you,
then I never would have met Daphne.
- Donny, I think it'd be best if...
- It's okay. Sit.
Maybe I'll just have
a little bit of this sherry.
You know, I thought
that being a divorce attorney
would've just soured me
on relationships,
and then I met you.
And now I find myself
telling my clients to reconcile,
because I think that if they could find
even just a tiny little bit
of the happiness
that I've found with you,
they could make it.
I've been thinking about that time
we went to the little bed-
and-breakfast in the country,
and we sat in that porch swing
all night
and looked at the sky.
You told me that your dad and you
used to sit on your stoop
and do the same thing
when you were a kid.
He said that the only man
good enough for you
would scoop the stars
out of the sky with his hat
and lay them at your feet.
Well...
I've...
I've only caught this one so far,
but if you'll accept it,
I'll spend my life chasing down
the rest of them for you.
I know it's very soon,
so just think about it.
I don't have to think about it.
Yes. Oh, God, it's beautiful.
Oh, Donny. Oh, God.
Thank you.
Boys, give me a break.
You look more surprised than I do.
No, no.
No.
We're just so happy for you.
- Congratulations.
- Yes, it's wonderful, it's wonderful.
- Thank you.
- If you'll excuse me, I need to...
- Yes, champagne. Let me help you.
Oh, Niles.
I'm so sorry.
Frasier, why don't you take
the champagne in there?
We're gonna stay out here
for a second.
All right.
I'd do anything to fix this for you.
I know.
It's my own fault.
I had chance after chance
to tell her how I feel,
and I always kept my mouth shut.
Until tonight,
when I probably should have.
Well, you can't regret what you said.
It was the right thing to do.
And that's something
I can always count on from you.
Thanks, Dad.
I'm gonna get you
some of that champagne.
- Oh, yeah, me too.
- Oh, just a second, Dr. Crane.
I'm sorry I got cross with you.
Once I thought about what you said,
it really made sense.
And then when Donny did ask me,
it was fear I felt, just like you told me.
I figured the best way to overcome it
was to just jump in with both feet.
Thank you for your help.
- I wish you the very best, Daphne.
- Hey, hey, hey, don't squeeze so hard.
That's a precious commodity
right there.
My number one client here,
you know.
- Still looking for that TV Guide?
- Yeah, it's the damnedest thing.
What are you still doing up?
Where's Donny?
He's on the phone with my folks.
He really is wonderful, Mr. Crane.
I'm very happy for you, Daph.
Oh, my God.
I just had that vision again.
Only this time...
Oh, that's a bit scary.
My mystery man is standing
with some sort of dragon.
- A dragon?
- Yes.
That makes no sense.
It must be just what Dr. Crane said.
- These visions are about my fears.
- I guess.
Imagine spending the rest of my life
looking for some poor bloke
with a dragon.
- That's weird.
- What?
I just had a vision myself.
What is it?
There's a mystery woman.
She's standing in the kitchen.
She's making me
a Monte Cristo sandwich.
- Oh, brother.
- No, no, it's just a grilled cheese.
Make it yourself, you lazy old goat.
Oh, Roz.