[DAPHNE LAUGHING]
DAPHNE: Hello.
NILES: Hey.
Ah, the weekend warriors
have returned.
You better watch out, Dr. Crane.
I'm getting pretty good at kickboxing.
It's true, it's true. She hits so hard,
they call her the British Pound.
You hit pretty hard yourself there,
Nails.
I'm gonna hop in the shower.
- Nails?
- Oh, you scratch one guy...
Oh, my electrolytes are plummeting.
Care to join me in a sherry?
Well, actually, I'd love to, Niles,
but I'm off to see Dr. Tewksbury.
Oh. I didn't realise
your mentor was still in town.
Yes, and because of it,
I've been the recipient
of some informal therapy.
It's really been quite enlightening.
You know, I consider myself lucky
to be in the hands of such a master.
NILES:
Mm.
Well, I'm happy for you, Frasier.
He is a gifted psychiatrist.
Even if I don't share
your godlike worship of him.
Well, I simply have
a healthy respect for the man, Niles.
It's hardly worship.
Oh, please. You're one step away from
seeing his image appear in a tortilla.
- Niles, thank heavens you're still here.
- Uh, what's wrong?
- You can't go to Nervosa today.
- Why not?
I had a psychic vision that
something bad's gonna happen to you.
- Oh, come on, Daphne.
- Niles, I'm serious.
I know you don't believe in visions,
but it's important to me.
Promise me you won't go.
Well, all right, if it means
that much to you, I won't go.
- I'll go straight home.
- Thank you.
I feel much better.
I'll see you later.
Wow, that was scary.
Don't tell me
you believe in that stuff.
No, I mean the way
she can manipulate you like that.
Oh. Please,
I was just being diplomatic.
FRASIER:
Is it difficult to kickbox without a spine?
NILES:
You're gonna find out.
- Hello, Frasier.
- Oh, hi, Roz.
Oh, been on a shopping spree,
I see.
Yes, Alice is visiting her grandmother
for the week.
- So I finally have some time to myself.
- Oh.
It is great shopping without her
pulling down a display rack.
Not only that, I actually woke up today
without someone jumping on my bed
and sticking her little fingers
up my nose.
And I didn't have to spend
half the morning
combing knots
out of that little girl's curls.
- Give Alice my love.
- Thank you, I will.
Psst. Frasier.
- Can you get me a latte?
- Well...
Why don't you just get it yourself,
Niles? Oh, that's right.
It's bad mugambo
for you to enter.
You know I promised Daphne.
Yes, yes, and woe betide
he who disobeyeth the oracle.
Oh, all right, all right, all right.
Wait, wait.
Maybe if I get it to go
and don't actually sit down,
then I won't be
breaking my promise.
Step aside, everybody.
Big set of onions coming through.
NILES:
Latte to go, please.
Hello, Frasier.
Dr. Tewksbury. Well, uh...
Gosh, this is quite a surprise.
What are you doing here?
I've heard you mention
how good their coffee is here.
- I thought I'd give it a try.
- Oh...
- May I join you?
- Oh, yes, yes, of course.
I'm terribly sorry.
Oh, Roz, uh, meet Dr. Tewksbury.
- This is my producer, Roz Doyle.
ROZ: Hi.
And my brother, Niles.
Niles, Dr. Tewksbury.
- How do you do?
- Hello.
I don't believe we've ever met,
but I seem to recall reading
a fascinating paper of yours recently.
Oh, yes, it was probably
the one about phobias.
Oh, can't sit, can't sit.
Oh... Uh...
Uh...
It's a long story, uh...
Anyway, uh, Dr. Tewksbury,
uh, I was just wondering,
did you read the article
on behaviour modification...?
Now, Frasier, let's not talk shop.
You don't want to bore Roz.
Oh, it's all just white noise
to me now.
Yes, all right.
Niles, please, would you stop hovering
and just sit down, hmm?
Uh, all right. What can it hurt?
- Niles.
- Daphne!
How could you come down here?
- You broke your promise.
- And my patella.
Well, nothing bad
would have happened
if you'd paid attention
to my premonition.
Well, actually, nothing bad would have
happened if you hadn't shown up.
It wouldn't have not happened
had I not shown up.
Wouldn't not have happened
if you hadn't not shown up.
I wouldn't have shown had I not known
you wouldn't be able to not come here.
Well, I'm not... Not... Not... What?
My point exactly. You don't listen.
- Daphne. Oh. Ooh.
- Niles. Niles, you all right?
Oh. No, I've aggravated
my old bossa nova injury.
Well, perhaps I'd better drive you.
- I'm sorry, Dr. Tewksbury.
- I understand.
- Bye, Roz.
- Bye.
Well, heh-heh,
what was that all about?
Well, she thinks she's psychic,
but he doesn't believe her.
Well, no matter
who's right or wrong,
Niles needs to set up
stricter boundaries with his patients.
I learned that
from years of practise.
No. No, she's not his patient.
She's his girlfriend.
Oh, well, in that case,
no matter who's right or wrong,
he's wrong.
I learned that
from years of marriage.
[ROZ CHUCKLES]
There anything I can get you, Niles?
How about a cold pack, perhaps?
No, no.
If Daphne ever comes out of her room,
I'll just use her icy stare.
If you don't mind, I'm gonna
have to cancel on the opera tonight.
Oh, Niles, you know
I hate going to the opera alone.
Throwing a woman's shawl
over the seat next to me
and glancing expectantly back
at the ladies' room all night.
- You do that?
- No.
Hey, why don't you ask
Dr. Tewksbury
- if he'd like to go?
- Oh...
Ever since his divorce, I'm sure
he's anxious to get out of the house.
Well, we're in a quasi-therapeutic
relationship right now.
And truth be told, I was uncomfortable
socialising with him at Nervosa.
Oh. Well, I understand.
You don't want to see the wizard
behind the curtain.
Everyone needs an idol,
someone who represents a higher
plateau of truth and knowledge.
That's very insightful, Niles.
For so many years, I must have
represented that plateau to you.
Thank you, Frasier.
Laughter is indeed the best medicine.
[DOOR OPENS,
THEN FOOTSTEPS]
Oh, Daphne. Uh, my knee
is feeling much better.
Oh, good.
Well, I hope she doesn't expect me
to run in there after her.
- Good for you, Niles.
- With this knee, I can only hobble.
Daphne, I'm sorry.
Are you sorry for breaking
your promise or for not believing me?
I'm sorry for breaking my promise.
You don't believe
I had a premonition?
- Well, it wasn't a premonition.
- It certainly was.
I told you if you went to Nervosa
something bad would happen,
and you hurt your knee.
What more proof do you need?
Something a little more scientific
than that, I'm afraid.
You need scientific proof?
Well, I think
we can do something about that.
What do you mean?
There are people around
who do this sort of research.
Are those people here now?
- No.
- Ow.
I'm talking about
legitimate professionals.
Well, uh...
All right. All right.
But it has to be a real scientist.
Not some huckster who comes here
with crystals and a ghost-o-meter.
As long as you have an open mind.
And it's pronounced ghostometers.
- I'm glad we worked this out.
- Me too.
And now that we've made up,
maybe we could, mm...
Mm... Well, I guess we know
who's not psychic.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Frasier.
I thought you were the pizza guy.
I thought we were writing
promos tonight.
- You forgot, didn't you?
- No.
Yes. I'm sorry.
[IN SING-SONG VOICE]
Pizza, we're gonna have pizza.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Frasier. Hello.
What are you doing here?
Oh, just, uh, wearing clothes.
Oh, right. Ha-ha.
Frasier brought over some work
from the office.
Ah. I'll just go get dressed.
I've gone blind.
And ten seconds too late. Ha-ha.
So since when have you
and Dr. Tewksbury
been seeing each other?
Well, um, the other day at Nervosa,
we really hit it off after you left,
and, uh, he asked me to dinner.
And we've been out
every night since.
Really? Well, I must say,
I'm a bit surprised.
Why? He's smart.
Very insightful.
And he's such a great listener.
Yes, well, I'm happy for you, Roz.
It's just a little difficult
imagining the two of you together.
You don't think I can appreciate
a sophisticated man?
You know, it's not
just about sex for me, Frasier.
Uh, do you have a stepladder?
My pants are stuck in the ceiling fan.
Frasier, listen, before we begin,
I hope it wasn't too awkward
seeing me with Roz last night.
Not at all. It's just a little... jarring
to see you out of context that way.
- Yeah.
- It's just...
But your personal life
is your business.
Speaking of which,
let's get down to business.
- The Crane mind.
- Yes, let us.
Now, last time
we had just broached the subject
of your father's expectations and
their effect on your early adulthood.
As we know, ahem,
the internalisation
of a parent's moral code
is crucial to the development
of the superego.
And considering
your father's strictness...
Frasier, is everything all right?
Yes, yes, of course.
Of course. Please, continue.
You must admit
that having a father
whose very occupation
is the enforcement of the moral code
would lead
to an overdeveloped superego.
I believe I have a paper
on this subject.
It's right here.
- Oh, hey, Dad.
- Hey.
How was your day?
Why don't you just tell me
what happened to you?
- What are you talking about?
- Well, you know how my day goes.
Play with Eddie, watch TV,
do my stretches.
You only ask so I'll ask you
about your day, so I'm asking.
I am hurt. You're my father.
Of course I care about your day.
Oh, well, uh, I played with Eddie,
uh, watched TV, did my stretches.
Ah. Good.
- So how...?
- I just came from Dr. Tewksbury.
Throughout the entire session,
I just couldn't focus
on anything he was saying.
Wasn't he talking about you?
Yes, yes, but recently,
I saw him in...
Well, a less than dignified light.
And, uh, ever since, I've just found it
impossible to take him seriously.
I know exactly
what you're talking about.
In Korea, I had this commanding
officer, Lieutenant Franks.
I would have followed that guy
into the gates of hell.
I saw him a few years later.
He was flipping hamburgers
in a fast-food place.
Now, that was hard to handle.
I mean, this guy took me
under his wing and moulded me.
- Like a mentor.
- Yeah, exactly.
He always used to say that one day
he'd be taking orders from me.
Just never thought
it would be for extra onions.
So how did you handle it?
Well, I just realised
that it was my problem, not his.
And I wasn't going to let that erase
all he meant to me.
So I just marched right back
into that kitchen and saluted him.
And after we were talking for a while,
I realised nothing had changed.
He was still the same
hard-charging man's man
who wasn't afraid
to get his hands dirty.
Which is why
I never ate there again.
Uh, if you two don't mind,
Daphne's psychic evaluator
is on the way over,
and we'd like to use
the living room.
Fine with me.
That stuff creeps me out anyway.
Niles, I still can't believe
you ever agreed to this.
Those tests
are based on nothing more
than subjective evidence
and lucky guesses.
Yes, not at all
like the subjective evidence
and lucky guesses
psychiatry is based on.
Thank you.
Don't worry, I will thoroughly appraise
the examiner and his testing methods.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
- Good luck.
- That'll be him.
Come in. I'm Dr. Niles Crane.
This is Daphne Moon.
- Hello.
- Hello. I'm Dr. Sheldon Morey.
Hmm. Oh, a doctor.
Doctor of...?
Spookology.
- Kidding.
- Aha.
- It's just what most people expect.
- Heh-heh.
Actually, I'm a professor of psychiatry
at Seattle University.
- Really? Well, please, have a seat.
- Mm.
- Oh, thank you, thank you.
- So, hmm, you're more of a debunker.
Well, no, not at all.
Actually, I apply scientific method
to the search
for paranormal phenomena.
Believe me,
nothing would make me happier
than discovering
a legitimate psychic.
Oh, so you've never found one.
Well, if by psychic you mean
people with above normal prescience,
then a few.
If you mean somebody who can
beat the house in Vegas, then no.
I thought I had one for a while,
but, uh, no.
So, Daphne,
you still wanna go through with this?
- I'm ready if you are.
- All right. Doctor, she's all yours.
Great. Now, I've got a card...
Ace of spades.
With my office
and fax number on it.
And your address.
[CHUCKLING]
Correct.
Star.
Circle.
And finally...
That's it.
That was your final test.
And I'm psychic, right?
First we have to compare
your results
to those of the rest
of the control group.
It'll just take me a few minutes here
to run these numbers, okay?
So... how do you think you did?
I think I did pretty well
on the cards.
The premonition test was a little tricky,
but all in all, I was in the zone.
Well, we'll soon find out.
You know, Daphne,
I'm always curious.
When was it that you first suspected
you had psychic ability?
Oh, years ago
when I was a little girl.
Grammy Moon
first saw the gift in me.
See, I was a girl in a house
full of boys, which I hated.
Until Grammy told me that
only Moon women had second sight.
She had it, her mother had it,
and so on.
After that, I began noticing I could
sense things before they happened.
Sort of like a secret power.
Anyway, it's always just been
a part of who I am.
I see. Well, we have your results.
All right. I don't know why,
I'm a bit nervous.
- So, Daphne, from what I see here...
- Wait. Uh, wait.
I don't think we should do this.
I don't wanna know.
DAPHNE: What do you mean?
- I'm sorry. I think this was a bad idea.
Well, I thought you wanted
scientific proof.
I changed my mind.
I don't need a stranger
telling me anything about who you are.
I want us to get to know each other
on our own, over time.
I knew you were gonna say that.
- You did?
- No. But I loved hearing it.
I'm sorry, Dr. Morey,
we've wasted your time.
It's okay.
Dog told me a couple of funny jokes
while we were waiting.
- I'm kidding.
NILES: Oh.
They weren't that funny.
TEWKSBURY: All right, Frasier,
let's start with our last session.
As I recall,
you were having difficulty
getting rid of a certain image
in your mind.
- That is correct.
- Mm-hm.
Well, perhaps
we should confront that.
Oh, dear Lord.
I assumed that was Roz's.
It is.
I was at her apartment this morning.
I started thinking
about your issue with the robe,
and I decided to bring it with me.
Now, Frasier, ahem, you consider me
a competent psychiatrist, don't you?
Of course I do.
Does seeing me dressed like this
diminish that?
No. Of course not.
It's just, well,
I know on a conscious level,
that the garment
does not change who you are.
But on an unconscious level,
I'm all weirded out.
I mean, you're my mentor
and you're wearing Roz's robe.
- I'm still the same person.
- Yes, but it's Roz's robe.
And what does Roz's robe
signify to you?
- Roz.
- Well...
Then maybe this isn't
about you and me.
Maybe this is about
your relationship with Roz.
Seeing me dressed like this
brings up deep feelings.
Don't be afraid of those feelings.
Go with them.
Ah, Peterson.
Here for your makeup test?
I was, but I'll just take the D.
[TEWKSBURY CLEARS THROAT]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
- Oh, Frasier.
- Hi. You got a minute?
We're not supposed
to be working, are we?
Because I'm kind of busy
right now.
- It's not about work.
- Oh, come on in.
- Have a seat.
- Thanks.
Listen, uh...
Something's been troubling me
ever since I saw Dr. Tewksbury
in your robe.
And, uh, at first I thought it was about
the toppling of a hero.
But I've since discovered
that it's really about you.
Oh. Let me guess. I'm not good
enough for your precious mentor.
No, no, that's not it, Roz. Uh...
When you were describing
what attracted you to Dr. Tewksbury,
I couldn't help thinking that...
...that very well
could have been me.
So?
So, Roz, I've known you for what,
eight years now?
And in all that time,
I've seen you date hundreds of men.
- Careful.
- Oh, all right.
Dozens of men.
Yet you never showed
any interest in me.
Well, except for that one
drunken flirtation at the station retreat.
[ROZ SNORTING]
Well, anyway, I just assumed
that it was because I wasn't your type.
Then I see you drawn to someone
who's similar to me.
- You're jealous?
- Well, no, not jealous. Not exactly.
It's more along the lines of, uh,
why everybody else and not me?
Frasier, did you ever stop to think
there may be something special
about not being picked?
That didn't work
when I was cut from pee-wee football,
it's not gonna work now.
Okay, I'll be honest with you.
When we first started
working together,
I had a little crush on you.
- Really?
- Yeah. Sure.
I mean, you were handsome
and sophisticated,
and you had your French suits
and your Italian shoes.
Actually, it was vice versa,
but, go on, go on.
But you were coming off this divorce,
and you were my boss,
and the whole thing was just too weird,
so I never acted on it.
And you were right. You were, but...
Anyway,
it's nice to know how you felt.
- Thanks.
- Sure.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
So just for the record though,
you did have the hots for me?
Yes. Yes.
- You're not just saying that?
- No.
All right, all right.
Can you imagine
the two of us together?
Gosh, no. Ha-ha-ha-ha.
- Strange idea, isn't it?
- Really strange.
Gosh, it's pretty hard
to picture, isn't it?
Of course,
it wouldn't be your problem.
It would be all me.
Trust me. All me.
I mean, you're a perfectly
wonderful person.
- What are you doing?
- I'm saying how great you are.
No, you're giving me
the "it's not you, it's me" speech.
If anyone should be giving that speech,
it's me, not you.
- Whatever you have to tell yourself.
- All right, get out.
Sounds to me
like somebody still has a soft spot
for the old boss man.
Out!
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]