[DOORBELL RINGS]
- Hey, Daphne.
- Hello, Roz, Alice.
- What brings you here?
- We're borrowing Frasier's car.
Oh, I see. And you're leaving
Alice here as collateral.
Actually,
he's being very nice about it.
Mine's in the shop,
and I'm taking Alice and her friends
to an ice cream party.
You told me it was your friends
and the Science Centre.
He said, she said,
we'll never know what really happened.
Frasier, don't be so uptight.
I'm not gonna hurt your precious car.
I am not uptight. I've just had
unfortunate experiences before
loaning out my car.
DAPHNE: I left an umbrella in the trunk.
- It was a wet umbrella.
Can I have the keys?
Yes, yes.
After all, what are fine possessions for
if not to be used and enjoyed?
And who better to enjoy them
than the delightful souls
of small children?
- I'll put a tarp in the back seat.
- Oh, bless you.
- Hey, Roz. Hello, Alice.
ROZ: Hey.
- What brings you here?
- Frasier loaned me his car.
I backed mine into a telephone pole.
- You said you were getting a tune-up.
- It needs one, trust me.
- Is Daphne ready?
- Uh...
Actually, I think she's in her room.
You two have plans?
Yes, I am taking her
to the botanical gardens.
Can you believe
she's never been before?
Didn't Donny take her
to the botanical gardens last year?
Can you believe
she's never been before?
- Hey, Daphne.
- Hello, Niles.
NILES:
Ready to go to the gardens?
I'm afraid I'm gonna have to take Eddie
for a walk first.
- Where's Dad?
- I don't know, he's gone.
Here, I'll take him for a quick walk.
DAPHNE: Oh, no, he's gonna need
more than that. He'll go stir crazy.
He's gonna need a full run
at the dog park.
We don't have time
to go to the dog park.
The tour of succulents
starts promptly at 12.
- Hey Frasier, can you take him?
- No, I'm sorry.
Roz has my car, you see,
and Lana's coming to pick me up
for a tutoring session with Kirby.
Oh, I'll just get Eddie's toys.
Hello, this is Dr. Frasier Crane.
I need to make
an emergency appointment tomorrow
for a complete cleaning of my BMW.
June 10th?
But I have
a Clean Team Privileges Card.
Yes, of course, it's a platinum one.
No.
No, there are no diamonds
on the corner.
Well, yes, I'd like to become a member
of the Diamond Alliance immediately.
Fine.
Put me on the waiting list.
I'll see you in June.
- You're not in the Diamond Alliance?
- Don't do that.
- So this is it.
- Mm-hm.
I'd hardly call this a dog park.
It's more like a dog orgy.
Whose beagles are those?
Don't stare. It only encourages them.
All right, hurry up, Eddie.
There's lots of exciting depravity
to explore.
He wants to play a little fetch.
- Oh, here, you throw it.
- With my bare hands?
- Come on, it's fun.
- All right, ready?
Here we go, and fetch.
I didn't give you
enough of a challenge here.
Come here. You ready? Ready?
And...
Go get it.
I'm sorry. I was a bit of a grouch.
This is actually a fine way
to spend the day.
In fact, it's kind of...
Hello.
Do you suppose the rest of Eddie's
in there?
JIM:
Good boy, good boy.
Sorry about that, Daphne,
but with the organic vitamin paste
I've been feeding Tank,
Eddie can't keep up with him
anymore.
It's no problem, Jim.
Niles, this is Jim Brady and Tank.
This is Niles, my boyfriend.
- It's a pleasure.
- Boyfriend? I should have known.
Every time I'm single,
you're in a relationship
and every time you're single,
I'm in a relationship.
Yeah, that's true.
- I guess we just don't have good...
- Timing.
Exactly.
- And I'm a drummer.
- Which makes it even more ironic.
Tank, that's rude. Now, chill.
Wow, you've really got him trained.
That's the problem with Eddie.
He only listens if he thinks
he's gonna get food.
Or one of my socks.
But mostly food.
It's all in the voice tone, really.
Any dog can learn to respond to it,
even an old wheezer like Eddie.
- You want me to show you?
- I'd love it.
Come on. Come on, buddy.
Yeah, we'd all love it.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
You guys go ahead.
Yes.
- Hello?
- Hi, Niles, it's me.
I just want to make sure
Daphne took Eddie for a walk.
I completely forgot about him
this morning.
Yeah, yeah,
we're in the dog park now.
- Where are you, anyway?
- I'm at the track.
I had an itch for it when I woke up
and so I just dropped everything
and went.
I'm at the window.
I'll have a trifecta in the eighth.
Gotta run.
Well, I didn't realise I was gonna be
selling houses with you today.
Why didn't you drop me off
and then come on your own?
Stop whining. It'll only take a minute.
I hope we don't run into the sad sack
who owns this place.
I've been trying to sell this house
for a year,
and he keeps driving away
every potential buyer.
- How does he do that?
- Oh, hi.
I heard a woman's voice.
I thought it might be my wife
coming back to me.
No. She lives in Portland now with
her new husband Lamar, remember?
Oh, excuse me, Frasier Crane,
Phillip Donovan, the current owner.
- Hello.
- Hi.
LANA: I'll see you later, Phillip.
- Anyway,
my wife just left with the kids.
No talking, no explanations,
just ripped my heart out,
threw it to the dogs.
Which she also took.
Well, at least you're getting out
at the top of the market.
Actually, this is a very good time,
Phillip, and I think today is the day.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, God.
What's wrong?
The damn basement
must have flooded again.
Everything in this box is ruined.
Little Susie's cap she wore home
from the hospital. Ruined.
Danny's first soccer uniform. Ruined.
Well, you know,
I have an excellent dry cleaner.
LANA:
No.
Once, actually, I spilled butter
on a pair of white velvet pantaloons.
Well, it's a long story,
but he had it out in under a minute.
- Just give him the address.
FRASIER: Yes.
I have two sons and two daughters.
The perfect American family.
Until that bastard Lamar showed up
to snake our drains.
Now all I have left are weekend visits
and a few treasures
from their childhood.
Like this house little Danny and I
made at day camp.
Oh, thank goodness,
it made it through unscathed.
Just a little water damage
in the basement.
- Just like this house.
- Oh, well...
Yes, well, Phillip,
you are still their father.
I mean,
I know things seem difficult right now,
but believe me, it'll get easier.
Well, it's already easier.
I mean, look at me, I'm dressed.
You know what would cheer you up
is to make a killing on this house.
Now don't you think
you should get back to work?
Yeah, I guess.
That air traffic
isn't gonna control itself.
LANA: Okay, here we go out...
No, not the front door.
Let's go out the side door.
Gosh, good to see you again, Phillip.
I'll call you real soon. Thanks, bye.
Well, that man is obviously in pain.
The least you could be
is a little sympathetic.
I have been sympathetic
for 15 months.
I had him over for Thanksgiving.
He got drunk the first half-hour
and cried himself to sleep
in my coat closet.
And I consider that
one of our good days.
Well, so where are these
so-called buyers of yours?
- You told me they'd be here.
- They're obviously running late.
- It'll give us time to go over the plan.
- What? There's a plan?
Well, sure. When the Smolenski's get
here, you act like you want the house.
You know, a little competition.
Put a little pressure on the deal.
You're asking me to be your shill?
That's the word. Yes, yes.
Now listen, listen.
No, you don't have to say anything.
- Well, I'm sorry, no.
- Well, why the...?
Look, all you have to do is walk around
with an interested look on your face.
- They'll fill in the rest.
- I will do no such thing.
- Why won't you help me?
- Because I refuse to lie for you.
- Fine, then go wait in the car.
- I never wanted to leave the car.
Oh, just get out!
All right, I got some Creamsicles,
and Fudgesicles,
and something they call Bomb Pops.
Well, I called the Smolenskis.
I bought us a little extra time.
Right, good, good, fine. Spread out
some paper and then build us a house.
So, Frasier,
with all your talk about honesty,
how do you justify faking this thing?
Well, we're simply protecting
the feelings of an innocent man.
There's nothing dishonest
about that.
Uh-huh.
So, are you gonna write,
"I love you, Daddy" or am I?
I'll do it.
Sit. Wave, wave.
All right, hide your eyes.
Hide your eyes.
Hide them, hide them.
- Hide your eyes.
- Hello.
JIM: Come on, hide your eyes.
Hide your eyes.
Hey, Eddie,
don't worry about that other dog.
He may be bigger and flashier
and better looking,
but you have substance.
She knows that.
DAPHNE:
How amazing is Jim?
He's so connected to animals,
it's almost magical.
Daphne, I've been musing
about you and me.
- And I have a thought.
DAPHNE: Yeah?
In every healthy relationship,
I think there should be room
for an occasional,
very occasional, irrational demand.
What do you mean?
A thing we insist the other do
or not do,
and the other one has to do it
or not do it without question.
- Is that fair?
- It is.
Because we each get one and
only one for our whole relationship.
- Well, if it's important to you.
- Then it's agreed?
- Agreed.
- Good.
Oh, I've got mine.
- Already?
- Yes.
I want you to promise
never to come to this dog park again.
- What?
- I know it sounds extreme,
it's even unreasonable, but that's
the beauty of the irrational demand.
Is this about Jim?
The demand cannot be scrutinised.
It's by definition, irrational.
Are you sure this is how
you want to use your only one?
Absolutely.
I've thought this through a lot.
Irrationally, of course.
Okay, if you're sure.
I promise never to come
to this dog park again.
Thank you.
I knew you'd understand.
All right, we're going home.
Tank needs to rehydrate,
and I'm late for a deltoid workout.
Well, I guess this is goodbye, Jim.
Yep, by this time next week
I'll be leading my first raft tour in Chile.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Wow, when do you get back?
- Oh, he's not coming back.
He's moving there.
- Good luck, Jim.
- Yes, you too.
- Take care.
- And stay cool, buddy.
Oh, you know it.
I wonder how I'll use
my irrational demand.
Oh, what's my rush?
I've got years to think it over.
- Hi, Martin.
- Oh, hello, Joanne.
- How have you been?
- Pretty good.
- Oh, please, have a seat.
- Thanks.
I was worried I was going to be late
with all that construction going on.
Yeah, I know. It's a mess.
How's your hip?
Oh, you learn to live with it.
I think about you a lot, you know.
I've wanted to call, but...
I don't know.
Oh, I understand. It's okay.
- So, another year has gone by.
- Yeah, time really flies.
I guess it goes a little slower for me.
- How's our roof coming?
- Almost done.
Good.
You know, there was a time
back in high school
when I would have paid a thousand
dollars to watch you eat a Popsicle.
It was a long time ago.
I think it's kind of funny
that we became friends.
We're friends?
Well, sure we are.
Why wouldn't you think so?
- Oh, dear.
- Nice going, dipstick.
It's a brand new shirt.
I hear a car. It's the Smolenskis.
- Okay, keep working.
- Right.
I've got to go to Phillip's room,
spray some air freshener around.
His room reeks of,
I don't know, despair.
It's even nicer than I remember.
Well, hello there.
Are you having fun
making your little house?
Oh, hi. Oh, there you are.
Hi. Oh, I see you've met Frasier.
You know,
I'm so glad you came today,
because the interest on this place
is really heating up.
Well, we're certainly interested
as well,
but we heard that a lot of homes
in this area have a flooding problem.
Now what do you know
about the basement here?
LANA: Honestly?
SMOLENSKl: Yes.
This house is 60 years old,
and I have only heard of it
flooding once.
[COUGHS]
And I can tell you for a fact
that the current owner
stores some of his most cherished
keepsakes in that basement.
[FRASIER COUGHING]
Are you choking on your lolly?
No. I am choking on something
far more dangerous and destructive
than a simple sugary treat.
It's a prolific and powerful poison
known as deception.
He's very verbal.
Oh, you know, I just remembered.
Gosh, you know,
the owner did mention something
about a recent
little moisture problem downstairs.
Why don't I give him a call and see
if he'll come down in the price?
Oh, that'd be wonderful.
If you give us a break in the price,
I'm sure we'll make an offer.
- Great, I'll call you tonight.
MRS. SMOLENSKl: Thank you, Lana.
- Sure.
- Goodbye, sonny.
LANA:
Call you tonight.
Bye-bye.
There, now, you see?
You did the right thing.
- It wasn't so bad, was it?
- I guess not.
Oh, look at our little house.
It looks great.
Say,
we've got a few Popsicle sticks left.
Why don't we add on a half a bath?
Frasier.
You know, Lana, I think the house
should go the other way around,
with the door facing the couch.
Feng shui.
Fine, fine, fine.
- Oh, perfect.
- Perfect.
FRASIER: Doesn't that
feel good to tell the truth?
It's like breathing a breath
of fresh air after...
- Yeah, yeah, let's get out of here.
- All right.
[ELEVATOR BELL RINGS]
Okay, Alice.
Before we see Uncle Frasier,
let's remember together
what really happened.
Now, did you throw up
in Uncle Frasier's car?
No, you didn't.
That smell was there before, wasn't it?
That's my girl. There you go.
Besides the library assignment,
I've been taking the computer class
on Wednesdays.
I hope to get a job with computers.
You know, when I get out.
Can you tell us what consideration,
if any, you've given this crime?
Well, I regret it every day.
I was young at the time,
and I wasn't thinking,
you know, about the consequences.
I'm very sorry.
The victim is here.
Mr. Crane,
would you like to make a statement?
I have nothing to say.
WOMAN:
Would you give us a moment?
[WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY]
Mr. Hicks, the board commends you
for your participation
in the in-house programmes
to better yourself and for your record
of excellent conduct.
We have weighed this
against your conviction
of shooting a police officer
during the commission of a robbery,
and find that the length
of your time served
has not yet met the standards
for proportionality,
equality and justice
as required by state law.
Parole is denied.
[DOOR BUZZES]