Rule number one:
Always stand in back of the kerb
until the bus comes
to a complete stop.
Now take your money
and put it right in here.
Yes, thank you, Roz. But I am not
completely lacking in street smarts.
Good day, busman.
The northwest corner
of Highland and First, please.
- That's not a stop.
- I know.
Perhaps if I just shove
a little encouragement into this box...
- Come on.
- I'm paying my fare.
Keep your eyes peeled for a seat
and hold onto a pole.
It doesn't look very clean, Roz.
Well, would you rather wind up
on the floor?
Dear God!
WOMAN 1: Francine.
WOMAN 2: Miranda.
Wow, it's a long time.
How are things at The Colonnade?
MIRANDA:
Oh, trust me, you are missed.
Things have gotten so crazy,
they put me in charge.
- Oh, that's great. You deserve it.
- Thank you. How are you doing?
- Which one are you staring at?
- I'm not staring. That would be rude.
- Which one?
- The blonde.
Why don't you go and talk to her?
Please, Roz, come on.
The woman's a perfect stranger.
Stranger? You know her name,
you know she has a job,
you know she's attractive.
It's like an A&E Biography compared
to what I usually know going in.
[FRASIER CHUCKLES]
No. Gosh, look at me.
I'm soaked through, my hair's a mess.
Believe me,
you could look a lot worse.
After I specifically told people,
on the air, not to do that.
Look, why don't you go over
and talk to her?
It's not like you'll ever see her again
if she shoots you down.
Well, perhaps you're right.
What harm could it do?
My goodness, who would've thought
that such a rare butterfly
could exist in this tin cocoon?
Hey, for your information,
plenty of refined, sophisticated women
ride the bus every...
Open your eyes, nimrod.
That was my stop.
- Good luck. Bye-bye.
FRASIER: All right.
Oh.
Please, take mine.
Oh, here you go.
You better take mine too.
That way you can spread out.
Well, not that you need
to spread out.
Well, it's my first time on a bus.
Excuse me, miss? Um, Miranda.
So, Duke, how's the weather
in Florida?
Eighty-two? I sure envy you.
Yeah, it's nothing but rain here.
Yeah, Channel 4 said
it should clear up tomorrow,
but the Channel 5 guy said
probably not till the weekend.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Yep, then there's
the Weather Channel.
Early morning guy said
it'll probably break by Saturday.
But then the midmorning guy said...
What do you mean you gotta go?
Shuffleboard?
Oh, come on, Duke, get a life.
Hey, Niles.
I thought you were working.
Well, a patient cancelled,
so I thought I'd drop by and see you.
Oh, my God. You have no idea
how good it feels to say that.
I'm here to see you.
[SIGHS]
No more flimsy pretences.
No more making tedious small talk
with Dad.
Hey, Niles, it's 82 in Florida.
Here to see Daphne, Dad.
Well, I better check on the roast
in the oven.
- It's 375 in there.
- Ha, ha.
All right, no more weather talk.
I'm probably just getting
a little stir crazy
from being cooped up for two weeks.
But, won't be too much longer.
It will all end
when the meteor shower,
if you can believe
those Channel 7 Doppler guys.
Ooh! I wonder what they're up to.
Remember that meteor shower
we had a few years ago?
Oh, please, don't remind me.
I was over here
having dinner with Maris.
- I will never forget that night.
- Neither will I.
I've never seen a person
cut a caper in half.
No, no. I was out on the terrace,
witnessing this incredible display.
And I was absolutely miserable.
Now I know it's because
I would much rather have been
sharing that moment with you.
- Well, I'm here now.
- Mm.
Why don't we watch it together
this Saturday?
Oh, Daphne, that's a wonderful idea.
We'll re-create the entire moment,
right there on the terrace,
right down to the last detail.
Except we'll be together.
And instead of serving
'92 Dom Pérignon, we'll serve the '90
and we'll right two horrible wrongs.
[DOOR OPENS]
- Wow. Frasier, what happened?
FRASIER: What happened?
I went six months without replacing
my pollen filter in my car,
so it was in the shop.
Couldn't get a cab,
so I took the bus home.
Which splashed me.
And I fell down, missed my stop,
and had to walk home ten blocks
in this downpour.
You went six months
without changing your pollen filter?
- You could use a spot of tea.
- Desperately.
What will it be, then?
I've got Earl Grey, English breakfast,
chamomile, orange pekoe, oolong,
lapsang souchong...
Oh, for God's sake...
...just throw a bag
in some hot water.
Earl Grey. Uh...
Fras, I know it's not your thing,
but Duke sent me tickets
for tomorrow's Sonics game.
- You wanna go?
- I've got plans.
- What plans?
- Just plans.
- If you don't wanna go, just tell me.
- I don't wanna go.
Would it kill you
to spend one night with me?
I spend every night with you. I have
done my best to keep you entertained,
but in the seven years
since you've landed at my doorstep,
have you ever known me once
to show any interest in basketball?
You know I'd go, Dad,
but I have the quilt show.
Please, Niles,
I feel bad enough already.
- Care for sherry, Niles?
- Thank you.
Little rough on Dad, weren't you?
Oh, I suppose so.
It's just been a rotten day.
You don't even know the topper.
There was an enchanting
young woman on the bus.
Just when I had worked up
enough nerve to go and talk to her,
I slipped on something
that I can only hope was an old burrito.
Before I could manage to get up,
she was gone.
Well, I suppose
it just wasn't meant to be.
Wait a minute. You know...
...I did happen to overhear her name
and where she works.
Well, then what are you waiting for?
Seize the day.
Do you think I got together
with Daphne by just sitting around?
- Take a chapter from my book.
- Mm-hm.
Exactly what chapter
would that be, Niles?
- The last chapter.
- Yeah.
Suppose I did go and talk with her.
What would I say?
"I spied on you on the bus
and I've managed to hunt you down
where you work.
Would you care
to have dinner sometime?"
I might as well just lop off my ear
and mail it to her.
No, just pretend
you're there on business.
Where does she work?
It's a retirement home.
Oh! Well, tell her you're there
looking for someplace for Dad.
In fact, bring him along for cover.
No, no. You know how he hates
those places. He'd never agree to it.
He doesn't need to.
Take him to the game tomorrow
and make an unannounced stop
on the way.
You're suggesting
that I go crawling back to Dad,
beg him to let me take him
to the game,
use him to meet a pretty girl,
then sit through a sport I loathe?
All right, I see your point.
No, I'm just trying to get
the sequence right.
Oh, Dad...
You could have told me
we were stopping here when we left.
You never would have
agreed to come.
You didn't have to trick me.
I mean, I would never do that to you.
Someone is forgetting sending
Niles and me off to camp
to earn our opera badges.
Oh, there she is. Remember:
You're interested in living here.
All right. But I don't wanna be late
for the game.
Excuse me. I'm Frasier Crane.
- This is my father, Martin.
- Hello.
We're interested in finding out
more about The Colonnade.
Is there someone we could talk to?
Well, I'm the director here.
Miranda Rogers.
Why don't I get you brochures?
And if you like what you see,
you can fill out an application.
- Application?
- It only takes about 20 minutes.
- Twenty minutes?
- Yes, Dad. Application, 20 minutes.
He likes to repeat things.
It's a soothing mechanism.
Twenty minutes. Twenty minutes.
You're very patient with him.
I'll be right back.
You didn't say
I had to put anything in writing.
You haven't even seen her before.
- You're trying to put me here for real.
- No, I'm not.
You said you met on the bus.
I knew that was full of holes.
For God's sakes, will you stop?
No one's gonna put you anywhere.
Damn right.
I'm not filling out any application.
Will you hurry up and make your date
and let's get off this ice floe?
I'm starting a tour. It'd be a good way
to get your questions answered.
- That's a splendid idea.
- A tour?
Yes, Dad, a tour. A tour.
Now come along.
As you can see,
we're a full-service facility.
Will you hurry up and ask her?
If we move any slower,
they're gonna start harvesting
our organs.
It's difficult
with all these people around.
Well... The game's already started.
Two minutes and I'm calling a cab.
All right, all right.
- Hey, I know you. McGinty's, right?
- Yeah. Marty Crane.
- Yeah, Lee Zeplowitz.
- Hi, Lee.
Hey, we can really use a fourth
for poker if you're moving in.
Oh, jeez, no, I'm sorry.
I'm just here to do a favour for my son.
We're on our way over
to the ball game.
Uh-huh. They told me
I was going to the Space Needle.
- Thanks for the tour.
- Oh, you're welcome.
If you have any more questions,
don't hesitate.
Actually, you know,
I do have one more question.
Do you think it'd be possible
to have dinner sometime?
Oh, sure. Come by with your father
around 5 tomorrow
and I'll set you up at the cafeteria.
I should warn you,
tomorrow's steak night.
So be prepared to throw
a few elbows. Ha-ha-ha.
And you just asked me out on a date,
didn't you?
Yes, but that was before I knew
it was steak night.
Sure. Why not?
How about this weekend?
- Well, that's great. I'll call you.
- Okay.
I don't normally date people
I've just met,
but you seem
like such a nice person.
I can tell by the way you are
with your father.
Yes, well, we're very close.
All right, Dad, I've checked.
The rain's letting up a bit.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
[SOFT MUSIC PLAYING]
Niles, what are you doing here?
Daphne and I are watching
the meteor shower.
No, you're not. I have a date.
- That's tonight?
- Yes.
Well, what are we gonna do?
I don't know. Go to the roof.
We can't do that.
We're having a re-creation.
You'll never believe this.
Frasier wants to send us to the roof.
- What a romantic idea.
- Isn't it?
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Yes, yes, it's very romantic.
Now get your crap and go.
Coming. Coming.
Where'd you put Dad, in storage?
I have no idea where Dad is.
All I know is he's not here and you are.
- Hello.
- Good evening, Miranda. Come in.
I'd like to introduce you
to my brother, Niles Crane.
- Hello.
- And this is Daphne Moon.
- Hi.
- His lady friend.
- Oh, I suppose I am.
- You are my lady friend. Yes, she is.
We're trying to keep it hush-hush.
We're not really...
I'm sorry, my brother's
not very social, really.
Here we are.
So would you care for some wine?
Oh, I'd love some. Yeah.
- Oh, you have a beautiful place.
- Thank you.
Something tells me
this must be your father's chair.
Yes, well, you know,
I insisted that he bring it with him
when he moved in here.
I mean, after all, this is his home too.
- How thoughtful of you.
- Yes.
Well, I imagine he'll be bringing that
with him when he moves in.
Gosh, Miranda, you know,
I've got to be honest with you.
As much as I like The Colonnade,
I'm not sure Dad's ready to move yet.
Well, then,
I guess he hasn't told you.
Your father filled out
an application today.
Application? My father? Today?
Sounds like he's moving just in time.
You're picking up that repeating thing.
I've been giving a lot of thought
to this idea of a pet name for you.
And you've decided to give it up?
No, I don't give up that easily,
Woggles.
[LAUGHING]
I was kidding.
You're not really a Woggles.
You're more of a Cuddles.
No, I was kidding again.
Someone stop me.
Oh, what have we got in here, then?
Oh. Well, we have the finest
champagne and beluga caviar.
Oh. Broken bits of pottery.
That's peanut brittle.
I made it myself so we could have
something sweet. Go on, try some.
Well, I hardly need something sweet
with you here.
You are such a dear.
Seriously, try some.
[DAPHNE CHUCKLES]
Oh.
Mmm.
Mmm!
- Oh. Oh.
- Is it good?
It's like little shards of heaven.
Oh, dear. The wind's picked up.
Oh, dear.
I hope nothing else blows away.
- What happened to the peanut brittle?
- It blew away.
[CAR ALARM WAILING]
Oh.
I'll run and get some books
to hold this cloth down.
What happened?
DAPHNE: I moved the block
to hold down the blanket.
Now the door seems to be stuck.
All right. Daphne, you sit tight.
I'll run and get the super.
- I'll have it open in a minute.
- All right.
Daphne, where's the key
to the stairway door?
DAPHNE:
Oh. I've got it.
- I'll slide it under.
- Oh, all right.
No problem. Take your time.
- No need to panic.
DAPHNE: Oh, dear.
There is no under. It's sealed tight.
Sealed? All right.
Now, Daphne, try and remain calm.
Well, we'll just have to wait
for the night watchman.
He checks all these doors when
he does his rounds in a few hours.
For the last time, Daphne,
I told you not to panic.
And please don't make me say it again.
I have to conserve oxygen.
- Hey, look, Marty. There's your son.
- Yeah.
Nice try. Like I'd take my eyes off you
while you're dealing.
Dad, can I have a word with you?
Oh, Fras, yeah.
All right, keep going, guys. I'm in.
What happened to your date?
Well, suffice it to say
it didn't go so well.
I spent the whole time
worried about you.
Listen, I came down to apologise.
I've been selfish
and I've neglected you. And I'm sorry.
Oh, well, apology accepted, son.
We've both been cranky.
It's probably just the rain.
No, Dad, listen, listen. I want us to go
to games together. I really do.
And I want us to see movies
and go drinking at McGinty's...
- Well, that's great, son.
- No, Dad. I'm trying to say something.
I'm not ready for you to leave.
L... I don't want you to move in here.
I'd miss you too much.
Please, Dad, come home. Please?
What the hell are you talking about?
I'm not moving in here.
But Miranda told me you'd filled out
an application. That you told her
you'd found a new home.
[WHISPERING]
Well, I had to.
It's the only way to stay in the game.
It's for residents only.
This was just a ruse
so you could continue playing poker?
Well, it's not just poker.
It's poker with the three worst players
I've ever seen.
Hey, Marty, you in?
Sid's got a pair of tens showing.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Look at me, Sid.
Raise you 20. You dream about
getting in games like this all your life.
But you never think
it's gonna happen. Ha-ha-ha!
Dad, Dad, please. I can't let you go on
taking advantage of these people.
I'm not taking advantage of them.
I'm giving them an education.
Consider it an expensive seminar.
Seminar, my eye.
Now, you're gonna give every dime
of that money back to those men.
All right. I'll let them win it back.
- Come on, Marty. You in?
- All right. Yeah, I'm in.
Let's see.
Lee's got a pair of aces. Whoa!
Three tens here. What have I got?
Four, five, seven...
Well, I'll just bet it all.
Too rich for my blood.
I'll leave the light on for you, Dad.
How are you holding up?
Is that spider still around?
I think he's realised he's more afraid
of me than I am of him.
He's not in his corner.
Oh. There he is. Found him. Ha-ha.
Oh, Daphne, you must be starving.
Please, don't wait for me.
You go ahead and eat.
You're sure?
Oh! I just saw one.
- A spider?
- No, a meteor.
It's beautiful.
It just appeared out of nowhere.
That's it. I missed it the last time.
I'm not gonna let it happen again.
Daphne, stand back.
This door is coming down.
Okay, I'm ready.
Oh! I just saw another one.
Oh, it's breathtaking.
It just streaked
from one end of the sky to the other.
Oh, Niles, I wish you could see this.
So do I, my love.
What did you just call me?
Oh, well, it was kind of a place-filler.
I didn't have time
to think of a good one.
No, I like it.
"My love." Yeah, it's nice.
- Oh! I just saw another one.
- What's it look like?
It's got a long, glittering tail.
It reminds me of the time my father
drove home from the pub
with a trash can
stuck underneath his car.
Sparks were flying everywhere.
- Did I ever tell you that story?
- No, you never did, my love.
Well, my father stopped in at the pub
on his way home from work...