But what about our date?
Oh, there, there, there, Daphne,
don't cry, don't cry.
It's all right.
This sounds like a job
for Braveheart.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
MARTIN: Don't look now,
but there's a guy in a bow tie
who's been checking me out
for the last 20 minutes.
Oh, one of Mel's colleagues.
I met him earlier.
What's he keep staring at me for?
Well, he's a plastic surgeon.
Maybe he's looking at your eyelids
and planning his next trip to Maui.
[NILES LAUGHING]
Good Lord, look at him overacting.
Trying to convince everybody
he's happily married.
Have you ever seen anything
so pathetic in your life?
How about you and Lilith?
It was a rhetorical question.
Thank you.
Niles, I'd like you to meet
Adrianna Pettibone.
- Hello.
- Adrianna stables General Prescott,
our current grand champion,
right here at the equestrian club.
Wonderful.
Speaking of grand champions,
how about this little filly, mm? Huh?
I didn't even have
to check her teeth. Oh!
[NILES LAUGHING]
- What are you doing?
- I'm sorry. I'm a little nervous.
Well, I'm here.
Congratulations and all that B.S.
Where's the bar?
Roz, what are you doing here?
I invited her. Your side of the guest list
looked a little sparse.
Forgive me if I'm not in the spirit
of this wink-wink "happy occasion,"
- but I'm in a very crappy mood.
- Are you limping?
Yeah, I twisted my ankle on the stairs.
You know how that happened?
I couldn't find shoes,
so I had to wear these 3-inch spikes,
and the "check engine" light
on my dash keeps coming on.
What does that have to do with it?
Nothing. It just really ticks me off.
The bar! The bar! Thank you.
- That was so sweet of her to come.
- Niles, this is important.
If anyone should ask
about the honeymoon,
we're flying to Paris,
then we're taking
the Orient Express to Venice,
where we'll spend two weeks
at the Mansarda Palazetto Suite
at the Cipriani.
What's the matter?
It sounds like a wonderful trip.
- It's not my fault we're not going.
- I know.
Ah. Here's the happy couple.
All right, you two,
show me those pearly whites.
- All right, now, how about a kiss?
- Well, I hardly know you, but... Ha-ha!
He's kidding.
Here we go. Mm.
Come on, doc.
This is your wife, not mine.
- All right, well.
- Okay.
CROWD:
Ohh.
[CROWD APPLAUDS]
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
I'll go check on dad and Frasier.
- Yes, they do make a lovely couple.
- Don't they?
I'm sure they'll be happy together
for many years.
Well, you never know.
- Dad?
- Well, you don't, do you?
I mean,
I'm just saying you never know.
No, I guess you don't.
Been lovely talking with you.
Enjoy the party.
What the hell's wrong with you?
In a few weeks,
I'm gonna look like a genius.
Well, I feel really stupid.
I just came on to the guy in the tux.
They really should make waiters
wear nametags.
Yes, Roz, carrying trays
and taking drink orders
leaves so much room for ambiguity.
Shut up.
I think it's going pretty well, don't you?
Do you think anyone's suspicious?
No, it's the greatest phoney reception
I've ever been to.
So how are you holding up?
If I have to stretch my muscles
into a smile one more time,
I think my face may crack.
MEL: Niles.
- Yes, darling!
It's time to cut the cake, so why
don't you just gather everyone around?
- Okay.
- All right.
Excuse me, I'm sorry, I need
to borrow Frasier for just one moment.
Oh, sure.
Uh, Frasier, I had an interesting little
phone call from Donny this afternoon.
- Oh?
- Yes.
He said you'd been by
to see him earlier today.
I may have done so.
Yes, he said you were a busy little bee
before the wedding,
first buzzing in Niles's ear and then
you were buzzing in Daphne's ears...
- Let me explain. Now, you see...
- Buzz, buzz...
Now... Now please...
Just stop that, please!
You see, I've been torturing myself
trying to figure out
how this all happened so quickly,
and now I know.
I won't forget this.
- What was that all about?
- Donny talked to Mel.
- Told you not to go down there.
- Oh, Dad, stop it!
MEL:
Attention, everyone.
Before we cut the cake,
Niles's brother Frasier
would like to make a toast
in our honour.
I didn't know you were doing this.
Neither did I.
Well, uh...
Love...
...is an awesome force.
It can make us do things
we never imagined were possible.
For you see,
we don't actually choose love.
It chooses us.
And once it has, we are powerless
to do anything about it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
raise your glasses with me
in toasting my brother
and the love of his life,
for she is truly the woman
of his dreams.
And my father and I couldn't be
more thrilled with his choice.
To the happy couple.
[CROWD CHATTERS]
Well, wasn't that clever
of your brother?
It's only too bad
your little English muffin
wasn't here to enjoy it as well.
Which reminds me,
you do realise that
while we are pretending to be married,
you absolutely cannot be seen
in public with Daphne.
- L...
- I love you too, honey.
Hello?
Hello, is anybody home?
MARTIN: Hey, Simon.
Just making coffee. You want some?
I was thinking of something colder
with a bit more of an amber hue.
MARTIN: Beer?
- Brilliant!
If you aren't the finest detective
in Seattle,
I am the prince of Wales.
MARTIN:
How did Eddie like his walk?
The little nipper loved it.
Oh, I think nature's calling him again.
His bladder's worse than mine.
I'll be back in a flash.
MARTIN:
Okay.
Was that Simon's voice I heard?
Yeah, he just took Eddie
on a walk for me.
Well, about time that chowderhead
made himself useful.
Oh, don't be so hard on him.
He tries.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Yes, well, if you're talking about
my patience, he certainly does.
- Ah. Niles, come on in.
- Frasier.
Oh, hey, Dad, about a block
from here I saw a dog
that looked remarkably like Eddie
tied up outside a bar.
- Impossible. He was just here.
NILES: Oh.
So, uh, did you say anything to her?
No, no, you told us not to.
Want us out of here?
No, I think I'll be safer
with witnesses.
- Niles, I didn't hear you come in.
- I just got here.
DAPHNE: Hey.
- Hey.
- How are you today?
- Wonderful.
I realised that postponing
our date one day
doesn't really amount to much
in the great scheme of things.
- So how was your wedding reception?
- Oh, it was your average night in hell.
Well, that's behind us now.
We have a wonderful evening
to look forward to.
I bought a new dress.
It's much too expensive,
but you're worth it.
And I'm getting my hair done
and my...
Why are you looking
at each other like that?
We're not looking
at each other like that.
Like what? Like anything.
MARTIN: Uh-uh.
DAPHNE: Yes, you were.
Those darty little glances
mean something's up. Niles?
- About tonight...
- I hate the way this is starting.
Mel feels that as long as she and I
are acting like we're married,
you and I can't be seen together
in public.
- So that means...
- I know what that means.
It's just until the divorce.
- Whenever that bloody is.
- Daphne...
If you'll excuse me,
I have a splitting headache.
NILES: You know, if you look at it
from Mel's point of view,
it really does make a lot of sense.
He came so close.
- What did you say?
- I said, "Damn that Mel."
No, you didn't.
You should have, but you didn't.
Sounded to me
like you were taking her side.
All right, could we turn
the clock back two minutes
and pretend this never happened?
Why don't we just turn it back
to 10 minutes before my wedding
and save everybody all this trouble?
NILES: What are you saying?
- What do you think I'm saying?
Sounds like you're saying
you're sorry you did this.
- Maybe that's what I'm saying.
- Oh, boy.
Before anybody
says something they'll regret...
Butt out! If you hadn't opened your
mouth, we wouldn't be in this mess.
Donny wouldn't be suing me
and everyone else in sight.
And I wouldn't be out
two weeks' salary
for a new dress
I'm apparently never going to wear.
And you wouldn't be kowtowing
to that shrew of a wife of yours.
- This is all my fault?
- Oh, shut up, Frasier.
The only thing more hollow
than your protest of innocence
is your big, fat head!
I am wounded!
I intervened only out of love and caring
about the two people...
Oh, put a sock in it.
I am sick of listening to you yammering
on about everything under the sun.
- Daphne...
- And I'm sick of listening to you too.
You got anything to say, old man?
Good!
[DOOR SLAMS]
I'm waiting.
For what?
An apology for that unprovoked
broadside you levelled at me.
You expect me to apologise to you?
Expect it, sir, and demand it.
Well, then here's my answer. No!
- No?
- No!
And furthermore, why don't you take
your broadside, stuff it in a chair
and keep your unlimited supply
of opinions, suggestions, proposals
and recommendations to yourself.
- Well, I never.
- No, you always.
Get out!
How's a corned beef sandwich
sound?
I am appalled.
Well, no problem. There's some
smoked turkey in here too.
What is my offence?
What egregious sin
have I committed
that I should be so maligned?
Was I to just sit idly by
and watch these two misguided souls
embark on doomed relationships?
Would they have thanked me
for that?
- Not very likely, I dare say.
- Who moved the mustard?
- Top shelf, door.
- Bingo.
And then, when they were perched
on the very brink of disaster,
I snatched them
from the gaping maw
and placed them gently
into one another's arms.
But am I accorded a hero's welcome
for my troubles?
Am I hoisted on their shoulders
and paraded about the room?
I don't have my glasses.
What's the expiration date?
Last week.
I'll chance it.
No.
Those two ingrates
turn on me like vipers
and make me the villain
of the piece.
Well, hear me now.
From this day forward, Frasier Crane
will not interfere with those two.
This is it. Finished. Finito.
[SPEAKS IN LATIN]
MARTIN: Uh-huh.
- I know I've made
declarations like this before, but I tell
you what, Dad, you mark the calendar.
You note the time on your watch.
This is it.
Well, if you figure out a way
to get them back together,
I'll be in my room
if you need any help.
Have you been listening to me?
MARTIN: Well, I tried not to,
but some of it still got through.
Hello, Dr. Crane.
Daphne.
- Making yourself a sandwich?
- No, Dad did.
Hope he didn't use the mayonnaise.
I meant to throw it out.
- I've seen him eat worse.
- I'll say.
Remember when he dropped
his hot dog at the petting zoo?
Oh, Dr. Crane, I'm so sorry
I said those things about you.
I didn't mean them.
Oh, I know, Daphne. Come here.
I guess this all finally came
crashing down on me.
Yes, I know.
It's perfectly understandable.
Listen, I know you can't go out
on your date with Niles tonight,
but what's to stop two friends
from going out to dinner?
My treat. You can even wear
that new dress of yours.
DAPHNE:
Thank you.
That's a lovely offer,
but I think I'll just stay home tonight.
Have a quiet night.
- I understand.
- Thank you.
- Sure you won't change your mind?
- Positive.
Hello.
My furry friend and I have just
concluded our daily constitutional,
with young Edward here dropping
a few amendments along the way.
So, what's on the docket tonight?
All I want is a quiet night at home.
Oh, Stilts,
you and I are of one mind.
I'll hoist a beer
while you get dinner started
and then when our bellies are full
and you've done the dishes,
we will adjourn to the Winnebago
where Mr. Jean-Claude Van Damme,
the Muscles from Brussels, will ply
his trade against the forces of evil.
- Ready at 8?
- Make it 7:30.
NILES:
Good idea, Dad.
An evening out, just the two of us.
I had no idea you enjoyed
the Natural History Museum.
Oh, sure, and that documentary on
the rain forest is supposed to be great.
That's what I hear.
Hope it has Pygmies. I like Pygmies.
I know you do.
So, uh, where's...?
She went out with Frasier
to a restaurant for dinner.
Ah.
- Did she happen to ask about...?
- Sorry.
Dad, we're going up.
Oh, God. Oh, I'm sorry.
Well, we'll just have to take
the long way.
Why do you like Pygmies so much?
They're short and they blow darts.
What's not to like?
Come on. Come on up here.
NILES: What could possibly be
so important for me to see up here?
The guy in 1708
got some homing pigeons.
He built a coop up here for them.
Pigeons? I don't like pigeons.
They have no respect for public art.
Trust me. You're gonna like this.
Dad, I don't think I handled things
very well today.
Do you think Daphne
will ever forgive me?
Why don't you ask her for yourself?
Your table is ready, sir.
- You look stunning.
- Thank you.
You look dashing.
FRASIER:
I trust this will be to your liking.
Everything's to my liking.
Looks like we're having
that first date after all.
You went to so much trouble.
It wasn't me. It was your brother.
Well, you know me. I hate to butt in.
NILES:
Ohh...
I'd planned to take Daphne to dinner
when suddenly inspiration struck.
Since you two couldn't go
to Au Pied de Cochon this evening,
my faithful companion and I
would bring it to you courtesy
of their caterer.
If dancing at the Starlight Room
was impossible,
we'd give you the real thing.
It's all so overwhelming.
Yeah. Frasier, Dad,
I don't know what to say.
You even got that man
to move his pigeons.
There were no pigeons.
Ohh.
How can we ever thank you two?
Just have a beautiful evening.
I think we can do that.
- And, Frasier, listen...
- Apology accepted, Niles.
Oh, just remember to give
the lingonberry sauce a little stir...
MARTIN:
They can figure it out.
Right.
- Daphne, about today...
- Let's just forget about that.
Why don't we start from here?
I would love that.
- To us.
I'm usually so nervous
on a first date,
but not tonight.
Would you like to dance?
Oh, I'd love to.
So where are you from?
- Manchester, England.
- Oh, my.
- Big family?
- Hideously.
[NILES CHUCKLES]
DAPHNE:
And you?
I'm from a small mountain village
in Tibet.
[DAPHNE CHUCKLING]
Tenzing Norgay used
to carry me to school.
You know what
I've always wondered?
- Think I can guess?
- Yeah.