NILES: Ah.
FRASIER: Yay!
- Did you make a wish, sweetheart?
- Of course she did.
She wished her father
still loved his children enough
to call his only daughter
on her birthday.
Or his wife.
Oh, but that's a man for you.
Once he's planted his seed
and you've borne his spawn,
he moves on
to spread his filth elsewhere.
Sounds like a toast to me.
- I'll get the champagne.
- I'll just have a beer.
Oh, I'm not sure we should
introduce alcohol into the situation.
Well, Daphne, why don't you
open your presents, huh?
- Oh, that's a good idea.
- Here, here. Mine and Dad's first.
Heh, heh.
[NILES CLEARS THROAT]
Happy birthday, Daphne.
Oh, it's a journal. Oh, it's lovely.
Thank you.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
You don't need to say that
for my benefit.
I wanted to get you
one of those robot dogs.
You know,
something you could really use.
- Hey, Niles.
NILES: Hey, Roz.
FRASIER: Oh, hi, Roz.
- Thank you. Sorry I'm late.
Oh, no, not at all.
Uh, Daphne's just opening her gifts.
Oh, here's mine.
Roz, you didn't have to
get me anything.
Don't be silly. Happy birthday.
- Ooh.
- FRASIER: Oh.
MARTIN:
Wow.
We love it.
Yes, Roger loved black lace,
but he didn't get to see me in it.
Black lace, I mean.
I bought this one for you. New.
- Thank you, Roz.
- Some man break your heart, did he?
- Oh, yeah, but I'll be okay.
- Sure you will.
Until you realise he was the love
of your life, and he's gone for good.
Then not a night will pass
when you don't beg the good Lord
to take you in your sleep.
We all have those thoughts.
Niles, can I see you in the kitchen,
please?
Yeah.
- What's this?
- Ha. That's what I said.
Difficult?
I yearn for the days of difficult.
Difficult was a picnic.
I keep a picture of difficult in
a heart-shaped frame next to my bed.
- Difficult was a...
- All right, Niles, I know.
But it's harder for her now.
I think she's finally realising
that Dad's not coming back.
And I guess I am too.
I'm sorry.
I will be more patient with her.
Thank you, Niles.
- And if you do it right,
he'll bleed from the inside
and no one will know it was you.
Oh, Daphne, I think there's still
an unopened gift here for you.
I think there's an unopened gift for me
in the fridge.
Try and stop me.
Daphne.
Happy birthday, darling.
Oh, Niles, it's a trip.
This weekend, you and I are jetting off
to Hawaii
for a five-star Polynesian retreat.
Oh, how exciting. Oh, thank you.
The first day,
we're being taken by Outrigger
to an exclusive island
for a private luau.
Roger and I were supposed to go back
to Wisconsin this weekend
for my family reunion.
Oh, that's lovely.
Then the second day,
we're going to take a cruise to Molokai.
ROZ:
Of course, you can't go to Wisconsin
without taking a couple
of cheese tours.
[NILES CHUCKLES]
- Well, you sure can't.
FRASIER: No.
And then when we're in Molokai
we're going to go snorkelling
- with the sea turtles.
- And then the Dells.
I mean, Roger really wanted to ride
one of those big duck boats.
I've heard enough.
All these lovey-dovey stories
about travelling and romance.
And you with your birthday.
Can't you all see that I'm hurting?
I can't hide it anymore.
What are you doing?
I wanna change my wish.
ROZ:
I started the dishwasher.
FRASIER:
Thanks, Roz. I'll see you tomorrow.
Do you want me
to run the vacuum cleaner?
No, thanks.
I can do it in the morning.
Are you sure?
I mean, it would just take a second.
- You don't wanna go home, do you?
- Not really.
Alice is in Wisconsin
with her grandmother,
and it's just hard
to face an empty house.
Well, I'll tell you what, Roz.
Why don't you sit down
and we'll shoot the breeze for a while.
Thanks.
And when I think about this trip
to Wisconsin,
I just dread going without Roger.
My family thinks I'm a total loser
as it is.
Now I'm just gonna prove them right.
"Roz is a failure at love.
Roz can't find a man."
- They don't really say that, do they?
- Oh, you haven't met
my perfect sister, Denise.
I mean, I love her and everything,
but she's a total bitch.
Hey, you know,
l... I could go with you. Hmm?
- What?
- Sure. For moral support.
Oh. Frasier, is that how you wanna
spend your vacation?
I don't know. It just might be
the perfect time for me to see
a giant duck and a lot of cheese.
Thank you, Frasier.
You wanna watch some TV?
Maybe we can find a good movie.
Yeah.
Yeah, ever since
this whole Roger thing happened,
you've really come through for me.
It means a lot.
Why can't more men be like you?
I mean, you are exactly
what women are looking for.
Yeah, the women I date
don't seem to know that.
Some women don't know
what's good for them.
Terrific.
I'm the broccoli of dating.
FRASIER: Morning.
- Morning!
- Can I get you some coffee?
ROZ: I would love to stay, but no.
I really gotta run.
I got the tile guy coming.
Right.
- So this is a little strange, huh?
ROZ: Yeah, it is.
But good strange.
Yeah.
[ROZ SIGHS]
You know.
Tile guy.
Right. Uh, y... I'll get up.
No.
Okay.
I really have to go.
I'll see you at work.
- Roz, are you okay?
- Everything's super.
- Maybe we should talk about this.
- And we will. Just not right now
because I'm really late.
You know, I mean, for the tile guy.
Let me walk you out.
Oh, Roz,
uh, maybe we could have dinner later?
Okay. And we can talk then.
I mean, not that I really need to talk,
because I'm fine.
- Unless you're not fine.
- No, no, I'm fine.
- A little strange though, huh?
- Yeah. But good strange.
MARTIN: Eddie, just because
I dropped something
doesn't make it yours.
God, what have I done?
What have I done? What have I done?
- Morning, Fras.
- Morning, Dad.
- See the paper yet?
- Uh, no, I haven't.
Big story about how Roz's purse
spent the night on the coffee table.
- It's not what it looks like.
- I know that.
Oh, what do you mean? Shows what
you know. It's exactly what it looks like.
Ah! I knew that.
Well, anyway,
it's none of your business
so I'm not discussing it with you.
Oh, Dad, I've done a terrible thing.
Oh, jeez, what happened?
And don't tell me too much.
Oh, l... I don't even know
how I let this happen.
She was lonely. She probably thinks
I took advantage of her.
I mean,
that's why she ran out of here.
- Do you think I did?
- Fras, you're both adults.
- Where's the harm?
- Well, you can't be serious, Dad.
I mean,
do you realise what this means?
I have probably
destroyed our friendship.
Do you know what she'll see
every time she looks at me?
- Your naked body.
- Oh, dear God.
I was gonna say
somebody who has betrayed her trust,
but, oh, dear God.
Frasier, don't get all worked up. When
are you supposed to see her next?
- Uh, we're meeting for dinner tonight.
- So everything's normal.
You're gonna feel weird and stupid
for a while,
and then you'll have a big laugh
about it and move on.
Yeah, you're probably right, huh?
I mean, we're... We're adults.
We can discuss this.
We're gonna be fine.
Well, we better be.
I told her I'd go to Wisconsin
with her.
Wow, you really were lonely.
I want to go on this trip
as much as you do.
But we can't leave Mom alone
for a week right now.
She seems unbalanced.
Well... Well, maybe she could
stay here with Frasier and Dad.
Oh, oh!
What are we talking about?
It's Mom again.
She's been crying non-stop
since we left here last night.
Sounds like a job
for the prescription pad, Niles.
I can't even get Dad on the phone.
He doesn't even know I'm engaged.
I guess I can forget about him
walking me down the aisle.
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello.
Roz, hi.
Yeah, hang... Hang on one second.
Daphne, I have the solution.
I want you to use those tickets
and take your mother to Hawaii.
Are you out of your mind?
No, no, we are gonna have
a lifetime of romantic trips.
Now what's important
is taking care of your mom.
- Like you said, she's fragile.
- Niles, that's very thoughtful,
but I don't want to go to Hawaii
with my mom.
- I want to go with you.
- Just hear me out.
[SIGHS]
You really gonna let that old bat
manipulate you out of a trip to Hawaii?
- Dad, I have a plan.
- Niles, you're a sucker.
You know Mrs. Moon's
so-called knee injury?
Well, last night I noticed her
limping on the wrong leg.
I know. She switches.
So how's Roz?
- She's fleeing the city, thank you.
- Oh, come on.
She's going to Wisconsin
without me.
She's leaving immediately.
I told you this was gonna happen.
- Our friendship is in ruins.
- Yeah.
What do you mean, "yeah"?
Well, I kind of thought
that might happen.
I was just trying
to make you feel better.
Now, remember,
when you arrive, a car will be waiting
to take you to
the Nani Emaka Hehila Ai House.
I don't know why we can't go
somewhere where they speak English.
They do speak English in Hawaii,
Mom.
How come you can fly to Hawaii,
but you can't fly to England?
How come you can drive your car,
but you can't do your own laundry?
Have a good trip.
Thanks again, Niles.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
I wish I could walk you to the gate,
but...
Yeah, well, we better hurry
if we're gonna pass customs.
It's the same country, Mom.
- I'm gonna miss you so much.
- Dear God, I know.
Well, that's gonna be a good time.
I do feel a little guilty,
but it's for a greater good.
- Where to, Niles?
- Uh, Virgin Atlantic. It's right there.
What's this?
Are you going somewhere?
England. I'm gonna find Daphne's
father and bring him back here
if I have to check every pub
in Manchester.
- You can't be serious.
- I can't do my own laundry
because I can't carry the basket
and my cane at the same time.
That's what I should have said.
Daphne wants to get
her parents back together,
and I'm gonna try
to make that happen.
At the very least,
he's gonna walk her down that aisle.
- It'll be the biggest surprise ever.
- It's a beautiful gesture, Niles.
MARTIN:
Bye.
Why didn't you tell me
he was going to England?
Same reason I didn't tell him
you were going to Wisconsin.
- Which way?
- Oh, right.
Uh, it's Concourse B.
Think this is a smart plan,
surprising Roz in front of her family?
Well, what else would you suggest
I do, Dad?
I couldn't reach her.
Roz and I gotta talk
before this turns into
a permanent divide in our friendship.
Okay. But you know what she's
gonna see when she looks at you.
I know, my naked body.
I'll have you know there are worse...
All right, just stop there. I've got
enough horror shows in my head.
- Here we are.
- Thank you.
Oh, by the way, Dad,
I got you a little something
to keep you company while I'm away.
Oh, no way!
- The robot dog.
- Yeah.
- Thanks, son.
- Sure.
Oh, good, you got the girl one
so it won't fight with Eddie.
Dad, it's not a girl.
That's where the batteries go.
Hi. Um, I'm looking for Roz Doyle.
Oh, well, she's out shopping
with her cousin right now.
But come in. I'm her sister, Denise.
- Oh, well, it's a pleasure to meet you.
- Oh, likewise.
All we've been hearing is
Roger this, and Roger that,
- but we've seen no Roger.
- Yes. Well, l...
We were beginning to think
that you didn't really exist.
- I'm afraid you've made a mistake.
- Well, obviously, we did,
but you can't blame us.
It wouldn't be the first time
that she's made up a boyfriend.
We've really been having a lot of fun
with her.
Oh, honey, look, Roger is here.
- There really is one.
- Well, I'll be a son of a gun.
Good to know you.
Craig Dawson, MetLife.
Hi. Roger Hammerstein.
DENISE:
Oh.
Well, come on in
and meet everyone.
- Oh, good, thank you.
- Roger, this is Aunt Pearl
- and Curtis.
FRASIER: Hello.
- And Great Uncle Olaf.
FRASIER: Oh, hi.
Well, honey, it looks like you owe Roz
an apology.
DENISE: Oh, no, she knows
I was just teasing her.
I'm just relieved
that she's finally found someone.
We just want her to have
the kind of happiness that we found.
Well, you know,
I intend to do everything in my power
to give her just that. I love Roz.
And I intend to prove it to her.
- That's why I've come.
- Oh, my God, what's going on?
- Roz.
- Oh, Roger, can Craig fix you a drink?
- Roger?
- Yeah, sweetheart, hi.
I'd love that drink.
DENISE:
Well, well, well.
Looks like you've really made
an impression on Roger here, Roz.
ROZ: Yeah.
- How did you two meet again?
Gosh, well, it's... It's the cutest story.
Here, come on, honey, sit down. Uh...
Uh, actually, um, it all started
when Alice used to wave at me
when I was driving
my trash-collecting truck.
Oh.
Well, I guess Alice is sure
gonna be happy to see you again.
Oh, well, you know, it's funny.
As well as, uh, Alice and I get along,
she always mistakes me
for Roz's boss.
- It's weird, isn't it?
- Oh, yeah.
- Here we are.
- Oh, uh, thank you.
So, Roger, I hear you're a big golfer.
What do you shoot?
Well, you know, actually, since I met
Roz, um, I don't get much time for golf.
Well, don't get too used to that, Roz.
I've been a golf widow
ever since I've been married.
It's like a disease with them.
Well, maybe with, uh, most men,
but not with me.
I mean, my spare time is precious
so I like to spend it
with the people that I love.
Like Roz and Alice, and, who knows,
maybe someday some more little ones.
DENISE:
Aw.
Especially if they look like this here.
Oh, my God, I hated that picture.
Big ugly glasses and I guess
I was trying to look like Dorothy Hamill.
We warned you not to get that haircut,
but you insisted.
You know, if I'd met this girl
in the fifth grade,
I wouldn't have dated anybody else.
Gosh, can I get a copy of this
for my desk at work?
- You have a desk?
- Dashboard. Heh, heh. You know.
Yeah, I looked
in the "getting started" section.
Yeah, I did that.
Voice activation?
Yeah, I did everything it said.
[BARKS]
MARTIN:
Huh?
Appendix B?
Well, where is Appendix B?
I just want this damn thing
to do some tricks.
Can't you make these things easier?
You shouldn't have to be
a rocket scientist
to play with some stupid toy.
[EDDIE BARKS]
Eddie, be quiet. I'm on the phone.
So this one's getting tired,
she wants to head back up the beach,
when finally she sees the blanket
surrounded by candles,
and the food and the wine
that I'd set up.
And don't forget the diamond bracelet
you gave me.
CROWD:
Aw.
I had no idea there was that kind
of money in the garbage business.
You have no idea
about a lot of things.
What's that supposed to mean?
Well, why can't you be more like him
and do something special for me
once in a while?
Why can't you be more like her
and not be such a nag?
That was the best half-hour
I have ever spent with my family.
Thank you.
But what are you doing here?
I just had to make sure
we were okay.
- I told you we were okay.
- Yeah, I know. Then you ran away.
I know. I should have stayed
and talked to you.
It's just, usually when I'm freaked out
I turn to you.
And this time I just didn't feel
like I could.
[SIGHS]
- I'm so sorry.
- For what?
For that. For that evening. That...
You were vulnerable
and I feel like I took advantage of you.
Oh, Frasier, I'm a grownup.
And I make my own decisions.
I was just worried that...
Well, over the years we've almost
gone to bed a couple of times,
and we haven't because we were
afraid it would damage our friendship.
- Now we've done it.
- Right.
I was just worried that things
have changed between us.
That's what I came here to ask you.
I remember the last time I sat here,
just like this.
My old high-school boyfriend
sat right where you are
and he told me he'd been accepted
into college in Boston.
Hmm.
And I just stared at his shoelaces.
I was afraid I'd cry
if I looked anywhere else, you know.
Anyway, we promised
that we would always be friends.
And it was just the saddest thing
in the world
because I knew it wasn't true.
And this time?
We will always be friends, Frasier.
Nothing's gonna ever change that.
I can't believe
you travelled all this way.
Well, that's what people do
when they care about someone.
[CHATTERING]
[COUGHING]
Excuse me.
Do you know a man
named Harry Moon?
And no, that is not the start
of a limerick.
Mr. Moon?
Who's asking?
My name is Niles Crane.
I'm planning to marry your daughter.
You look okay to me.
All right, you have my blessing.
Uh, thank you. But, actually,
I'm here to reunite you with your wife.
Oh, Mr. Moon, Mr. Moon. Mr... Mr...
Aah!