Does he wear jewelry?
'cause I don't do "man jewelry. "
He doesn't wear jewelry.
What about skin issues?
Because I have a thing
against tags, growths,
any kind of fleshy masses.
Ann, he's male and his heart is beating.
What else do you need to know?
Okay.
Frasier.
Roz, I came as quickly as I could.
What's the emergency?
Oh, no, it's not an
emergency. It's just...
Hi. I'm Ann Hodges .
I'm divorced.
I'm sorry. I'm Dr. Frasier crane.
I thought you two would like to meet.
Ann is in insurance.
Oh, well, I'm sorry she dragged you
all the way down here.
I've just renewed my policy.
Perhaps Roz could introduce
you to my brother Niles.
Is he single?
No, but with a baby on the way,
he might need some additional coverage.
Super.
Well, thanks a lot, Roz.
This was totally worth
a drive across town.
Are you dense? I was
trying to set you guys up.
Why would you do that?
I don't know.
Maybe because you
haven't had a date in ages
and it's starting to show.
What is that, your purse?
This is a grocery tote.
I wanted to pick up some vegetables
and some cat food at the market.
You did not get a cat.
No, no, I am cat-sitting
for a neighbor.
And I go out. I'm
going out this evening .
With whom?
People.
People you're related to?
They're still people.
Listen, Roz, I may not
go out as often as you do,
but that's because I have standards.
Haven't you ever heard
of waiting for Miss Right?
Yeah, well, Miss Right
has standards, too,
and she's not looking
to meet Mr. Mothballs.
You can smell that ? Oh, dear.
You need a place holder.
You know, someone you can go out with
and just keep your dating muscles toned.
That way you'll be ready
when Miss Right comes along.
And Ann Hodges is a born place holder.
I don't want to go out with
somebody I'm not interested in .
I would rather wait for Miss Right.
And while I'm waiting,
there's no reason I can't
li a rich and rewarding life.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I need to get these vegetables home
and into a hearty winter soup.
Oh, hi, guys.
Hey, Doc, you're always free.
My cousin's in town.
Why don't you help me show her the city?
Did Roz put you up to this?
I had nothing to do
with it. I swear to God.
Well, I'm sorry, Kenny,
but I am booked all this weekend.
Oh, here's luck.
I found a perfectly good
thimble in this pocket.
See you later.
Thanks anyway.
Hey, I tried.
NILES; Reservation for crane.
For four, sir?
No, sorry, for five. We added one.
All we have is a table for four.
We can all squeeze.
This one's always on my lap
after the second drink anyway.
very well, madam.
get the chair.
You know, there's really no
need to go to all this trouble.
I have a perfectly good
winter soup back home.
Don't be silly. Oh, no.
All right, um...
Well, um...
Oh!
I'm sorry. Do you have anything higher?
Sorry, sir. I will look for a cushion.
So, Fras,
tell everybody about that new
antique you picked up today.
Well, it's a late Regency
fruitwood mirror.
very valuable if it has the
original glass, which mine does.
No. What are the odds?
Boy, if you like mirrors
you should see the one Ronee's
got in her dressing room.
It's got lights all around the edges,
and it has three settings.
Yeah. Daytime, nighttime, and yikes.
(laughing)
Oh, yes, excuse me.
If I could get a place
setting, that would be lovely.
What's Inizio Due cuore?
That's our appetizer sampler for two.
A bruschetta for you,
a bruschetta for your love and so on.
Is it possible to make that for one?
One?
Yes, a bruschetta for me,
no bruschetta for my love and so on.
I'm sorry. It's dueor no.
NILES; That's fine.
We'll get two orders
and we'll just all share.
very good.
Mm, looks delicious.
This is fun, you know.
This is the first time
Marty and I have been
out with another couple.
And... Frasier.
It's fun being out with Frasier, too.
(all agreeing)
We love being out with
Frasier, don't we, Niles.
All right, listen, all
of you, just knock it off.
Welcome, everyone.
42 years ago tonight,
I married my beautiful Theresa.
And now, we hope
that all you loving couples out there
will help us celebrate our happiness
by joining us in a dance.
The fish..
Oh, just go dance .
Hello...
Mr. Bottomsley.
Dinner was an absolute nightmare.
Fortunately, I was able
to slip out of there early
and pick you up a little treat.
(chuckles)
Fresh tuna.
. You're welcome
(over answering machine)
; Frasier, this is Roz.
Write down this number.
555-01 79.
Don't get mad, but that's Ann's number.
I talked to her and she really thought
you were cute and sweet and...
Honestly, why does everyone assume
that I need some
companionship in my life?
Has the world gone mad, Mr. Bottomsley?
What shall we two bachelor
s do this evening, Mr. B?
Perhaps a crossword puzzle?
Maybe watch a little telly?
Oh, I
know--
how about a nice hot bath?
(chuckles)
I'm just teasing.
, Now, I know that you're
used to eating canned tuna
so this will taste different,
but if you're like me,
I think you'll agree
it's much better.
If only there were a treat here for me.
(gasps)
What's this?
A delicious nine-vegetable winter soup.
Oh...
(sniffs)
Yes, Mr. B, I think you were right
about the bay leaves.
(with British accent); Oh, Mr.
Bottomsley, lovely to see you again, sir.
Your customary table, I presume, hmm?
Splendid.
Here you go.
(sighs)
come on, buddy.
Well, isn't this civilized?
Beat it, Eddie. There's none for you.
Do you feel a draft, Mr. B?
I'm just a little bit cold.
There we are.
That's better.
Ooh, that's still a little too hot.
You know what? While
we're letting that cool,
why don't we find a
home for our antique.
There we are. Yes.
You know, you don't find
one of these very easily.
Especially in such good condition.
Won't that covetous Niles
be m when he sees it, hmm?
But he can't have it, can he?
No.
Yes, he can't have it,
can he?
No, no...
Dear God, I'm Aunt Shirley .
(cat shrieks)
get that number.
Mrs. gablyczyck... these new shirts,
did Mrs. crane ask
you to buy them for me?
Because I already have
shirts just like these.
No, no, after I wash, I pin them
and wrap in plastic.
You not like?
No, no...
(voice breaking); I like very much.
Thank you, mister.
(doorbell ringing)
Oh...
No, I'll get it.
Hey, Dad, come on in. Hi.
Daphne will be right down and we can go.
Where's Frasier?
On a date.
get out!
About time, huh?
You know, it's like I
was saying to Eddie--
this guy's got to get a life.
DAPHNE; Niles, I left $60
on the desk yesterday
and now it's gone.
Is that proof enough for you?
Are you sure you didn't misplace it?
You know I didn't.
What's going on?
Ever since we hired Mrs. gablyczyck
things have been
disappearing--
liquor, money, linens.
So she's stealing from you.
Yes. We don't know that.
And frankly, it's hard to believe
that someone who'll
go out in a rainstorm
to clean pigeon muck
from the solarium skylight
is capable of theft.
We can't put up with stealing
just because she's
good at what she does.
First of all, she's not
She's brilliant.
She's an artist.
Tell you what-- you give
me five minutes with her.
If she's hiding anything,
I'll get it out of her.
Dad, we are not going to coerce
a confession out of this woman
based on circumstantial evidence.
(bell dings)
Oven is clean.
Now I scrub down dishwasher.
Oh, Mrs. gablyczyck, you
dropped some... money.
Thank you, mister.
All right, Dad, you've got five minutes.
FRASIER; We'd like your famous
appetizer for two, please.
I'll let your waiter know.
Thank you very much.
So, Ann...
tell me everything.
Who is Ann Hodges?
Wow. Well, I'm an
insurance claims adjuster.
That's what' s so funny.
When we met, you thought I was in sales,
but I'm not.
Oh.
I'm in claims.
Well, you know, we don't
have to have just shop talk.
What are your dreams?
Oh, my God.
Well, my dream is to be
aseniorclaims adjuster.
It's sort of the same,
but you get a private cube
and your own extension.
I would've got it last year
but I paid a big claim
the company didn't like.
I knew I goofed the second I did it.
It was just one of those
"Shoot!" moments, you know,
when you just say "Shoot!"
Do you ever do that,
make a big mistake and
want to go back in time
and just do something different?
Oh, yes.
Well, I'm going to run
to the ladies' room.
I just had to have that Dr. Pepper
while I was getting dressed.
good evening, sir. Ah.
Would you care for something to
drink? Yes, as a matter of fact,
I would-- I'd like,
uh, your finest bottle
of Barolo, please.
Why don't you come back in a minute
and see what the lady likes.
Doc? Hm?
Hey, small world! Oh, Kenny, hi.
This is my cousin I
was telling you about.
This is Dr. crane. Oh.
e, Hello. Dr. c ran
I heard your show
today-- it was great.
(chuckles); Well...
Is this your, uh, first time in Seattle?
Yes, it is-- I'm
a fine arts dealer,
but I'm considering a curator
position at the Seattle Art Museum.
That's impressive.
KENNY:Oh, that's nothing.
She teaches kids ballet,
and she rock climbs, she plays the harp.
Oh, what am I doing? I
haven't introduced you.
Dr. Frasier crane,
Liz Wright.
It's lovely to meet you. .. Miss Wright.
(chuckles)
Well, it's too bad
you're not free tonight.
You could've joined us.
Well, how about tomorrow night?
Oh, I'd love to, but I'm on
a plane tonight to Amsterdam.
I have a job offer there as well.
I'm doing my best to
convince her to pick Seattle,
but it's tough when you're
up against the Dutch.
Ah.
I could've really used
your help there, Doc.
Yes, well, you know, I'm
just about finished up here.
You know, we wouldn't want
to interrupt your date.
Oh, it's not a date. It's not a date.
It's just a little business thing.
I'll tell you what,
I'll just wrap things up here
and then I'll come and help
yo wage the battle for Seattle.
(laughs) ; Okay.
That's great. We'll see you soon.
Man, oh, man, that place was a madhouse.
I got so tired of waiting,
I just decided to hold it.
I'm so glad yo u picked Italian.
I love macaroni.
Ah.
That's another thing w e
have in common, I guess.
(chuckles) ; Well...
Uh, you know, Ann, uh,
first dates are funny.
Uh, sometimes it takes a
while for two people to click.
Sometimes you know right away, and, uh,
I think when you do, you
should just feel free...
You are so cute. c lick.
(laughing)
What?
click,
click--
the sound of us clicking.
Ann, um...
You don't know what a relief this is.
I've only had one date since my divorce.
Well, half a date.
The jerk actually called
it off in the middle of dinner.
I was a wreck.
I didn't get out of bed for a week.
Or shave my legs.
Your appetizers. Oh.
gosh, this is a feast.
I'm not sure we'll need
to order a main course.
Well, this ain't gonna do it forme.
I'm starvin' like Marvin.
Mrs. gablyczyck, we're friends here.
No one wants to send you to
jail or back to your country.
We just need you to admit
that you took the money.
I no take nothing.
Do you want to go to jail?!
Do you want to go back to your country?!
Well, I was hoping it
wouldn't come to this,
but I'm afraid we're going
to have to show her the tape.
What tape?
It's from the surveillance camera.
It shows you stealing.
(whispers) ; You have a camera?
DAPHNE; You might as well confess.
I've got the evidence.
I want to see tape.
All right.
I'll give you one last chance
to tell the truth, Mrs. gablyczyck,
because if we watch this tape,
we'll have no choice
but to call the police.
I see tape.
All right.
I'm putting the tape in.
Here I go.
I'm pressing play.
Now I'm switching the
input from cable to video.
Niles, get ready to call the police.
?? .. (people singing on tape)
; ??... birthday, dear Dad...
Hey, that's me!
Yes,
I used an old tape of
your birthday party,
but the surveillance part's coming up.
Last chance, Mrs. gablyczyck.
It's coming up...
Okay, I have to step in here...
All right, all right!
I stole.
You did?
I didn't think you know.
I bring it back.
(sighs)
Well done, Daphne.
Oh, but I'm so disappointed.
I was really hoping you were wrong.
Hey, hey, did you see that?
Watch this again.
What?
You must have put the camera down
when we went into the
kitchen for ice cream.
Watch Daphne's mother.
My mother? She stayed
behind to grab her sweater.
And our candlesticks.
And our
20-year-old scotch.
This is plate I brought home.
so I take Mrs. crane'
leftover meat pie.
But I brought plate back.
Mrs. gablyczyck... we're so sorry.
We've made a terrible mistake.
We know now you didn't steal anything.
can you ever forgive us?
Of course, mister.
You're nice man.
And you're nice lady.
Are you sure that' s all the
little bunny wants to eat,
just a little green salad?
The bunny had a big Mexican lunch.
You know, if you're feeling full,
then I'm sure they could wrap
up the rest of that for you.
Oh, no, I'm just trying to pace myself
so I'll have room for dessert.
I hear the souffl here
is well worth the wait.
Excuse me. I'd better get that.
That didn't even ring.
. Yes, it did. Hello? Oh
Niles?
Is there something wrong?
Oh, dear God, well,
you-you just stay there on the floor.
I'll be right there.
I'm so sorry. Uh...
Is everything all right?
Well, uh, actually, it's my brother.
He's thrown out his back again.
Oh, God, right in the middle
of our magical evening, too.
check, please. Thank you.
Uh, you know...
I guess I'm just going to
have to put you in a cab.
I'm so sorry-- I was having
such a lovely evening.
Well, maybe we could meet
for coffee tomorrow. Yes,
um, all right, all right.
Ah, thank you very much.
Uh, yes, here, yeah, that's fine.
You just keep the change. Uh, thank you.
Uh, shall we?
You know, I'm just going
to call a cab later.
There's no sense all
this food going to waste.
You know what? I-I can't leave.
I can't. It would be rude.
Oh, don't be silly. go . No, no.
It's... it's not like
he's going anywhere anyway.
(chuckling)
Okay. Well, uh, are
you sure you're not hungry?
You're welcome to try some of mine.
Well, now that you mention it,
uh, I guess I would like to try it.
Yes, thank you.
Well, help yourself. Mm-hmm.
Okay, well, where were we?
Oh, that's right. My husband.
Anyway, he says he doesn't love me
He's bored, blah, blah
, he's suffocating.
If only, I say.
I would have gotten a
nice little settlement.
I mean, we were
covered up the yin-yang.
He had a sweet whole-life policy
that paid double for accidental death.
I borrowed against it to get my Hyundai.
Hey!
Who's the ravioli monster?
Roar.
You're worried about
your brother, aren't you?
Mm. Maybe we should just go.
All right.
Once again, I've had
such a lovely evening.
(Ann laughs)
I hope I didn't talk your ear off.
I can still hear you, so no.
(chuckles)
gosh, you know, uh...
I'm parked out back, so I'll
just slip out through the kitchen.
I'm sure the valet can flag you a cab.
Oh.
Okay. Well...
here we are--
the awkward part.
Oh, it's not awkward at all.
I'd be delighted to pay for your cab.
Here we are. Bye-bye.
(chuckling); I...
I hope I'm not too late
You know, I think I talked her
into taking that Seattle job.
Oh, well,
let me be the first to offer
my congratulations... to Seattle.
Thank you.
And please let me offer my services
as, uh... cultural attach?.
Well, I would love that.
I think this calls for a toast.
May I see your list
of champagnes, please?
Ann.
I thought you left our date
to go take care of your brother.
Date? I-I thought you said
you were just wrapping
up a business meeting.
Is that why you ate all my raviolis?
Because you were just
trying to get rid of me?
No, no, of-of course not.
Listen, there's a perfectly
logical explanation
for all this, which is...
I'm sorry. I've-I've got to take that.
Hello?
That didn't ring.
It's very soft.
FRASIER; Oh, gosh, Dad,
that sounds serious.
You stay put. I'll be right there.
(phone rings) Ow! That's loud!
Oh, Doc, what are you doing?
This is exactly like my other date!
Kenny, I think I'd like to get to
the airport a little early tonight.
But, Miss Wright...
I'll meet you out front.
Excuse me.
But, Liz...
This one hurts, Doc.
I had a souffl? coming.
. I'm sorry, Ann
I'm sorry, too.
Sorry for thinking you were different
than all the other jerks out there.
But you're not.
You're just another
selfish, dishonest creep.
You're right. I don't know what to say
Well, maybe you can
come up with something
before we have coffee tomorrow.
Are you seriously suggesting that...
What?!
See you at 1 0:00?
Okay.