(thunder crashing)
(doorbell ringing)
Oh, Niles, thank God
you came quickly.
I've been going mad.
This better be a real emergency,
Frasier.
You pulled me away
from the Gifted Infant'?
Toy Expo.
Yes, yes,
so you missed out on buying
a Tickle Me Tolstoy doll.
Niles, my problem is
more important than that.
You see, I've...
Oh, dear God!
Niles, I've committed a crime.
Don't tell me...
you forgot to send
the Opera Board a thank you note
for the Christmas brickle.
By God, man, it's a real crime
.
Punishable by law!
(thunder crashing)
By law?
Of the United States of America.
(thunder crashing)
Heavens, what have you done?
I'll tell you.
But before you
judge me, Niles, please,
remember how much stress
I've been under lately
.
Of course.
Tell me everything.
Leave nothing out.
All right...
It was a dark and stormy day...
You can leave that out.
All right.
It was an average day,
marred only
by a persistent cough,
caused by a barista's
over-nutmegging my machiatto.
Go ahead, Babette.
What can I do for you?
Well, Dr. Crane,
for about a year now,
I've been... stealing.
I get these uncontrollable urges
to take things.
Such as?
(coughs)
All kinds of things.
Magazines from stores,
a friend's sunglasses.
Things I don't even want.
I see, um...
(clears throat)
Go on.
It's just so unlike me.
I mean,
my friends think I'm dull.
They all say, "Babette,
you're like an old shoe. "
But stealing is so exciting.
It's really the only time I feel alive.
Well, it sounds to me
like you have a classic case
of klepto--...
(coughing)
klepto--...
Kleptomania.
Hi, Babette.
This is Roz.
And if Dr. Crane weren't
hacking up a hairball,
I'm sure he would tell you
that this thrill you get
from stealing
makes up for an emptiness
in your life.
That's the problem you
really need to address.
So, you should seek counseling
or at least find
a support group.
Yes, and may I add...
She's gone and
we're out of time. Oh.
Well, then,
this is Dr. Frasier Crane
saying "Good day, Seattle,
and good mental health. "
Are you okay?
I haven't heard
so much coughing
since I was backstage
at Reggae Sunsplash.
Well... (clears throat)...
I'm fine, Roz.
Thank you, thank you so much.
Your advice was spot on.
It should be.
I've heard you say the
same stuff for ten years now.
"Confront your emotions, "
"communicate, "
"seek counseling. "
I didn't realize my advice
had become so predictable.
Well, it's not
your fault
everyone calls with
the same dumb-ass problems.
They're not
the same problems.
What about
that caller last week--
the sleepwalking transvestite
that kept breaking off his heels
on sewer grates?
I remember him.
You told him to seek counseling.
Yes, I also told him
to wear flats.
Oh, oh, did
Maintenance remember
to bring me
that hammer I asked for?
Oh, yeah, right here.
What do you need it for?
Some imbecile's
been parking in my spot
despite several
strongly worded notes
I have left on his windshield.
The time has come
for me to take matters
into my own hands.
NILES:
My God, Frasier,
so that's what you did.
In an uncontrollable rage
over the commandeering
of your parking space,
you took hammer to car.
You are a vandal.
It was nothing
like that.
My reserved sign was a-dangle.
I used the hammer
to tack it back up.
I'm sorry.
I didn't realize
this spot was reserved.
So all those notes
that I left...
must have...
blown away. Hello.
I'm Dr. Frasier Crane.
Yes.
So you know my show.
It's on your sign.
Willa Haver.
I'm so sorry.
My assigned spot is on the roof,
and with the rain...
Oh, no, no,
it's perfectly
understandable.
And now that I know
that this is your Audi,
let me be the first
to say, "Audi, neighbor. "
NILES:
And that's when
she took the hammer
and put you out of your misery.
That would have
been preferable.
You know, in the
spirit of detente,
I... I could, uh,
buy you some coffee.
Oh, well, that is so sweet
of you,
but I can't right now.
Well, perhaps tomorrow.
Uh, no,
tomorrow's no good either.
Next week, perhaps?
Next week
I'll be out of town.
You know, I'm not sure
if we're hav
ing a devil of a time
coordinating our schedules
or if you're giving
me a polite brush-off.
(car alarm chirping)
Okay.
Now I'm sure.
FRASIER:
My morning's travails aside,
Niles,
you'll be happy to know
I didn't strike out with every woman
I encountered today.
Frasier...
Hm?
I heard the elevator
and I thought,
"I bet that's Frasier,"'
and it is.
How are you,
Mrs. Magrini?
Oh, just grand
and how many times do I have
to ask you to call me Opal?
You make me feel
like an old woman.
Opal, then.
Lovely to see you again.
Some weather.
Yes, it's just awful.
It's blowing a gale.
Yes, it's quite a storm.
And colder than
a well-digger's wallet.
Yes, that's quite apt.
I wonder
if I could ask a favor.
I know you're probably as busyas an ant farm,
but do you think you could
change a light bulb for me?
The last time I tried,
I fell off the ladder
and I lay on my back like...
Like a helpless turtle?
No, like a half hour,
till the ambulance came.
Well, um, let me just get out
of these wet shoes
and I'll be right over.
Oh, great.
I'll make some tea
and cookies.
We always have
such lively conversations.
Yes, we're reviving a lost art.
Hey, Fras.
Some weather, huh?
Yes, it's raining.
I've just gone over that
with Mrs. Magrini.
Hey, come look at these pictures
from our engagement party.
Yeah, that camera you gave me
is terrific.
What, is that the camera
I gave you ten years ago?
I can't believe
you've never
used it before.
Shows you what you know.
Turns out half the shots
on this roll
were taken the night
you gave it to me.
Niles,
come and look
at these old pictures.
NILES:
Yes, and then we all looked
at the pictures.
I remember it as if
it were four hours ago.
I am coming to my point.
Martin, look at you--
sitting in your chair,
all sour and grumpy.
You must be drunk
in this picture, Niles.
You got your arm
around a floor lamp.
Oh, no, that's Mar
is in her Easter hat.
Why are you all
hunched over in this one?
You were looking
at my bum, weren't you?
Oh, heavens, no...
It's all right, Niles.
We're married now.
All right, yes.
I might once,
in a moment of weakness,
have permitted myself
a fleeting glance.
Or twice.
Many, many times.
It's all about the rear
with you, isn't it?
Darling, let's not...
Seriously, what color
are my eyes?
You're looking at it
again, aren't you?
No, I...
Boy, you look
at these pictures
.
and you really see
how far we've all come
Oh, I'll say.
You were such an old sourpuss,
and you were the Crypt Keeper.
And you, well...
God, you haven'?
changed a bit.
You're even wearing
the same jacket
that you wore
in this picture.
It's hardly the same.
I've had it relined.
I don't mind telling you
, Niles,
what happened next was
particularly galling.
I remember exactly
what happened,
and I haven't got a clue
what you're talking about.
Our lives
are so complete.
We really are lucky.
FRASIER:
Oh, please.
That's not
how it happened at all.
Our lives
are so complete.
We really are lucky.
Well, come on, Niles.
We should be heading off
to the baby show.
If we're lucky, we might get
a lead on a nanny.
Oh, well, there are ads
in the back of that
Seattle Weekly.
RONEE:
Just make sure you look
in the right section.
If she says that she's
got her own toys
and is willing to spank,
she may not be a nanny.
NILES:
Don't tell me
in your desperation
over being
the only Crane man
not to find love,
you picked up that paper
and did the unthinkable.
Tawny LaRue, I presume.
FRASIER:
I did no such thing, you nit.
And I am telling
this story.
Very slowly.
I'm beginning to think
you didn't do anything.
All right,
I'm getting to it.
As you recall, I promised to
change my neighbor's light bulb.
Oh!
Here we are.
I was just admiring
your bust.
Thank you.
Might look nice
a little higher.
It might look nice
a lot higher,
but heck, I'm 83.
Anyway, I can'
t thank you enough
for coming to my rescue.
Yes, it's lucky you ran into m
in the hall.
Oh, I knew that would be you
coming out of the elevator.
If there's one thing
I can count on,
it's old Frasier's routine,
unchanging
as Granddad's whiskers.
There's old Frasier
off to work.
coming home.
There's old Frasier
off to work.
There's old Frasier...
Yes, old Frasier
gets the idea.
That's why I gave you
my spare key.
I knew if there was
ever an emergency,
I could count on you.
Oh...
we should have our tea.
My date's picking me u
p in 20 minutes.
How marvelous.
You're still dating.
Well, I think an active
social life keeps you young.
So, what are you doing
this evening?
I thought I'd stay in
with a good book.
Ah, isn't that nice?
How you're so cozy
in your routine.
You're like
an old shoe, Frasier.
That's when I snapped.
You didn't.
You bludgeoned her
horribly with that bust!
No, you insane twit!
You're like
an old shoe, Frasier.
Now, come have some tea.
FRASIER:
I suddenly flashed
on my caller Babette.
Before I knew what I was doing,
I impulsively pocketed
something
that belonged to her.
I stole, Niles.
Like some craven thief.
.
And I've never felt more alive
(thunder crashing)
You can't imagine
the thrill I felt
as I sat there sipping
her inferior tea
and eating her
excellent cookies,
all the while...
fingering the stolen
object in my pocket.
And then, how
coolly I walked out,
scot-free,
the old bird none the wiser.
What's in there?
Some sort of
decorative medallion.
Well, it's pretty clear
what happened.
The depressing series
of events today
Ied you to conclude
that you're in a rut.
Your spontaneous
transgression generated
the excitement that you
so desperately wanted.
Any Caribbean-trained psych
student could tell me that.
Well, if you didn't
want my diagnosis,
why did you call me here?
I am plagued by guilt.
I have to return
this box before
it's discovered missing.
Why did you call me here?
I need your help, Niles.
I have her key.
I know she's out.
We can put this back
and be done with it.
But I don't want to.
I have excitement in my life.
Please!
I can't trust myself
to be alone.
I am caught in the grip
of this mania.
Who knows what
I might steal next?
You took a little box.
I hardly think you're gonna
run off on a crime spree.
Oh, really?
Thief!
That's right.
I took it, and I liked it.
Please. Please, Niles.
I don't want to get involved.
Fine!
I'll do it myself.
Here, hold
this for me.
What for?
Now your prints
are on it, too.
You have to help me.
(grunts)
Admit it, Niles.
It's intoxicating,
isn't it?
Can't you feel a tingle
running down your spine?
In a minute it's
going to be running
down my inseam.
Hurry up.
I've become a danger junkie.
A cunning cat burglar
with nerves of steel.
(rattling)
(shrieks)
Hide. Hide! Here, here.
Take this box.
No, no, you've
got a pocket.
Put it...
All right, everybody.
Put down your gifts.
Give me your coats and
I'll put them in the bedroom.
(phone rings)
Hello?
Thank you.
Okay, that was the doorman.
Aunt Opal is on her way up.
Everyone find a place to hide.
All right,
quiet, everybody.
I hear them.
ALL:
Surprise!
OPAL:
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, you! Oh!
Frasier?
Who are you?
I'm Dr. Frasier Crane,
the next-door neighbor,
and this is
my brother Niles.
We just want to say
Happy birthday, Opal.
Thank you.
Did someone invite you?
Uh, well, news
of this birthday
has been just buzzing
through the building.
We wouldn't miss an opportunity
to honor this
wonderful lady.
But how'd you get in here?
We slipped in as
the door was closing.
I could swear...
Stop grilling them,
please, Roland.
He thinks he has
to grill everyone
.
just because
he's a district attorney
Now, what would
you like to drink?
Champagne.
Well, we really
can't stay.
Oh, you can stay a few minutes.
You don't want
to hurt my feelings.
Let me
take your coat.
Oh, my coat,
no, I'd really
rather you...
Uh... Okay.
Oh, my God.
What? What?!
You're
Dr. Frasier Crane.
Here, take this, Roland.
I love your show.
be
Oh...
It's going to
so exciting to have
a celebrity here
when we take Aunt Opal'?
picture with her medal.
Medal?
She won the bronze
at the 1 936
Berlin Olympics.
So what's it like
being a huge radio star?
Frasier...
Yes, yes,
in a minute, Niles.
Actually, I don't really
think of myself
as a star,
so much as a healer.
The important thing
is to listen.
Frasier.
Not now, Niles.
Frasier, they're
going to take
her picture
with her medal.
Yes, I heard that.
Oh, dear.
Uh, excuse me
just a moment.
You've got to get that
medal out of your coat.
Why don't you get it?
I'm a celebrity.
They're watching
my every move. Go on.
Aunt Opal, tell Dr.
Crane the story
about how you refused
to shake Hitler's hand
when he gave
you that medal.
It looked sweaty,
that's all.
Who are you?
It's just a dream.
Then why aren't
you Harry Truman?
Where's my cake?
I'm ready
for the cake.
No, not until we take
the family picture, Mother.
I got it.
Then let's take
the darned picture.
Roland, get my medal down.
Where is it?
Same place it
always is,
unless it's grown legs
like a tadpole and hopped away.
We have got to get
that medal up there.
We?
You're right.
Bad plan. You've got
to get it up there.
All right, top shelf,
right of the sconce.
You know, before
we take the picture,
I have a little story
I'd like to tell
that just may rival
that Hitler tale.
(laughing)
The place...
was right here.
The time was
this afternoon.
Opal had just set out
a lovely service of tea
and a plate of sweets.
I remember there were three
cookies sitting on the plate
and I reached
for the left one.
Not the center one,
the left one, and...
Just at
the same moment,
Opal reached for
the very same cookie.
Oh, what did you
say, Opal?
It was priceless.
"
.
I said, 'you take it
Right off the
top of her head.
What are you doing?
I can tell from the panic
in my brother's voice
that he, he must
have seen a spider.
You see, he has a,
a crippling fear
of spiders and it
sent him up the ladder.
Yes. I hate spiders.
I don't see a spider.
Come back down.
No!
Why not?
Because he also has
a crippling fear of heights
and this may be
just the breakthrough
we've been looking for.
Higher, Niles.
Conquer your fear.
Please, everyone,
I'm going to have
to ask you to turn around,
as his fear
of crowds has set in.
Crowds, too?
Yes. You are looking
at that rarest of beasts--
the arachno-acro-agoraphobe.
Please, avert your eyes.
.
Oh. Oh
This is the most
difficult part of the process.
I am using a
technique known
as behavioral
exposure therapy.
Climb higher, Niles.
Ever higher.
Conquer your fear.
Wow. Frasier
Crane in action.
No, please.
No peeking.
You don't want
to cause a setback.
Everybody freeze!
This is the moment
of truth.
I haven't done this
since my days in med school.
Hurrah!
He's done it!
He's conquered all three!
What are you doing?
Well, you as an athlete
should know the...
the time-honored tradition
of hoisting the victor
on one's shoulders.
They never did that to me.
Well, you finished third,
didn't you?
Now, if
you'll excuse me,
I've got to journal all this
while it's still fresh.
Good night, everyone.
Oh.
Good Lord, I
should have dipped.
go.
Yes, there we
Ooh!
So sorry.
Oh, hey, Dad.
I didn't know
you guys were here.
Where's Ronee?
Oh, she's in bed waiting for me.
Hey, know what?
She can't see a thing
without her contacts.
Why don't we play
a little joke on her?
You tiptoe in...
No, Dad, I'll pass.
Still looking at those
old pictures, huh?
Yeah.
It's funny, isn't it?
What?
How suddenly
your whole life can change.
p
I never would have dreamed
back then that I'd end u
getting married again,
at my age,
and to someone
so young and full of pep.
I'm very happy
for you and Ronee.
That's the way it is.
Just when you think
that you're in a rut
and nothing exciting will ever
happen to you again...
Pow. That's when it does.
Maybe you're right.
I know I'm right.
Good night, Fras.
Good night, Dad.
You know, you could put on
my robe and a little bit
of my Aqua Velva.
Good night, Dad.