Hey, Daph. Hello, Martin.
What's that?
Oh, it's Frasier and
Niles's old playpen.
Got it out of storage for you.
Looks a bit rickety.
Nah, it just needs a
little weight to balance it.
Put a baby in there, and it'll be fine.
(both gasping)
You're not putting my
baby in that deathtrap,
and by the way, did you move your gun
out to storage, like you promised?
I'm getting to it.
What? That gun is
still around? Oh, geez.
Dad, two years ago, I
demanded you get rid of it.
You said you did.
Don't tell me it's still in your closet.
No. It's in a shoe box under my bed.
Well, I don't want it
he re in my apartment.
All right, all right,
it'll go into storage today,
but I don't know what we'll
do if a burglar breaks in.
You could lure him into that playpen.
You slept awfully late. Mm, yeah,
oh, well, I was having
the most distressing dream.
I was climbing up a volcano
that was spewing ice instead of lava.
Ice volcano. Wonder
what that could mean.
Oh, what's this?
Hello, it's Lilith.
Oh, well... Ah, okay.
We're supposed to be having breakfast,
but you're not here,
and, as I don't know if you're tardy
or have been in a terrible accident,
I am unable to commit to an
appropriate emotional response.
Please call me. Thank you.
Oh, damn, I completely forgot.
Lilith is in town for
a one-day conference.
Now I'll have to
canceI lunch to see her.
Can't you catch her on the next trip?
No, no, she'll only be hurt,
and of course, she'll...
she'll dredge it up
the next time she needs
an emotional trump card.
Ooh! Maybe I can trick her
into canceling lunch on me.
Instead of playing games, why
don't you just talk to her ? .
We tried talking when we were married.
We were better at games.
Hello, Lilith. It's
Frasier. Gosh, I'm so sorry.
I was on my way to breakfast, and, uh...
I-I swerved to avoid
hitting a Pomeranian,
and I-I ran up on the
curb and blew a tire.
All right, well, maybe if
you come by here for lunch.
(gasps) She won't, she won 't.
Okay, then.
All right, see you
here around 1 :00. Okay.
Damn.
She came to play.
Hey. Hello.
Hey, Niles. Hey, Dad.
Hey, do you want to join us for lunch?
We're trying a new Indonesian place
that's famous for its Besengek Daging.
Well, wish I could,
but I promised Frasier
I'd stay here till he
got back from the dentist.
Oh, well, we'll keep you company.
Why'd he need you to hang around?
He's making lunch for Lilith.
And off we go.
(doorbell rings)
Too late.
Shouldn't you get the door?
You're closer.
I don't live here.
Doesn't matter. You're family.
So is Daphne... Oh, no, you don't.
LILITH: Maybe if you slid me a key,
I could let myself in.
Hey, Lilith!
Sorry for the holdup, but, uh,
Frasier should be back
from the dentist any minute.
Oh, all right.
That'll give us a chance to visit.
Daphne, Niles, congratulations
on the successful commingling
of your genetic material.
Thank you.
Do you know the sex?
Do we? That's how we got pregnant.
Thank you. No, we're-we're...
we're going to let it be a surprise.
Oh, okay. Please sit down.
Thank you.
Well, if I was to
guess the gender--
and I'm usually right
about half the time...
I'm being humorous, of course.
(laughs)
I would say it's a boy.
Oh. What makes you say that?
Well, it's highly unscientific,
but the proverbial old wives
would cite the spreading of your nose,
the unevenness of your breasts,
and the coarse black hair on your legs.
Interesting.
Is that the shoe box
from under your bed, then?
(cell phone ringing)
Excuse me.
Hello?
Yes, Frasier.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
Hear what?
He's still coming, isn't he?
Yes, all right, all right.
I'll meet you then. Bye.
Frasier can't make it.
Oh...
well, if you still want lunch,
I've got leftover meat loaf
that's today or never.
Thank you, but I'll get
something at the conference.
Ahh...
There's a bulimia talk today
and I'll wager that's one lecture hall
with a snack machine outside.
Lovely to see you.
Bye-bye.
Did you hear what she said about me?
Yes.
That I've got a flat nose,
uneven boobs and bristly legs?
I mean, are they really that bad?
Not bad.
Maybe a little cock-eyed,
but with a heavy sweater...
I was talking about my legs.
Oh, forget about lunch.
I'm just going to make a sandwich.
Oh, no, hey... what about me?
Oh, have a banana.
(gunshot)
DAPHNE: My God!
What was that?
I think the banana went off.
You knocked my gun on the floor.
Is everyone all right?
Daphne, are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine. Dad, you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine. I don't understand this.
I thought the safety was on.
Oh, my God, it blew a hole
through Frasier's chair.
(Martin gasping)
And it shot the head off the statue.
Look what it did to the fireplace.
MARTIN: Oh, no, Frasier's
going to kill me.
This is why I've been telling you
to put the bloody thing in storage.
Niles was the one who
knocked it off the table.
Well, accidentally, because
I had a banana thrown at me!
To you, not at you.
And you should know
how to catch a banana!
I am not having this argument again!
If Frasier sees this,
I'll never hear the end of it.
You guys have to help me fix
things up before he gets home.
Forget it, old man. You're on your own.
If he kicks me out over
this, I'm moving in with you.
All right, what's the plan? .
You start calling upholsterers.
Niles, get me some Spackle.
I'll see if I can Crazy Glue
the head back on that thing.
Dad, Dad... what's Spackle?
Anyway, long story short,
" . six months in he says
I'm "too tightly wound
Me.
Wow, I don't know what to tell you, Lil.
Lilith. My name is Lilith.
(pager vibrating)
Oh, it's my beeper.
Oh, darn, they need me
back at the conference.
Okay, but listen, we all
have bad dating experiences,
so don't give up.
Get out there, have fun, meet people.
You're right.
Thank you, Nancy.
You're a real pal.
And the best survivor guilt
and phantom limb expert in the game.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Roz... Roz?
Oh, hi, Lilith. What
are you doing in town?
Well, I'm here for a conference
and was supposed to meet
Frasier here for coffee,
but I'm afraid I have to leave.
Will you tell him I'll call him later?
Sure, no problem.
Thank you. Bye-bye.
Can I have change for the meter?
Only if you buy something.
I don't have time--
the meter maid's coming.
Sorry, can't do it.
Well, someone doesn't
want his tip very much.
You haven't ordered anything.
I meant the tip I gave you yesterday.
Oh, hi, Roz. Hey, Frasier.
Oh, um, Lilith had to leave.
Oh, damn! Again?
Can I help you?
Yes... Yes, I'd like.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry
. Please, go ahead.
No. that's all right. You go.
No, I insist--
after you.
We'll go together.
What're you having?
All right-- a
macchiato for here.
One macchiato for here
and a Mocha Valencia to go, please.
Macchiato man.
Don't meet many of those.
No, no...
We're a... a rare breed.
Spartan... rugged...
You like a dusting of
nutmeg on that, right?
Just a sprinkle.
So, is this your first time here?
Yeah. I'm in town on business.
First time in Seattle.
That entitles you to a
complimentary beverage.
These are on me.
Thank you.
Tell me, is there a Mrs. Macchiato?
(chuckles) : No.
This may sound a little crazy,
but would you be interested
in having a drink later
with a friend of mine?
I think you might really hit it off.
Well, it sounds intriguing.
I'm late for a meeting,
but if you're game,
Iet's just say 7:00
at the Marina Tavern.
And if you change your
mind, here's my number.
All right, then.
Roz, have you ever been set
up on a date with someone
whose name you didn't know? .
Oh, please, I've woken up with dates
now. whose names I didn't k
Cappuccino, please.
What's going on?
Well, I just met this woman
who's in town on business.
She asked me to join a friend of hers
for a drink at the Marina Tavern.
Oh... well, you know there is no friend.
The woman you met is
the woman you're meeting.
Oh, that's what I thought.
I wonder why she
wouldn't give me her name?
Well, when you're in tow n on business
and you hook up with a stranger,
no names is standard procedure.
I'm not sure that's something
you want to admit knowing, Roz.
I only know it from reading
Erica Jong novels, okay?
I'm not sure that's something
you want to admit, either.
(door opening)
I've got the Spackle.
Good, good-- we'll
fill in the crack,
then my faux finisher
can match the stone.
Fabrizio is on his way
here to re-upholster.
Dad, how are you doing?
Great.
This glue should hold it just fine.
Your guys better get over here soon.
Frasier's meeting Lilith
after work at the cafe,
which only gives us...
FRASIER: Oh, hello, Mrs. Richman.
(whispering): Shh! Frasier!
Ahh!
Hello, what's going on?
Oh, just admiring the sunset.
I think it looks best over here,
but Niles thinks it
looks better over there.
FRASIER: Oh, really?
Oh, Niles,
have you changed your
mind about my new statue?
Yesterday you said it
was sterile and unmoving.
Oh, it's moving now.
Well, I'd love to stay
and gloat, but I have
a very intriguing date
for which I must get ready.
Well, good luck with
that. Thank you, Dad.
Oh, what's this?
LILITH: Frasier, I'm
just leaving the cafe.
Sorry I missed you.
Anyway, if you're available for a drink,
I'm staying at the Harbor View .
Call me.
Oh, dear... damn!
I've got an exciting mystery date
and who should rear her head
at the last minute but Lilith.
MARTIN: Well, you know,
if you leave right away,
you'd probably have time
for a quick drink with Lilith
and still make for your date.
Good thinking, Dad.
I could dispense with the pleasantries
and be on my way.
Help me, help me. The
head is stuck to my hand.
(yelling)
FRASIER: On second thought...
maybe I should invite Lilith here
so that I can have
more time to get ready.
ALL: No!
She's already been here once.
You should go to her.
You're quite right,
but, then, should I change
or am I fine the way I am?
Fine. Oh, hubba-hubba.
Well, then, I'll just see you all later.
Dad, you're right.
It's a much, much
different sunset from here.
(flatly): Yes, of course
I'm excited, Nancy.
Can't you hear it in
the timbre of my voice?
Yes, well, I'm afraid I
might a little bit late.
I'm still waiting for my ex-husband.
(knocking) Oh, there he is.
I'll get through this as
quickly as I possibly can.
Yes, all right. Bye.
Hi, Lilith.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Traffic was a bear.
It's good to see you.
Likewise.
Anyway, I'm sorry about
all the missed connections today,
but at least we have a chance
to catch up, however briefly.
Yes, well, sometimes with old friends
five minutes is enough.
Ha.
One minute.
So, care for a drink?
Not if I'm keeping you from something.
Well, actually, I do
have a date this evening.
Oh, really?
Yes. A colleague of mine fixed me up.
I'm sorry for dragging you over here
when I have so little time to give you.
Actually, I'm running
late for a date myself.
I see.
Well, why don 't you run along?
I wouldn't want you
to keep Niles waiting.
(chuckles)
No. It is
with a woman--
a very vibrant, sexy woman.
Ah. Good for you.
Listen, if you're running late
and you need to cancel our drink...
No, no, no, I've canceled
on you once already today.
Well, I canceled on you twice.
That would make us even.
That's why we're having the drink.
Ah.
Unless you're worried
that your sexy date
will leave if you' re five minutes late.
Oh, no, not at all.
My absence will only make
her heart grow fonder.
You mind if I use the bathroom?
Certainly. Thank you.
Please don't leave. Please don't leave.
Please don't leave.
Hello.
Miss Mocha Valencia.
Yes, Macchiatto man here.
Uh, listen, I'm glad I caught you.
Hi. Where are you?
Uh, well...
something's come up, and
I'm afraid I have to...
Wait, hang on. I have another call.
Fine.
Hello.
Nancy, it's Lilith again.
Listen, this thing with my ex-husband
is taking a lot longer than I expected,
but I will be there, I promise you.
Uh-oh.
What do you mean "uh-oh"
I'm on the other line
with your date right now.
I think he wants to cancel.
Before he' s even met me?
Tell him I canceled on him first.
Okay.
I'm really sorry about this.
Hi. So I'm afraid tonight's off.
Off?
Yeah, that was my friend.
She had second thoughts.
Oh, really?
Well, please tell your "friend"
that I wasn't exactly bowled over
by her first thoughts.
I don't even know what that means.
So what would you say to that drink?
I'd say, don't get too
comfortable in that glass.
(chuckles)
Well, this is nice.
Yes, very.
Freddy tells me he dissected a frog.
Yes, and a fetal pig.
Of course, I made him
do his homework first.
Lilith, you seem preoccupied.
Is this about your blind date tonight?
You could say that.
Well, for what it's worth,
whoever this guy is...
he'll feel awfully lucky when
you walk through the door.
Thank you, Frasier,
but I really shouldn't be
keeping you from your date.
Oh, right.
Well, I guess I should be going, yes.
Although, you know, you
are here for just one night.
Perhaps I could call and
push things back a bit?
Maybe I could delay mine as well.
Great.
All right.
What excuse are you going to use?
Oh, I'll just trot
out my stand-by--
it works every time.
Simply say that I swerved
to avoid hitting a Chihuahua,
ran up on a curb and blew a tire.
This morning you said
it was a Pomeranian.
Well, this morning it was.
FRASIER: So I'm in the
middle of this date from hell,
when Kenny walks in with his cousin,
whom I'd passed on sight unseen.
Turns out she's not only gorgeous,
but her name is actually Miss Wright.
Okay, you win. Mm-hmm.
Say, are there any more
kettle chips in the mini bar?
No. We can have either
Gummi Bears or cashews,
both. but I'm afraid we can't afford
(door slams)
MAN: Erin, would you stop?
I don't even know what I did.
ERIN: Why do you always say
that like you think it will help?
Because when I guess, you get angrier!
Boy, that takes you back, doesn't it?
MAN: What, did I forget
to notice your hair?
That's not why I'm mad.
I'm just going to ask them to be quiet.
MAN: I can't talk to you
when you're like this.
I'm going out.
ERIN: Sean, what are you doing?
Oh, uh... Sorry.
That's not the hall.
Yes, uh...
It's all right.
You see, we overheard your quarrel,
and in the interest of
keeping the peace and quiet,
maybe we could offer some assistance.
It's okay, we can handle it ourselves.
Oh, can you, Sean?
You don't even know what you did.
Please, won't you come in?
We are psychiatrists.
There's no need to be afraid.
We are here to help.
So, what, you're like caped
crusaders for mental health?
No, not caped.
Please, come and sit down.
All right then.
What seems to be the problem?
Uh...
When we were at dinner,
he was checking out another woman.
And you feel threatened by this?
Shouldn't I? Well, maybe.
Shot in the dark here:
your parents are divorced; Dad left Mom.
Yeah. How'd you know?
It's classic transference.
Because your father and mother split up,
you overreact whenever
you perceive a threat
to your current relationship.
And, you, you care about this woman?
Absolutely.
Then keep your eye s in your head.
It bugs her and it's bad form.
And if he should fail at this,
which he will,
he's a man--
it does not mean he's
going to leave you.
you. Or that I don't love
Because I do.
I know.
I love you, too.
Wow, you guys are good.
ERIN: Yeah, that was amazing.
So, do you two just have
the best marriage ever?
Actually...
Yes... we do.
Well, uh... thank you.
It was really nice meeting you.
Likewise, likewise.
You seem like an awfully
nice young couple,
and I'm sure you'll
understand if I lock the door.
Good night.
Well done, Dr. Crane.
Back at you, Dr. Sternin.
I'd suggest that we try a high five
but I recall we attempted that once
after a bridge victory and
you scratched my cornea.
Well, I guess we shouldn't kee
our dates waiting any longer.
Right.
Good luck on your romantic
adventure this evening, Lilith.
Don't you
worry--
you're going to knock his socks off.
Frasier...
I don't have a date
anymore. He canceled.
You're kidding.
No. I was too proud to admit it to you.
How pathetic is that?
Well, there's no need to
beat yourself up about it.
Come on. A fake phone
call to "buy time"?
It's understandable.
Just a face-saving
gesture in the light of...
Oh, my God, your date
canceled on you, too.
All right, yes.
It's a banner day for both of us.
All this lying has certainly
worked up my appetite.
You want to get room service?
That might be nice.
Okay.
Certainly beats sitting alone
wondering what we missed
out on this evening, hmm?
SEAN: Oh, yes! Oh, yes!
(loud erotic moaning)
Frasier?
Hmm? Hmm.
Oh, gosh, I'm sorry.
I must have dozed off during the movie.
Me, too.
What time is it?
Uh... it's almost 6:00.
6:00?
I have a 7:30 flight.
Well, I'll just get out of your hair.
Listen, Lilith, dinner
was lovely last night.
I had a great time.
Yes. Well, much better
than those blind dates
could have possibly been.
Absolutely.
Well, listen, have a
safe trip and all that,
and give Freddy a hug for me.
I will. All right.
You know, it's funny... What?
Well, I was just thinking
that if we had never met,
we're exactly the kind of peopIe
that somebody might
set up on a blind date.
You always were one
for droll hypotheticals.
Yes. It's amusing to consider, though.
What would we think of each other
if we were just meeting
now for the first time?
But if we hadn't met,
we'd be different people now.
Ah, true.
But then that raises
many other questions.
I mean, what sort of man would
the non-Lilith Frasier be?
What sort of woman...?
Did I mention I have a plane to catch?
Of course.
But you're right.
It was a lovely evening.
We do have our baggage, don't we?
But then sometimes that's what
makes the trip so interesting.
With one hand, the
past moves us forward,
and with the other, it holds us back.
Good-bye, Lilith.
Good-bye, Frasier.
(door closes)