Oh, Dr. Crane
My God, after all our years together
all the good times, all the bad times
can't loan me a meager four
thousand dollars?
You must appreciate how hard it is
for me to approach you about this.
I thought I meant more
to you than this, but apparently I don't.
And they call themselves
"the friendly bank!"
What do you need to borrow money for?
I saw the most exquisite
Biedermeier footstool.
For four thousand bucks?
Niles, your mother and I didn't
pay that much for our first house.
I know, dad.
I lived there.
Well, I keep telling you,
you don't have Maris's money tothrow around anymore.
You're going to have to start
cutting back a little.
I have cut back.
Last month I told my masseur
I could only see him once a week.
Oh, I remember that scene
in "Grapes Of Wrath"
when Ma Joad did that.
You know, if you need to save a bit,
you should do what I do
and cut out coupons.
Coupons.
Well, what a wonderful way to economize.
Well, I could clip them and give them
to my personal shopper.
Oh, Niles, good morning.
Hey.
Daphne, has Bebe Glazer called back yet?
'Fraid not.
You're still consorting with that barracuda?
Well, a barracuda is what
you want in an agent, Niles.
It's just that the station's been sold,
I was hoping she might have some
scuttlebutt on the new owner.
I must admit she's rather hard
to get a hold of these days
Oh, really?  I thought one just
drew a pentagram on the floor
and chanted "I summon thee" three times.
Hello, Roz.
Hey.
What have you got on the new owner?
Oh, plenty.
Yeah?
Well, there's a little snapshot
of his psyche right there.
He's an eighty-five year-old Texan.
Practically no formal education but he went from
errand boy at a radio station to owning his own
media empire worth six hundred million.
This is great, I don't even know
what "Renuzit" is, but it's
twenty cents off and I want it.
You're clipping coupons?
I'm economizing.
Oh well it's about time, you spend
money like a drunken sailor.
She said authoritatively.
Excuse me, could we get back
to the subject at hand, please?
What are you so antsy about?
Dad, Wilford S. Boone-
Big Willy.
Please, Roz, I just can't say that yet, alright?
Wilford S. Boone owns thirty radio
stations across the country.
If he likes you he's been known
to syndicate your show nationwide.
So, I'm trying to find out
if we have anything in common
an angle, if you will.
So what are his interests, Roz?
Well, it's all in there.
He likes whittling, rodeos,
the novels of Zane Grey...
Gee, Fras.  It's like you two were separated at birth.
He also owns a 5,000 acre cattle ranch and the world's
largest collection of antique six-shooters.
Oh dear God, I'm sucking up to Yosemite Sam!
I think if we really want to impress Big Willy
we should think of some Western
theme to do for the show today.
Great idea, Roz.
Why don't we just start the
show off with a segment on
how to get in touch with your inner young'un.
What a fascinating theory!  Do go on.
What's going on?
Oh, this is great.
I told Gil the new station owner is a Greek tycoon.
He fell for that?
Hook, line, and souvlaki!
You can keep your overripe
Camembert and malodorous Stilton,
they can't compare with the
salty insouciance of Greece's
glorious Feta.
It's not just for shepherds anymore!
This is Gil Chesterton saying Bon Appetite,
or as we say in Athens, Kali Orexi!
Oh Gil, you've been had.
The new station owner isn't Greek, he's from Texas.
You are so easy!
Well, I hope you're happy!
I've just given four stars to a
restaurant called "A Taste Of Greece."
Which, trust me, is no misnomer.
Well that's what you deserve,
trying to suck up to some senile old coot!
Hell, he probably can't eat anything
but strained peas and farina!
Uh, Mr Boone?
Yeah, that's right.
Pleasure to see you.
I'm Dr. Frasier Crane.
This is Roz Doyle, Gil Chesterton and...
I'm Skippy the lunch boy.
So, uh, that's two strained peas
and a farina for the big guy.
Oh, uh, Skippy?  Change my order!
I've got a sudden hankering
for baby-back ribs and corn bread.
Oh, I've been looking for you Dr. Crane.
I have a little problem and
they told me you're just the fella
who could fix it.
Oh, I hope I'm not imposing.
Oh, no, don't be silly, Mr. Boone.
Well, actually I prefer "Big Willy."
Don't be silly, Big Willy.
You see, I'm engaged to be married.
Oh, congratulations.
Well, sweet young thing.
Just nuts about me.
Problem is, she smokes.
Oh lord, that is a very bad habit.
Oh, it's a vile habit!
Would have destroyed my affection for her if,
well she didn't possess
certain... compensating gifts.
Anyway, as a favour to me, could you help her?
Well, I'll certainly try.
Just keep in mind, though, addiction
is fraught with many complex issues.
Length of habit, motivation...
Forgive me, sometimes I don't
express myself too clearly.
When I say, "could you help her," what I meant to say was
HELP HER!
Consider it done.
Much obliged.
She'll be in touch.
That's me, Dr. Frasier Crane, bimbo wrangler.
Frasier, stop it!
This is a golden opportunity!
You makethis little tootsie quit
smoking and we're halfway to syndication.
Did someone just say the word "syndication,"
or do I just hear it every time
I lay eyes on my favorite client?
Oh, Bebe.
Is something wrong, dear?
Well, yes.
We just met Big Willy...
Oh, he thinks I'm some sort of a magician.
He wants me to play therapist to his little fiance?
No doubt some gold-digging piranha
so devoid of scruples that
she's willing to rob the coffin and just...
Oh, dear God!
Isn't it wonderful?
We met last month and it was love at first sight.
First sight of what -
his bankbook and a cardiogram?
Two minutes.
I'm hurt that she can even joke
about such a thing.
I love that dear sweet old man
with every fibre of my being.
I'm sure you do.
I'm afraid there won't even be a wedding if you can't
get rid of that rotten habit, and
he's just ordered me to see that you do!
God, you'd think a touch of
emphysema were the end of the world!
What's that in your hand, woman?
Sorry, pudd'n.  Bebe slipped.
Just that all-important last puff.
Well, see that it is!
Well, Dr. Crane, I'm heading
out of town for three days.
When I get back on Sunday, I expect
my little gal here to be smoke-free by then.
In... three days?
Now, you do whatever it takes to help her, doc!  Drugs,
straightjackets, electroshock...
You see how he dotes on me.
Excellent progress, Bebe!
You've really dived into the emotional void
that is the route of your addiction.
Your fear of abandonment, your fear
that those you trust will
suddenly turn their backs when you expect them to...
Excuse me.
My God, it all seems so clear now.
You're a miracle worker.
If I had a dime for every time... well...
Niles!
Hello Frasier, I noticed you
were out of capers the other
night, so I got you this.
Thank you Niles, but why so many?
I just discovered a place called
"Price Buster's Warehouse."
You have to buy in bulk, but the
savings are extraordinary
and they have a huge selection.
I found french fries and french doors in the same aisle.
Well, the next time you go back
be sure to buy me a thousand
swordfish so I can use these up!
You laugh, but I could do it like that.
So, how goes the great smoke-out?
Until today, I had no idea what
a brilliant therapist your brother is.
He has tunneled his way into the very depths of my psyche.
Well, let's hope he sent a canary down first.
Well, I'll be running along.
I'll see you at ten tomorrow.
In the mean time, it's exercise,
lots of fresh spring water
and nicotine gum for cravings.
That's my girl.
Oh, Bebe, you know I'm writing
a paper on addiction and I'd
love to ask you some questions -
unless there's some reason you're eager to be off?
Me?  No.  No, not at all.
Well, I just need to discuss
a personal matter with Frasier first.
Of course, I'll give you some privacy.
It's time for my water anyway.
Yes, Niles?
Let her out that door,
she'll smoke half a pack before the
elevator hits the lobby.
How can you know that?
You hardly spoke to her.
Well, obviously you didn't
see the crazed, cunning glint in her eyes.
She always looks like that, she's an agent.
I know about addiction.
It's the exact same look Maris
used to get during the cough syrup years.
The only way to deal with it is to lock her up,
take her money, and watch her like
a hawk until it's out of her system.
That means she would have
to stay here for the weekend.
Who's staying all weekend?
Bebe Glazer.
Here?
What does she have to stay here for?
She's trying to quit smoking.
Oh great, that means she'll be extra lovable.
Not to worry dad, there is no reason
she has to stay for the weekend.
Bebe and I made a real breakthrough today.
If you don't believe me, just come on into the kitchen
and you'll see that I'm right.
I'm sorry I can't stay and help
you with your paper, Niles,
wedding preperations and all.
But I'll remember those helpful hints.
It's exercise, gum, and lots of water.
Water should come in handy for
putting out those pesky purse fires.
All right Niles, secure the door!
Bebe, you are not going anywhere,
you're staying for the weekend.
Now give me that purse.
All right.
Let me remove one very precious momento.
Very well.
Oh, stop it!
More!
What again?
That's her third serving.
Now, now Dad, it's flattering to
Daphne that Bebe finds her food so tasty.
I'm orally fixated.
I could eat a half-stunned wharf
rat if you put some gravy on it!
I'll bear that in mind come breakfast time.
No, please, please.
Let's all try to remain supportive of Bebe.
I think she's really doing rather well.
So, I hear your fiancee is well to do?
Very.
You gonna eat that fat?
Well, marrying money can have it's perils.
Ten or fifteen years down the line,
after you've adapted to a lifestyle
now totally beyond your means,
you can find yourself cast
aside a hollow husk, penniless and crushed.
Niles, Big Willy's eighty-five,
he's on his third pacemaker.
Ah.
Mazel tov!
Just out of curiosity, has
this guy ever seen you eat?
After dinner is the time I need a cigarette most.
As long as I don't stop eating, I'll be fine.
Well, this is very good, Bebe.
You're already identifying those
moments that trigger your worst cravings.
Yeah, yeah!
No, really.  Perhaps it would help
to know that you're not alone.
Dad is an ex-smoker.
Dad, can you tell us about
those moments you crave a cigarette most?
Ah, when I had insomnia.
I'd get up, pour a water glass
full of Bourbon, light a cigarette -
next thing you know, I couldn't keep my eyes open.
Nothing relaxes you like a cigarette.
Of course, gives you a hell of
a headache in the morning.
Well, I smoked for years but I never became addicted.
To this day, I can buy a pack, have a cig or two, toss
them in a drawer and not crave another for months.
You know there's a word for people who can do that.
What is it?  Oh, yes -
bitch!
There's no need to be insulting
just because you're wrestling
with an unhealthy and disgusting habit.
It isn't disgusting,
it's wonderful!
Oh now, Bebe, tell me.
What is so wonderful about smoking?
Everything.
I like the way a fresh firm pack feels in my hand.
I like peeling away that little piece of cellophane
and seeing it twinkle in the light.
I like coaxing that first sweet
cylinder out of its hiding place
and bringing it slowly up to my lips.
Striking a match, watching
it burst into  a perfect little flame
and knowing that soon that flame will be inside me.
I love the first puff, pulling it into my lungs.
Little fingers of smoking filling me, caressing me,
feeling that warmth penetrate deeper and deeper,
until I think I'm going to burst!
Then - whoosh! - watching it flow
out of me in a lovely, sinuous cloud,
no two ever quite the same.
More potatoes, anyone?
You're up early, Miss Moon.
Oh!  God, you startled me!
Ever since your little speech
about smoking, I haven't been
able to think about anything else.
Please, don't mention this to Dr. Crane.
Silence has its price, dear.
And I think we both know what that is.
Forget it!
You can't make me give you one of these.
Oh... can't I?!
You open up right now!
All right, missy, here's the drill!
You drop those cigarettes, I'll open the door,
you kick 'em over to me, capisce?
No!
Oh, is it cold outside?
All right, you asked for it!
No!  No!  Please, I beg you.
Oh, oh no.  My fingers are getting weak.
Oh, oh, I'm losing my grip.
Stop, please!  I'll give you
anything you want.  I'll...
I'll make you a star!
What the hell's going on out here?
Daphne was smoking!
She made me!
Daphne, give me those.
Oh, look at me!
I'm all damp and chilled to the bone.
I'll get you a towel.
My God, it's five-thirty in the morning!
Dad!
I couldn't sleep.
Have you people all lost your minds?
Alright, now listen, get
back to bed, every one of you!
All right, all right...
Thank god you came in when you did!
She was praying on my weakness.
Who knows what I might have done, probably...
THIS!
Oh, get her!  Stop that woman!
Bebe, you will not be allowed to
smoke a cigarette in this house!
No, no, don't even think about it!
All right, just give me those!
All right now, that's it!
Back to bed!
Oh my God, you're insane, woman!
That's it, no more house guests.
Get off me, you brute!
Hand them over!
Never!
That'll be the neighbours!
Hello?  Oh, hello!
One moment, please.
It's Big Willy!
Big Willy, hello!
No, no, it's not too early, everybody's up!
Well, you know, there have
been a few minor setbacks, but
I'm keeping on top of her, yeah.
Oh yeah, I know she'd love to say hi, hang on.
Hello, pudd'n.  I'm fine, and you?
Oh, nothing's too much trouble
for you daddy.  Bye now!
Yes, sir?  Oh, oh, really?
No, no, I'm very flattered.
Yes, of course, I'd love to,
I'll talk to you this evening.
Bye-bye.
Thank you, Daphne.
All right, now listen up!
He thinks I'm very gifted.
Mmm.
He thinks I'm wasting my talents in just one city!
My God, woman, he wants to take
me national, don't you get it?
Unless YOU ruin it for me!
Oh my God, sorry.
Here, take 'em.
I don't know what came over me.
Well, don't be too hard on yourself, Bebe.
After all, addiction to Nicotine
is a very, very difficult... hey,
wait a minute.  This pack is half-empty!
For God's sake... I don't care anymore.
You know, I can't help you, nobody can.
You want to ruin it for both of us?
Here,
go ahead, knock yourself out.
I only wish I could be there when it happens.
When what happens?
When you see that newspaper headline:
"Big Willy Boone, Millionaire, Dead."
Oh, how I wish I could be there
when you watch the funeral on the news.
Watch the casket being slipped into the ground.
Only, you won't be watching that.
No, no, you'll be watching...
the widow Boone.  Tiffany, perhaps.
Oh no, better yet, "Kelli" - with an "I"!
Stop it!
You'll picture her wearing YOUR jewels,
sailing in YOUR yachts, sleeping with YOUR gigolos -
but, oh, you won't be sad, no, no, no!
Because you'll have your cigarette.
Yeah!  Clutched in your
nicotine-stained teeth, smoke
whirling about your once-pretty,
now creased, leathery,
smoke-ravaged...
Enough!
God!
You are one hell of a therapist.
Hey, you back from the wedding already?
No.
There was no wedding.
No wedding, no syndication deal...
What's she doing here?
No money, no fame...
Well, you might say things hit a bit of a snag.
No beach house, no pool boys...
Oh will you get a grip, Roz?!
Well, what went wrong?
Well, they were halfway down the aisle -
Big Willy beaming proudly, Bebe radiant,
supporting Big Willy on her arm -
when suddenly he clutched his heart,
and his head slumped against Bebe's shoulder.
Of course we were all concerned
at first, but then suddenly
it seemed like he was all right
because they kept moving on down the aisle.
But if you looked carefully, you could see
Bebe's little biceps bulging through her wedding gown,
and I swear I noticed daylight
between Big Willy's dress boots and the carpet.
Well, once they got up to the
minister the jig was pretty well up,
despite Bebe's valiant attempts
to animate his features by
twisting the loose skin at the back of his neck.
You know, I've never seen a woman more crushed.
Well, if I were you I'd get
her away from that balcony rail.
The doorman gets ticked if you
even through a piece of gum
over the side.
Bebe, dear?  Please, come on in.
That's a girl.
All right, let me have a look at you.
Come on, here we are.
Well, I don't really blame you, dear.
You know, Roz and I are both upset too.
You know, look at it this way: at least
you're no worse off than you were before.
You don't know the things I did for that man -
the depraved, Western-themed appetites I satisfied!
He was eighty-five, how bad could it have been?
Ever worn a saddle?
Do I have to answer that?
Well, you know, Bebe, there are
other Big Willys out there,
better ones!
Richer, older...
Impotent!
Oh dear, you always know what to say.
I know what hell I put you through over this.
I insist that you take this,
as a small token of my gratitude.
Oh Bebe, really...
Look, Roz!  It's a gold Rolex!
Oh my goodness...
Bebe... where did you get this?
Just don't wear it to the funeral.
Guest Starring
RICHARD HAMILTON as Big Willy