Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
This is Dr. Frasier Crane, KACL, 780.
Frasier, that was security.
Some woman insisted on seeing you,
she just blew right past them.
Oh, don't panic, Roz — probably just
one of my more ardent fans.
Niles, we've got to talk!  It's urgent.
Frasier, I'm with a patient!
- Is, uh, this about a woman?
- Yes.
Take all the time you need.
- Well?
- She's back...
the scourge of my existence.
Strange, I usually get some sign
when Lilith is in town —
dogs forming into packs,
blood weeping down the wall.
I'm talking about...
Diane Chambers.
Lucille, send Mr. Carr home.
She just showed up at the station today.
Apparently some play she wrote
is being produced here in town.
I admit, I just sort of panicked
when I saw her,
but I think I covered it masterfully.
All right, all right, all right.
Well, uh, why do you think you reacted
that way?
Oh, spare me the psychiatrist bit, Niles.
That includes putting down the pad!
In the drawer, Niles!
Fine. My first question to you is this:
Are you still in love with her?
No! Not in the least!
It's a ridiculous suggestion.
Seeing as how I have nowhere
to write the phrase, "classic denial,"
I'll move on.
So, about this woman
for whom you have so little feeling
that you raced across town and burst
into one of my sessions — is there
any lingering resentment?
Over what?!
Well, she did leave at the altar.
When you told her how that made you feel,
was there anything you left unsaid?
Any phrase or feeling
you wished you had expressed to her?
I'm making the assumption here
that you did tell her how you felt.
I sort of did.
"Sort of" is another one of those phrases
that just wants to go in my pad.
I expressed my distaste for the way
I'd been treated, yes.
Frasier, she rejected you
in the most debilitating way
a man can be rejected.
You've got to more than
"sort of" tell her how that felt.
Well, I can't just tell Diane
how awful she made me feel now!
It's a distant memory for her.
I'd feel weak!
You have no reason to feel weak.
You've moved on in your life too.
You have a new career, new wealth, new success.
You simply need closure in this one area.
I tuned you out after that.
I'm going to invite Diane over for dinner tonight,
and I'm really gonna flaunt my success,
really rub her nose in it!
That'll prove I'm not just some cast-aside
that never got over her.
Niles, I know it's not psychologically sound.
But we're still human.
We have to do
what feels good sometimes, don't we?
I'd just like to be on the record
as saying I'm against it.
- Fine.
- You know the path that leads
to peace with Diane and you're rejecting it.
- Yes.
- I'm washing my hands of the entire matter.
- Wouldn't miss it for the world though, would you?
- I'll be there at seven with a cheeky Bordeaux.
No, no, no.
Daphne, I was very specific about this.
The mayor's plaque goes on the piano...
The Otis Klandenning "Man of the Year Award"
goes right over here...
And my jewel — my SeaBea — goes right here
where she can't miss it!
Hmm, that seems a bit subtle.
- Why don't I just use this to serve the olives?
- Give me that!
I wish someone would just tell me who this woman is,
and why we're trying to impress the pants off her.
She's a one-time Boston barmaid
who had a nervous breakdown
and ended up in a sanitorium,
where I met her,
fell for her,..
and then was so mercilessly rejected by her
that to this day
there is a sucking chest wound...
...where once there dwelled a
heart!
You remember my brother Niles,
my father Martin,
and this is his health-care worker, Daphne Moon.
- What a tasteful abode.
- Well, it's modest in its way.
No, that's what I like about it.
After the rambling beach house
I've been living in,
I'm ready for something smart and efficient.
White wine, Diane?
I'm pouring an '85 Montrachet
La Guiche I purchased at auction.
Oh, I always keep a bottle of that
open myself.
Hang this up!
Well, Martin, it's been too long.
How have you been?
Well, my wife died,
I got shot in the hip,
and I had to move in with Frasier
'cause I kept falling down in the shower.
Well, you look wonderful!
Yes, you do!
That's the bad one.
Niles, do you remember the last time
I was in town and we dined together?
You had just started dating this woman —
she was the queerest little creature.
She ate everyone's sorbet, and
then she had to lie down
in the ladies' lounge
while the coat-check girl
massaged her abdomen!
Oh, I hope I haven't put my foot in it.
You and she didn't get married
and live happily ever after, did you?
No, can't say as we did.
- Care for an olive?
- Oh, thank you.
These are a Pyreenean taste treat!
They're handpicked and bottled
by Andalusian monks!
You can spit the pits in here.
So, there I was, on the balcony
of my Malibu beachhouse,
when a pod of whales passed by.
I knew I had to commune
with these gentle giants,
...so like a flash, I was on the beach,
scrambling to my kayak.
But cruel fortune interceded,
when, not twenty yards offshore,
I suddenly discovered myself
entangled in an enormous bed of-of, um—
- Sea kelp?
- Exactly right, sea kelp!
Oh, that's funny — I thought he said
"seek help."
So, you haven't told us
how you've come to be in Seattle.
Oh, a small theater group has decided
to produce a play I've written.
- Which one?
- Oh, my most recent work.
It's a sort of feminist odyssey,
experimental in places,
in tone akin to Saroyan,
with a soupçon of Gide,
and a hearty nod
to Clifford Odets!
I meant which theater?
- Oh!  The Roundabout.
- That seems appropriate.
You know, why don't you people
just keep talking amongst yourselves?
I will go and fetch the profiteroles.
They were prepared
by the hottest new pastry chef in...
oh, what's the use?
I'll help.
He always overpowders.
Yeah, I'm sure Old Man Kennedy
felt this kind of pride
when his boys would go out
and play touch football.
Now, Frasier, you know her better than I.
Is that what she looks like
when she's writhing in envy?
Oh, shut up.
All right, I admit you were right.
Before she leaves here tonight,
I am going to tell her
how much pain she made me feel.
The savage truth this time —
there will be no sugarcoating it!
And yes, I am aware of the irony!
Oh, it must be wonderful
to see your words come to life like that.
Oh yes.  It's a dream come true.
- Diane, are you OK?
- Yes, I'm fine.  Why?
- Well, your cheek was kind of twitching.
- It was?
- Oh well, it was probably fatigue.
Where were we?
- Oh, I was asking about your play.
- Oh, right!
- There it goes again, the twitch!
That was either a very large twitch
or a very small seizure.
You know, I'm not sure how much
I really want to talk
about my play right now.
Bad luck and all that!
Yes, and we all know what a struggle it is
to get Diane to talk about herself.
Oh Frasier, you always could kid!
How I miss that!
Look, Diane, please,
I-I really didn't mean anything by it.
I'm sorry—
It's not that!
It's my whole life, it's ruined!
- Niles, could you please get her some water?
- Of course, of course.
Oh, everything I told you tonight is a lie.
I'm sorry for this.
- Oh, I must look just awful.
- Your cheek stopped jumping.
All right, now.  Tell me what happened.
Was it about your play?
There it goes again!
Look, would you people please
just give us some privacy?!
All right now.  From the beginning.
Well, it all started a few months ago
when I lost my job.
I'd been writing for
"Dr. Quinn, Medicine Woman."
I was on the set one day,
and I was trying to show Jane Seymour
the proper way to cauterize
a wound with a branding iron,
and I accidentally
set her hair on fire.
Well, from there
it was a steady slide downhill.
A two-year relationship ended.
I lost the beach house,
friends stopped calling —
the one bright spot
was my play in Seattle.
Well, I flew up here yesterday
only to find that the backer
was pulling out.
I was so distraught
I found myself wandering around the city
in complete despair.
It's then that like a ray of hope
from heaven,
I saw your smiling face
on the side of a bus.
And that's why I'm here today.
You helped me the only other time
I was this low.
Frasier, I'm asking
for your help again.
Of course I'll help you, Diane.
- Well, that was a bit scary.
- I'll say — watching someone
go completely crackers like that.
- What's the matter with you now?
- Nothing, I'm fine.
Just suddenly missing my Maris.
INTERPLAY
My God, Niles,
it's such a glorious day!
I walked all the way here.
Thirty-two blocks,
and Bruno Maglies be damned!
Oh yes, I see the look,
I know exactly what it means too.
How could I very well say "no" to Diane?
She came to me in crisis.
Oh, excuse me,
a double cappuccino, please,
light cinnamon,
thank you very much.
Oh, you know, the change in Diane
has really been quite gratifying.
Dropped her off at the theater today,
and there was a smile on her face
that I haven't seen in...
well, far too many years.
Oh, I know what you're thinking.
Where did she get the money to do the play?
Well, she found a backer!
It's tax deductible!
Thank you.
Oh, why don't you go ahead and say
what you're thinking, Niles?
That I'm falling for her again.
"Well, you did bounce in here
as though you were on top of the world,
and babbling about her smile"
— I just don't want to  hear it, Niles!
I'm simply helping her
to get back on her feet
and out of my life as quickly as possible.
No, I don't know
how long it's going to take.
Look, I said I don't know!
Oh, really, Niles!
Curse you, you are the most
infuriating busybody!
I'm not sitting with you.
FOREPLAY
It really is a lovely city.
"Night — making all things dimly beautiful..."
"...One veil over us both."
Cyrano?
Yes.  Eleven years later,
we're still on the same page.
Frasier, these past few weeks,
you've given so much of yourself to me.
I want to give the one gift
I have to bestow.
I want you to be the first person
to see my play.
Will you come to dress rehearsal tonight?
- Diane, I'd be honored.
- Oh, wonderful, wonderful!