Well, we have time for
one more caller. Roz?
We have Ed on line three.
Hello, Ed, I'm listening.
Ed? Ed?
Well, we seem to have lost Ed.
Let's take another caller.
On line four we have...
Roz?
We have...
Eye... Lean.
Oh, Eileen.
-Hello Eileen, I'm listening.
-Dr. Crane...
I've been very happily married
for twenty years...
...and I wouldn't dream
of cheating but lately...
...when we're making love I find
myself fantasizing about...
-...people other than my husband.
-Well, that's perfectly normal.
It's quite normal to spice up one's
love life by imagining a tryst with...
-...a sports figure or a movie star
or... -Or a radio psychiatrist?
-Excuse me?
-It's your voice, Dr. Crane.
You must have the most
sensuous voice on earth.
Oh, I don't know, Eileen.
I've never seen your picture.
Would you mind describing yourself?
Oh, well I don't really
think that's appropriate...
-I'll do it.
-Roz, I don't think...
He's about six-one, with a granite jaw
and the broad shoulders of a marine.
He's been wearing
his hair short lately...
...but that only accentuates
his cobalt blue eyes...
...his chiseled cheekbones
and his full, provocative lips.
Wow! Thanks Roz.
And thank you, Dr. Crane.
I'll be thinking of you tonight.
With any luck, twice!
Well, this is Dr. Frasier Crane feeling
a little red in his chiseled cheeks.
Till tomorrow then,
this is KACL 780 AM.
Roz, that was quite
a flattering description.
You know, just out of curiosity...
Were you just helping
that lady with her fantasy...
...or do you really
see me that way?
You really don't
know, do you?
Frasier, I am so attracted
to you, I always have been.
Your looks, your voice...
You don't know how many times
I've wanted to strip naked...
...and hurl myself
at that glass partition...
...like a bug on a windshield.
-Are you through?
-Well, ask a stupid question!
All right Roz,
I will see you tomorrow.
Hey, aren't you going
to the staff meeting?
No, no, no, just tell them
that my aunt died.
I'm off to her lawyer's now,
she put me in charge of her memorial.
-Oh, I'm so sorry.
-Oh, don't be.
She was a dreadful old harpy.
Life around her was miserable.
That should look nice
on her headstone.
Well, I don't mean
any disrespect but...
...the entire time I knew her
she never said anything to me...
...that wasn't scornful,
derisive or contemptuous.
So how come she made you
in charge of her memorial?
I was her favourite!
-Evening all.
-Hello.
Dad, I thought we
had an agreement.
Eddie doesn't roll
around on the sofa...
...and I don't throw him
in front of a bus!
-Hello, Daphne.
-Oh, hello Dr. Crane.
-Will you be joining us for dinner?
-If it's not too much trouble.
It's Maris's night to
host her book club...
...and they are more comfortable
not having a man there.
Yes, apparently Niles makes
the ladies self-conscious.
Well, I sat in on
the last discussion...
...and Mrs. Esterbrook-Kindred
developed a facial tic...
...every time she had to
say the word "Balzac."
So how did it go with
Aunt Louise's lawyer?
Did you get the old bat's
affairs straightened out?
Ask her yourself.
Apparently, it was
Aunt Louise's wish...
...that Niles dispose of her ashes.
Now the pressure's on me to
find the perfect place for her...
...to rest for eternity. I haven't the
faintest idea what to do with her.
Why don't you just
flush her down the toilet?
-Mr. Crane, you can't do that!
-Why not? She loved the water.
Oh, oh, that's it: the beach.
Oh, no, no, she hated seagulls.
And vice-versa.
Oh, oh, oh... no!
It doesn't matter where I pick...
...you know it's not going
to be good enough.
Whatever I did she
always found fault.
Remember when I used
to mow her lawn?
Yes, what about the
Christmas tree I bought her?
The ashtray I made at camp?
"Is that the best you
can do? It wobbles!"
I wish I had that ashtray now!
-So when's the memorial service?
-It's two weeks after tomorrow.
Lucky lucky me, her last request
was that I deliver the eulogy.
Oh come on now, you can handle it.
You just stand up there
and say a few nice things.
There aren't any!
Then just make them up. Everyone
lies a little in eulogies.
No Daphne, I refuse to invent
virtues the woman didn't have.
I'll just have to find something
good I can honestly say about her.
Good luck! She was nothing but
a crabby, tight-fisted old pain.
All she ever did was sit around
that house day after day watching TV.
She kept that same old
cruddy furniture all her life.
What?
Oh, remember how she always
used to complain about the winters?
Oh yeah.
Every year she was going to take
a trip to the South Pacific.
It was her big dream.
But would she spend
the money? Nooooo.
She just sat around
whining all the time...
...about how she'd like
to be in a warmer climate.
My guess is
she finally made it.
I think it would be terribly
bad to go through life...
...having a secret dream
and never fulfilling it.
You'd never do anything silly
like that, would you Mr. Crane?
-What're you talking about?
-Oh, I don't know.
Perhaps a little something involving
a certain shoebox you keep hidden.
-Shoebox?
-Forget it, it's not important.
Oh fine, if you don't want to
talk about it, don't talk about it.
It's only something you've given
over thirty years of your life to.
Hey, I didn't tell you that so you
can go around blabbing it to everyone.
-Tell us, dad, what's in the
shoe box? -Nothing, all right?
All right, all right.
It's just some songs I wrote...
-...for Frank Sinatra.
-And he keeps them in his shoebox.
I think your work here is done.
Dad?
Your mother and I used to
listen to Sinatra all the time.
I know most of
his songs by heart.
I guess I got it into my head one day
that I'd try to write a song myself.
I'd be at the station
house or on a stakeout...
...I'd get an idea and pretty
soon I had a shoebox full.
I used to imagine your mother and I
seeing Frank in the stands in Vegas...
...and he'd open the
show with one of my songs.
Oh gee, dad, why did you
never tell us about this?
-Because it is stupid. They
were no good... -Oh...
And don't bother to ask,
I'm not letting you see 'em.
Here they are. Just like
I told you, in his shoebox.
-They're quite good if you ask me.
-"You are the song my soul would sing."
-Very poetic. -"You make my
heart go ring-a ding-ding."
That was during Frank's
ring-a-ding period.
Lord, this shoebox
is full of them.
-"I didn't mean to hurt her, she made
me lose my mind". -Hey, lemme see that!
No, that's just some confession I took
from a guy. The lyrics are on the back.
Anyway, I never finished them.
They were never any good.
Well, except this. I gotta admit...
...this has got "Frank Sinatra"
written all over it.
"She's such a groovy lady."
It's still got that nice
contemporary sound.
So, why don't you send it
to old Blue Eyes?
No, they're just words
scribbled on a piece of paper.
The tune's in my head, I don't
know how to write it down.
Well, Niles and I do. You've got
the tune in your head.
Why don't you let us
write it down for you?
We can finish this dream tonight.
-It's just a dumb idea.
-Oh come on dad, really.
Oh, you're wasting your breath
trying to convince him to do something.
-Dad, come on.
-Come on now. Drop it.
Yeah, you're probably right.
You just sit there night
after night watching TV...
...until the time finally comes
when we collect your ashes...
...and scatter them over that chair...
...where they'll probably go unnoticed.
-All right, okay.
-You mean it?
-OK, Niles.
-I get the piano.
Okay, so boys...
...the way I'm hearing the intro,
it goes something like this...
Of course, it is your piano.
No, no, it goes:
-So it's like... -No, no, come
on, this is the big finish.
Dad, dad, in Niles's defense,
after four hours your...
...sound a lot like your...
-Right, Niles, let's just try
it again. -All right. Like this.
Yeah! That's it.
-Yeah. Let's hear the chorus
one last time. -OK!
Niles. Dad, I don't
mean to criticise.
You know that "heidi-hiedi?"
It sounds like Cab Calloway
sung backwards.
-You got any better suggestions?
-Er, yes, yes:
No, no:
"She makes the bravest
cat go 'fraidy!"
I've got it: "She could have
slept with Warren Beatty!"
-Very nice Daphne, no. -Well,
I'm sticking with my one, keep singing.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
I don't mean to quibble...
...but it seems like her heart
is always going heidi-hiedi...
...ringy-dingy,
or scooby dooby.
-Look, I don't need another critic.
-Fine, perhaps a cardiologist?
In all due respect...
...I think I'm a little more
tuned in to what Frank likes...
...and this is pretty close to
perfect the way it is. -Well?
How about that! Thirty years
and I've finally finished it.
Congratulations, dad.
Thanks guys.
Yeah, first thing tomorrow,
I'm mailing it to Frank's people.
A little help from Lady Luck...
...maybe they'll kick it upstairs
to the chairman himself.
Oh Jeez! The service
is in an hour.
Aren't you finished
with that eulogy yet?
I can't even come up
with a first line.
I got this old photo album, probably
one of her pictures might inspire me.
How about this:
"We all loved Aunt Louise,
even if the camera didn't!"
Dr. Crane, you've been agonising
over this for two weeks.
Perhaps it's time to start
bending the truth a little.
No, I refuse to lie.
I find it hard to
believe there isn't...
...one nice story
you can tell about her.
Maybe a cute little saying she used?
I'm not sure that, "Stop crying...
...or I'll give you something to
cry about" would qualify.
-Where are you off to?
-Just going to go check the mail.
I wish they'd just give him
an answer about that song.
He must have made a hundred trips to
the mailbox during the past two weeks.
Oh, bless you, Daphne. Are you sure
you're up to coming to the memorial?
Oh, it's just a little cold.
Besides, in my family, when there
was a funeral everybody went.
I remember when
Grammy Moon passed on.
My brothers had been off
on a three-day bender.
They couldn't even stand on
their own - pissed as newts!
But they crawled to that chapel
on their hands and knees.
Very commendable.
Yeah, well, they had an obligation.
They were the pallbearers.
Hello, Daphne.
-Hello.
Oh dear Lord, Niles, don't tell me you
haven't disposed of those ashes yet.
Frasier, I have taken them
to a dozen locations.
Fossy glade, a babbling brook,
a moonlit pond.
None of them felt right,
what am I going to do?
Well, winter's coming. The
sidewalks are always slippery.
I'm having the same
problem with the eulogy!
Oh, remember when this
photo was taken?
the day Aunt Lousie took me to
Wilson's Meadow to fly a kite?
It cost her 35 cents and
when it got stuck in a tree...
...she made me climb up after it.
I fell out, broke my
collarbone in two places.
I think that's the only
time I saw her laugh.
Frasier! I think she might
be happy there!
Niles, I think you might be right.
And even if she's not,
let's still do it.
-Any news about your song?
-Nah.
Listen, we better get started.
All right. Perhaps
I'll have some inspiration...
...on the way over in the car.
And Wilson's Meadow is on the way.
We can stop and scatter the ashes.
Well, this sounds like a family affair.
-Maybe I'll take my car and meet
you there. -All right, let's go.
Wilson's Meadow is
the perfect place.
Aunt Louise, you've
tormented me for two weeks...
and finally I've shown you
I can do something right.
Oh, shut up!
Here, here, yes, yes. Perfect.
There's something rattling in here.
Like some great grisly morata.
What am I going to
say at this memorial?
-Don't ask me.
-You write lyrics, don't ya? -Right!
Tell that to Sinatra!
Oh, dad, it's a good song.
I even caught myself singing it
in the shower this morning.
Just because you haven't heard
anything yet doesn't mean...
-...you have heard something?
-Yeah.
-This morning they rejected it.
-Oh, I'm sorry, dad.
Oh, it's okay. Sinatra must
get thousands of songs...
...sent to him. What did I expect?
-Well, you know, at least you gave it
your best shot. -Yeah, I guess.
I mean, sure it would have been
nice to hear it sung...
...but hey, I finished it, finally!
Yeah, I walked down that highway...
...and climbed that mountain,
and reached for the stars.
Oh sure, now I get hot!
-I can't open the damn urn!
-Oh, you are so helpless!
-For Pete's sake, give it to me,
give it to me. -I made it loose.
It looks like Louise's
whole rest home showed up.
It must be "Liver & Onions
Day" in the cafeteria.
Apparently when they heard
it was Frasier Crane...
... from the radio speaking,
the whole rest home turned out.
-Can't wait to hear what he
has to say. -Neither can he.
He's huddled in the rectory still
working on his first sentence.
How did the scattering go?
Were there any problems?
No, nothing important.
Dear friends, thank you
all for coming today.
I know how very deeply your
friendship was treasured by Louise.
We are privileged to have
with us her favourite nephew...
...one of Seattle's most eloquent
speakers, Dr. Frasier Crane.
Dr. Crane has spent the
last fortnight reflecting...
...on what
Louise meant to him.
Dr. Crane?
Well, well, well.
What can I say about Aunt Louise?
What can
I say?
Louise...
...touched us all.
In fact...
...she touches us still.
Aunt Louise...
...loved to teach
us all lessons.
You know, it's hard to picture
her without hearing her saying,
"I'm going to teach
you a lesson."
What particularly comes to mind...
...by the very way
she lived her own life...
...she taught us how important it is...
...to pursue our dreams.
Whether we succeed or fail...
...what really matters
is that we tried.
And now as we say
goodbye to Louise...
...a phrase comes to mind. It was
coined by my very own father...
"She's Such A Groovy Lady."
I said, "She's Such A Groovy Lady."