So, what's the plan?
Are we going to
turn off the lights
and jump out
and yell surprise?
Oh, yes, Roz.
Let's startle a man who
just had open-heart surgery.
Sorry. I can't get used
to thinking of Niles as sick.
Oh, Niles is great.
All these exercises he's doing
he's going to be just as strong
as he ever was.
Here's the guest of honor.
Niles, good to see you out and about.
You look great!
Thank you. Thank you.
I'll tell you
it's good to be out
after being cooped up
in that apartment all week.
Hello.
I never thought I'd grow tired of reading Flaubert.
Oh, please.
He's been parked on his ass
watching The Young
and The Restless.
FRASIER:
Niles!
Not the soaps!
You can't be serious.
Well, I'm hardly hooked.
They fascinate me as cultural artifact.
I was just telling Gertrude.
Their use of stock figures is reminiscent
of thecommedia dell'arte.
Esther is Punchinell
o, Victor is Flavio
and Nicki, well, she's just the town pump.
Now do you see why
I need my own telly, Daphne?
You have your
own telly in Manchester.
(uneasy laughter)
Here's champagne and sparkling
cider for you Niles
and help yourself to brunch
whenever you're ready.
Word to the wise:
Stay away from the sausage.
They're not sausages, Dad.
They're soysages.
Niles is on
a postoperative diet.
We are trying
to support him.
Oh, sorry. What about the bacon?
Fake-un.
Hey, everyone,
I'd like to propose a toast.
To my family and friends:
Your love and support
have been overwhelming.
DAPHNE:
Oh, Niles.
During my operation
I was technically dead
for several minutes.
Yes, we know, son. You told us.
But it gave me a fresh
perspective on everything.
It took a brush with death
to remind me how lucky I am
to be alive.
And Gertrude,
thank you for giving up
the guest bedroom
so that I don't have
to climb all those stairs.
Oh, no, I'm happy
to sleep on that sofa bed
with the hard metal frame.
You have a nice, soft
bed in Manchester.
Oh, Daphne, it's okay.
Her bracing honesty reminds me
that I'm alive.
You, you... Oh, you!
You are a treasure to me.
I cherish every day
we're together.
Oh, thank you, Niles.
There may be others
around here
who could benefit
from a near-death experience.
Well, let's eat before
the fake-un loses its shape.
Wow, Niles is really loving
life with a vengeance.
I was the same way
after I got shot.
First day back at the precinct
I went around
hugging all the guys
Telling them all I loved 'em
How long did that last?
Until they started
calling me "Martina."
It is kind of weird
seeing Niles so lovey-dovey
with Mrs. Moon.
Believe me,
when you're in that state
you can find something to love
even in the biggest jerk.
Roz, I want to tell you you are a treasure.
Maybe I don't say it often enough,
but you are.
Shut up, Martina.
(humming)
Hi.
I know that song.
0."
Yes, Mozart's
"Symphony Number 4
Molto allegro.
I've just bought
this new recording for Niles.
It is fantastic.
I've never heard
such string articulation.
Oh, I remember
what it is.
It's that commercial
with the singing cats.
♪♪ If your cat has a yearnin
g for tuna ♪♪
♪
♪♪ Da-da-da, ocean buffet... ♪
One of the cats was wearing
a tiny tuxedo.
Good.
So few cats dress
for the symphony anymore.
Frasier, Roz.
Oh, hi, guys.
Guess who just walked
a mile on the treadmill.
Oh, way to go, Niles.
The doctor says he's
in the 95th percentile
of patients recovering
from bypass surgery.
95th percentile!
That's wonderful, Niles.
Well, now, Frasier
good health
is not a competition.
When you've heard time's
winged chariot hurrying near
as I have,
every day is a gift.
Oh, yoiks.
What tone-deaf prankster
gave you this?
You've heard it?
Well, as much as I could bear.
Did you hear what the conductor did
to the andante?
I just hope
he bought it dinner first
Well, I couldn't
agree more, Niles.
Frasier, you said
you loved that CD.
Well, Niles has convinced me
otherwise.
You know, I'm in
the mood for a scone.
Help me pick one out.
All right.
That was weird.
I'll say.
Who can't pick out
their own scone?
No. I mean you and Niles.
Usually that would have been
a two-hour argument
ending in tears
and cursing in Italian.
I'm afraid those days
are over, Roz.
What happened?
Well, it's a long story.
Okay. When Niles
was in the hospital
and he was being wheeled
into surgery...
he looked so frail and vulnerable
so I..
I took my case
to a higher power.
Hello, God.
It'’’s me, Dr. Frasier Crane
Though I don't talk to you
as often as perhaps I should
I want to thank you
for all the times
you've indulged me in the past
Although, I have yet to see
the inside of the Empire Club--
just kidding.
Anyway, today I ask you to look
after my brother, Niles Crane.
I love him, even if I don't always show it.
And I regret all the time
he and I wasted
in petty quarrels.
If you spare him, oh, Lord,
I promise to cherish
every moment we have together.
But, Frasier,
you don't think
God is going to strike Niles down
if you get in an argument,
do you?
Well, technically,
the way it's structured
he'd come after me.
Seeing as how I was the one
that initiated the deal, you see?
If I'd had more time,
I might have worded thin
gs differently, but...
Oh, oh, uh, le
t's get this to go
My soap starts in 20 minutes.
Ashley might come
out of her coma today.
You know, since your
recovery is going so well
maybe we should check you out
make sure all your equipment's
working properly.
You're not talking about my exercise bicycle,
are you?
The doctor said
it would be okay.
If you need
a second opinion
maybe Nurse Naughty
could make a house call.
I could use a checkup.
But I think we should
err on the side of caution
In a few weeks, I have another stress test.
Thank you.
And if all goes well,
Nurse Naughty will be
one satisfied
healthcare professional.
See you.
Oh, bye, guys.
Oh, Niles, wait.
Frasier says he thinks
the string articulation
is really good.
In this?
Frasier, you know
I hold your opinion
in highest regard,
but are you nuts?
Perhaps, I am, Niles.
Thank you.
Maybe you just need
to get your hearing checked.
I'll do that.
Thank you, Niles.
(loudly):
I'll see you later!
(chuckles)
Very amusing.
I get it.
Oh, oh, here they are.
Frasier, Frasier,
tell them what you told me.
I never thought
I'd live to see the day.
Perhaps this is why
I was spared.
Niles, how was your stress test?
Oh, the doctor cleared me
to return to normal food
and regular physical activity.
Oh, Darling,
that's wonderful.
Yes, yes.
In moderation, of course.
Congratulations, son.
Perhaps now, Niles
we can get back
to the squash courts.
Oh, I don't think so.
But the doctor said
it was okay.
Yeah, but shouldn't there
be more to life
than competition for useless bragging rights?
You didn't think they
were useless three months ago
when you won.
You bragged for three months.
I've changed a lot
since then.
The point is that
I have roses
to stop and smell.
I see. So, let me
get this straight.
You're going to give up squash and smell roses.
Poor Frasier.
I hope that you don't have to go
through what I did
in order to become
as wise as I have.
You can still be wise
and play squash, darling.
Daphne's right.
Go out, have some fun.
But I am having fun.
Since my incident,
birds sing more sweetly.
The sky is so much bluer.
Niles, it has rained
every day this week.
I see rain differently, too.
There's something I need
to tell you.
It's something I've been thinking about.
(thunder crashing)
You were saying, Frasier?
Nothing.
My grandmother died
a couple of weeks ago
and I feel bad
because I never told her
how much she meant to me.
Well, my heart certainly
goes out to you.
Grieving is difficult enough
without those unresolved...
Frasier, I'm sorry.
But we have Dr. Niles Crane
on line two.
I'm sure you all remember my brother Niles...
from our last segment.
I'm sure all my listeners join me
in hoping he can get back
to work real soon.
Thank you, Frasier.
I just thought I'd add
the perspective
of one who has ducked
the scythe of the Grim Reaper.
By all means.
Go ahead, Niles.
Your grandmother knows
how you feel.
When I was briefly dead
the overriding feeling I had
was the love of my family
and friends.
MAN:
Wow, so I shouldn't
feel bad?
NILES:
Certainly not.
Get out there
and live your life, Grant.
Carpe that diem.
Isn't that right, Frasier?
I couldn't agree more, Niles
We'll be right back
after traffic.
I'm beginning to regret
betting on the clown.
Roz, I can't eat,
I can't sleep.
I just lie in bed
awake at night
mentally arguing
with Niles.
And I win every time!
Frasier,
this is insane
Do you really think
something bad is going to happen
if you break your deal with God?
Oh, of course not.
Well, maybe a little.
I don't know.
Roz, my brother could have died.
I can't be ungrateful
to whatever higher power
may have spared him.
I just can't imagine
that God would be upset...
Roz!
Oh, he's God,
Have you read
the Old Testamtent?
He can be ruthless!
Traffic's done.
You're on in five.
Welcome back, Seattle.
Oh, I see we have someone
on line two.
Go ahead, caller. I'm listening.
NILES:
Still me, Frasier.
Say, I had some thoughts
about your advice to Cynthia
from Tacoma.
Speaking as one who has walked
through the valley
of the shadow of death
Cynthia,
I think diet and exercise
should take care
of your problems.
Nothing like a good
fat-free muffin...
Hi, Daph,
I'm here for Niles.
He's at your place.
He said you were meeting
him there for dinner.
I specifically told him
I would pick him up here.
Sorry.
Not bad enough he usurps
my radio show...
What are you doing?
Oh, you'll think I'm silly
but I'm donating food to the poor.
Why would I think that's silly?
What does that say about me?
No, I was just going to say...
I do my bit
for charity, you know.
You have no idea
how many vacations
I've bought
at silent auctions.
No, that's not it.
You see, when I found out
Niles needed heart surgery
I felt so scared and helpless.
So, I kind of made a vow
that if he came out okay
I would spend more time
helping the less fortunate.
A vow?
You mean like a promise to God?
I know it must sound absurd
to you, a man of science.
No, no.
Now, when...
exactly did you make
this promise?
The night before his surgery.
The night before, you say.
Interesting.
You say Niles
is at my place?
Yeah.
Excuse me.
Keep up the good work.
What's all this?
Food for the poor.
Oh, must be nice
to be poor
and have people just
giving you food.
Daphne, you were up
awfully late last night.
Yeah, I was watching television.
Were you?
Or was that husband of yours
sneaking upstairs
to demand you perform your wifely chore?
I wish.
He's still not ready to be
in the same bed with me.
He's rich and you don't
have to sleep with him?
Rub it in, why don't you?
I know he's trying
to ease back into things
but it's been weeks since
the doctor said he was okay.
Well, isn't it obvious?
The poor thing's probably
not feeling very attractive.
He's all skinny and pale,
and now he has that scar, too.
I don't think
that's it, Mum.
I just think he's scared.
And I understand that.
But how long are we going
to go on like this?
Until you stop babying him.
I'm not babying him.
I'm just giving him
the time he needs.
Oh, piffle.
What he needs is
a swift kick in the bum.
Look, you've got to seduce him.
Use your feminine wiles.
That's how your brother Billy landed Kevin.
Well, sharing a cell helped.
You know, maybe
I'll give that a try.
When Niles walks into
that guest room tonight
I'll have a surprise
waiting for him--
candles, soft music,
a negligee...
nothing too sexy.
We don't want
to strain his heart.
There's nothing wrong with your ego.
Thanks for the advice, Mum.
My pleasure, love.
Oh, and since you and Niles
will be in the guest room
I'll sleep in your room tonight.
No sense in letting that
king-size bed go to waste.
This time use a coaster
when you take your teeth out.
Stop the tape.
Who's he again?
That's Diego
the illegitimate son
of Sonya LaFontaine.
He joined the army to avenge
the death of his brother.
Although, frankly,
I'm a little worried about him
I'm not sure he's figh
this war for the right reasons.
Hey, you want some of this fancy dessert?
It must be really good
because Frasier told
me not to touch it
No, no, thanks.
I brought some of these
tasty rye flats
in case I...
in case I feel peckish.
They look like wood.
Well, he di
But, you know, I feel my tastes
have gotten simpler
since I cheated death.
It's hard to explain.
Don't need to explain
to me, son.
I know what it's like
to cheat death.
That's true.
Although I think I got a little
closer than you did.
Oh, really?
Well, let's see...
I got shot by a gun
and you ate a bunch of cheese.
I was clinically dead
for several minutes.
I looked death
square in the eye.
You may have looked him in
the eye, but I shook his hand.
Really?
Well, I kissed him on the cheek.
Well, I kissed him on the lips.
Also, Death was a girl.
Dad, I don't want to turn this into a competition.
I'm just trying to embrace life to the fullest.
Oh, would you
give it a rest.
Excuse me?
You haven't embraced a damn thing.
All you're doing is yakking about
feeling this and
experiencing that.
You're not doing anything.
You won't go back to work
or play squash or eat
any of your favorite foods.
I'm easing into things
until I'm back to normal.
The doctor says you're there.
Well, I'm just being
extra cautious.
Sounds to me like you're afraid, son.
Well, what if I am?
Haven't I earned the right to be afraid?
I could have died.
I understand.
Okay.
When I got out of the hospital
I was terrified to take a risk.
Just didn't want
to leave the house.
Ducked for cover every time
a car backfired.
I know my fears aren't rational.
I know my heart is sound.
I feel fine.
But I felt fine
before this happened.
How do I know
that the same thing isn't.
You don't know.
That's exactly
what I came to realize.
Life's a crap shoot.
We could all go at any time.
That's why we have to make the
most of whatever time we've got.
Like sand through the hourglass
so are the days of our lives.
Okay, point taken.
Thank you, Dad.
Where are you going?
To live my life.
You forgot the rye flats.
No, I didn't, Dad.
No, I didn't.
Well, you're not
leaving them here.
Good evening.
Hello, God, it's me again.
Dr. Frasier Crane.
Listen, it seems that when
we made our little arrangement
there was another deal in place.
Now, I've had some experience
with double-booking
and I know that the person
who books first
always gets priority.
So, as long as Daphne
keeps up her end...
which she is, to the letter--
it seems our little arrangement
would be rendered null and void.
Ergo, I am now going to yell
at my brother.
Unless of course, you give me a sign.
Very well, then.
This is going to be sweet.
(elevator dings)
Niles!
There you are.
You're 40 minutes late.
Well, no matter.
I have more important things to do.
Not so fast, mister!
You, sir, have been
insufferable for the
past few weeks.
It might enlighten
you to know
that your endless preaching
has been nothing more
than a thin cover
for your fear...
Yes, I know.
I know, Dad just told me.
And he was right,
I've been an ass lately.
I'm really sorry,
but I have to go.
My wife is waiting for me.
Frankly, Frasier,
I'm surprised you didn't
bring this up sooner.
But...
Huh.
Well played, God.
I'll see you at Easter.
(high-pitched scream)
Niles!
What happened?
Are you all right?
Yes.
I just jumped into bed
with your mother.
Oh, dear.
No wonder she screamed.
That wasn't her.
What were you doing in there?
I just... wanted to...
take my wife in my arms
and show her how much I love her.
Are you sure you're ready?
Trust me,
if my heart can take that
it can take anything.
♪♪ Hey, baby, I hear
the blues a-calling ♪♪
♪♪ Toss salads and
scrambled eggs ♪♪
Quite stylish.
♪♪ And maybe I seem
a bit confused ♪♪
♪♪Well, maybe,
but I got you pegged ♪♪
(laughs)
♪♪ But I don'’’t know what to do
♪♪
♪♪ With those toss salads
and scrambled eggs ♪♪
♪♪ They'’’re calling again
. ♪♪
Good night, Seattle!
We love you!