I, Daphne Moon,
do take thee, Niles Crane,
as my husband.
I promise you my fidelity
and my support...
My laughter and my tears...
My constant friendship
and my unending love
as long as we both shall live.
I, Niles Crane, do take thee,
Daphne Moon, as my wife.
I vow to you my fidelity
and my support
my honor and my respect.
My honesty and my protection.
You are my comfort, my joy,
and my one true love.
I will cherish you all the days
of my life
and treasure the journey
that has brought us
to this most wonderful,
perfect place.
For most folks, that's
one too many free cocktails.
(laughing):
Am I right?
Seriously,
do you have the rings?
Oh... no.
In our rush to get here,
I completely forgot about them.
Does this mean we can't get married?
It would if we didn't offer
seven different wedding band
packages for you to choose from.
Now, depending on your budget,
we can offer you anything
from the "Be Steel My Heart"--
that's genuine stainless
right there--
to the "Never-ending Love"
which can be returned for up
to 90 days; no questions asked.
They do seem
the nicest.
(cell phone rings)
Oh, damn, who could be calling
at this hour?
Wow, you certainly don't see
six-and-a-half karat gold
every day.
Daphne, it's Roz.
Hello?
Quick, turn on your TV.
My building's on the news. What?
Some murder-suicide thing.
I'm going to wave to you
from my balcony.
Darn, I'm not home.
Where are you?
You're not going to believe this,
w. hut Niles and I flew to Reno and
we're getting married right now
You are not!
I am so.
(high-pitched screams)
Apparently, it's some
sort of dolphin emergency
I should go.
I'll tell you everything
when we get back.
Okay, bye.
(sighs)
Ooh.
Sorry
You may exchange rings
as a symbol
of the promises
you've made here today.
(soft laughter)
By the power
vested in me
by the State of Nevada,
County of Washoe,
and the all-new Lucky Seven
Resort and Casino,
I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
Good luck.
(piped-in bells ringing)
Hey, don't forget to check out
our topless buffet.
He never said,
"You may kiss the bride."
You may kiss the bride
(keys jangling)
Chop, chop, Dad.
Let's get a move on.
Last time I was late
for the Farmer's Market,
I got the worst
of the squash blossoms.
Oh, whatever shall we serve
the duchess?
What?
I said, "I'm coming."
And it's not my fault I'm late,
it's Daphne's.
S.
l don't know where she is.
I had to make my own lunch.
Oh, dear Lord.
Give it here.
Two bags of chips,
three puddin' cups,
and a root beer.
H it?
What's wrong with it?
A: this is not a lunch,
and B: I fail to see
how it took you so long
since you did not
make anything
but simply transferred smaller
containers into a larger one.
Let's go.
Oh, uh...
Oh!
Hello, all. Hi.
Hello, all.
Where have you been?
I had to make my own lunch
Oh...
We've got some big news.
Yes, um...
Maybe they should sit down.
Oh, yes.
What's going on?
DAPHNE : Well..
Last night I told Niles
that I wanted to
marry him right then and there
NILES: And once I realized she
was serious,
we rushed out into the night
fully intending to.
But then we found
out that in Washington
it takes three days to
get a marriage license.
Thank goodness
Why?
"wHY"?
If we had missed
your wedding,
well, it would have
just killed me.
It would have?
Oh, of course
it would.
Niles, we've been there
through the last ten tortured
years of your courtship.
How could we not be hurt
if we missed the wedding?
But surely you could
understand if...
If someone were carried away
by their emotions.
Because it would have just
broken my heart.
We came here to tell you
that there's a wedding
in three days!
Oh, well...
Isn't that big news?
Yes.
We're going to have a...
A simple ceremony
at the courthouse.
That is just wonderful.
And you know what?
By way of a celebration,
please allow me
to treat us all to dinner
at Coeur du Singe.
How does that sound, huh?
That sounds wonderful.
(doorbell rings)
Hey, Martin.
Hey, how are
you doing?
Want to go
to the dog park?
Oh, my God,
you guys are here.
(joyous yells)
Well, I'm here, too.
Um, we were just talking
about our wedding.
Oh, good, I want to hear
all about it.
We're going to have a small
civil ceremony on Friday
(yells)
Huh?
Yes, if you'll excuse me,
I'm in a rush to get
to the Farmer's Market.
NILES: At this hour?
I hope you like
listless radicchio.
Okay, what the hell?
I thought you guys
got married in Reno.
We did, but
as we were trying
to tell Mr. Crane
and Dr. Crane,
they told us how hurt they'd be
if we got married without them.
NILES: Yes, yes, which in the
moment, failed to occur to us.
So, to spare their feelings,
we're having a fake wedding
on Friday.
Well, that works for me
because Alice is still
counting on being a flower girl.
Of course.
Great.
So, if you guys
have two weddings,
when's your anniversary
going to be?
Well, I suppose
to keep up appearances,
it'll have to be
the second one, won't it?
Well, could celebrate
two anniversaries.
A public on; and then a
second, secret
one just for us.
Ooh, I like that.
Sort of sexy
having an anniversary
only the two of us
know about.
Three of us.
I still can't believe
we're married.
It's our
one-day anniversary.
And we're the only ones
who know.
You know,
we should celebrate.
L-[ow about going
to the dog park?
That doesn't sound
very romantic.
I'm not talking to you.
NILES:
Nervous?
DAPHNE:
Less than last time.
Al. I guess it helps to
have had a rehearsal
That wasn't a rehearsal;
it was the real thing.
This is just
a touring company performance.
Right.
It's a bloody miracle
we're here in one piece
what with the way you drive.
I'm better at it when someone's
not screaming in my ear.
Well, in my day, people
didn't drive so recklessly.
Do you know why?
Is it because
you rode dinosaurs?
You should talk
to your daughter.
When we get home,
you're getting ice cream.
Why did we all
have to
just to pick up
a bloody license?
Couldn't we have met
at the church?
Mum, we aren't going
to the church.
We're getting married here.
You're what?
We're having
a civil ceremony
Without a minister?
Out of the question.
Mum...
That's enough, Daphne.
I am your mother and I will not
bear witness to a godless union.
Gertrude, I favor a
church wedding, too.
But this is their day,
not ours.
Maybe we should just let them
decide how it's going to be.
If people gut to decide things
for themselves,
no one would go to church.
If I may...
I'll handle this,
Your Honor.
Mrs. Moon...
You have my personal guarantee
that this will not be a
godless union.
For if you
truly believe
in the omniscience
and omnipresence of the Lord,
then surely are we not always
in His presence?
No, He lives at the church.
All I'm asking is
that you honor the wishes
of an old woman
whose every child has been
married by a minister--
or at least a prison chaplain.
Perhaps given the depth
of feeling here,
it would be best to wait.
Well, I suppose we
could find a church
in reasonably
short order.
I don't believe this.
Well, if you're
not going to get married now,
perhaps you could all
take this into the hall.
I have a schedule to keep.
Roz, take me home.
We'll call you when
we've cleared this up.
Ice.
Okay. Let's go, Al
Congratulations.
When you're ready to have
a proper wedding,
you know where to find me.
That we do.
On your fiery throne
presiding over the damned!
All right,
let's-let's go.
Where are we going
to find a clergyman
who will perform
on such short notice?
Hey, maybe the judge
knows somebody.
Hang on a second, you guys
Your Honor
I'm sorry, Daphne,
but it'll just be few days
and then we can be married.
We already are.
This is supposed to be the
happiest time of my life
I want to wear
my wedding ring.
I'm Mrs. Niles Crane,
and I don't want
to keep it a secret.
You just want to tell them
the truth?
Too complicated.
Let's just
get married again.
The wedding's on.
What? What about Mrs. Moon?
I'm sorry she'll miss it,
but that's her choice.
Your Honor, we've
changed our minds.
We want to be married.
Oh, all right, but we have to be
quick about this.
Are we ready to begin?
Yes.
JUDGE: Okay, let's do it.
Daphne, please repeat after me.
Actually, we've written
our own vows.
Of course you have.
I, Daphne Moon, do take thee,
Niles Crane, as my husband.
I promise you my fidelity
and my support...
My laughter and my tears...
You said you wouldn't
do this.
...my constant friendship...
I say a Int of things.
(chuckling)
Oh, Frasier, thank you
so much for dinner.
Yes, it was wonderful.
It was my pleasure.
Dad, don't you have
something to add?
Well, I already said thank you
for dinner.
What am I supposed to do,
get down on my knees
and kowtow to your fancy-ass
American Express card?
No...
I was referring to the gift
we have for them.
Oh, right!
I forgot about that.
Yeah, and thanks
for dinner, Frasier.
It really was excellent.
And I didn't think I'd
like beef cheeks...
Yes, yes, Dad,
give them the gift. I...
This is so exciting-
our first wedding present.
Oh, it's a silver
picture frame.
Beautiful.
And,nota hene,
it's been engraved
with today's date.
In order to commemorate
your wedding day
until your real gift
arrives.
Oh, it's very sweet.
Thank you Mr. Crane
and Dr. Crane.
Well, you can't call us that anymore.
We're family now.
So we are.
Well, thank you... Frasier.
(laughing)
Oh, that feels strange.
And thank you...
Martin.
Dad?
Dad.
Or Martin.
Whatever makes
you comfortable.
Oh, thank you, Mr. Crane.
Don't mention it.
Well, I'd better go and figure out
what to pack
for the honeymoon.
I'm just bringing sunscreen.
Pardon me.
I have to go poke out
my mind's eye.
Ah, you're lucky.
I always wanted to go
to Bora Bora.
Oh, it's going
to be fantastic, Dad.
We're staying in a thatched hut
built out over the water.
In the middle of the floor,
there's a window
where you can look straight down
to the bottom of the ocean.
Oh, well, I hope it's not ton deep.
When we went to the top
of the Space Needle
and you looked down,
you got sick.
Dad...
All over that poor
Japanese tour group.
Dad.
(doorbell
That was three years ago.
Mrs. Moon.
Did you find
a minister yet?
No.
I'm sorry,
Actually..
Good, then I'm not too late.
Too late for what?
When I got home
this afternoon...
And I began thinking:
I was married by a minister
in a church,
and what's it got me?
Alone and unloved is what.
And likely because I've been such
a rotten mother
to you all these years.
You haven't been rotten.
Oh, yes, I have.
On what should've been the happiest
day of your life,
I thought of only myself.
I'm ashamed, I'm, I mean,
I'm embarrassed.
And I apologize.
Oh, Mum.
Oh.
(frying)
Oh, my only solace is
you aren't married yet.
Because if I missed
my baby's wedding,
I wouldn't be able
to live with myself.
Daphne...
Niles...
You get married
any way you want to.
All that matters is that
I'm thereto share it with you
Of course you'll be there.
(Crying)
We'll go right back
to that courthouse tomorrow
and resume where
we left off.
Oh, nothing could make me
happier.
Ah, Mrs. Moon.
I see you've made peace
with the wedding.
Yes, Mrs. Moon
has rescinded her ultimatum
so we're having
the wedding tomorrow.
Ah.
Niles, may I have a word
with you?
NILES:Mm-hmm.
Excuse me.
What the hell is going on?
You guys already
got married.
Yes, but she doesn't
know that, so tomorrow
we're going to have another
ceremony for her benefit.
That's crazy.
It may be, but I'm afraid
the truth would crush her.
Oh, please
All the winepresses in Bordeaux
wouldn't crush that woman.
Niles, what you and Daphne
shared today was utterly unique.
You think so?
Yes, it was a singular moment.
Anyone fooled
by a repeat performance
would have to be
a complete imbecile.
True.
But if it's what Daphne wants,
I'll support her.
We'll get Roz back,
we'll find a different judge,
and we'll just do it
all over again.
And... it'll be just as perfect
as today's was.
Fine.
But I'm not singing
"Wonderful World" again.
(gasping):
Maybe more perfect.
Remember how
excited we were
at our first wedding?
Yeah, we were both shaking.
Yeah.
Hey, I noticed
the first time,
you promised me your honesty
and protection,
but not the second time.
No, because I vowed
to, uh, always be true
and to be your
constant champion.
It's the same thing.
I suppose.
You liked it better the first way?
Okay, we can go back to that.
Thanks.
You making
any changes?
Nope. Same old, same old.
.. J'J'
N Dah, dah, dah, dah.
Where's Alice?
Oh, upset stomach.
On the way home yesterday,
she snacked on t he leftover
petals in her basket.
Ble So, I'm sorry, but I won't be a
to join you for dinner
We understand.
Explain it to me then.
What sort of child eats roses?
This isn't normal
ROZ: You could've
stopped her, you know.
Not the way she was gnashing
them up, I couldn't.
Like a wood chipper, she was.
All right.
The incredible beaver baby.
We get it.
Oh, dear Lord
ls that Donny?
Everybody, look at your shoes.
Wait a minute.
Daph... is that Daphne?
Hi.
Donny.
What a surprise.
L-Ii, everybody.
Boy, I hope this isn't
uncomfortable.
Oh, no, no,
not at all
Uh, say, is that
a drinking fountain over there?
Sure looks
like one.
Well, Niles,
Daphne, I'd like you to meet
Bridget, my fiance.
Hi.
Hello.
We just filed
for our marriage license.
Congratulations.
That's great.
Thank you.
I know that
I was getting married
last time you ran into me,
but this time I found
the real thing.
Good, I'm glad.
Yeah.
You know,
if you hadn't left me,
then I never would've met
my ex-wife
who introduced me
to Bridget.
So, in a weird way,
you played a big part
in my eventual happiness.
That's a very
healthy perspective.
DONNY:
I think so, too.
So, what are you guys
doing here?
Niles and I
are getting married.
Well, congratulations.
That is great.
(chuckling)
Daphne.
Thank you.
Yes, well,
it's great.
And it's nice
seeing you.
And I hope you come
to our wedding.
Oh, same here.
Really, you'd be okay
with that?
Well, sure. Why not?
Of course, it's anybody's guess
how long we could be waiting here.
You can come in now.
Who had one second?
Uh, everyone, it's time
Oh, well, here we go, then.
This is Bridget.
Oh, lovely to meet you.
Hi,
nice to meet you.
Hi. Hi.
Hi.
Hi, how you doing?
Is this everybody?
Yes.
JUDGE: Let's get started.
We come here today to unite
this man and this woman
in marriage.
I understand
Daphne and Niles
have composed vows
that are especially significant
to them. Niles.
Yeah.
(clears throat)
Uh, I, Niles Crane,
take you, Daphne Moon,
to be my wife.
I-I vow to you my-
my fidelity and support,
honor, respect, uh, honesty...
Protection
...and support
Uh... you are my comfort
and joy and, oh...
Shoot, there's one more, uh..
One true love.
That's right,
that's right.
Go.
Okay, you
"Okay, you go"?
I, Daphne:"Moon, do
I'm sorry,
this is wrong.
I can't stand here
and rattle off a bunch of words
that don't mean anything
anymore.
I'm can't go through
with this.
DONNY:
Yes!
I knew it!
Now you know what it's like
to have the love of your life
dump you at the altar.
And good luck trying to find
somebody as good
because she just
ain't out there.
What?
No, no
No, Bridget!
Bridget!
(door closes)
I'm sorry, everyone,
but Niles and I,
we're already married.
What?
Mrs. Moon, I'm afraid it's
true.
Uh, Niles and Daphne
are already married,
and they were simply trying
to spare your feelings.
You knew about Reno?
FRASIER: I was talking
about yesterday.
What happened in Reno?
They gut married
yesterday?
This is all a lie?
No, yesterday was a lie.
We eloped last week.
I thought you had
to wait for the license.
That's why we went to Reno.
Why didn't you tell us?
We thought you'd be insulted.
I'm insulted now!
How could you tell Roz
and not your own family?!
How could you have two weddings
without telling your mother
about one?
How could you
cheat Alice
out of being
a flower girl?
We just wanted
to be married.
Hold on, I got a question here.
You've been married
for a week...
How come you're not
on your honeymoon?
Thank you... Martin.
I hope you can all forgive us.
Of course.
Well, of course we can. Of course.
Your happiness, that
's what's important.
This is such a relief.
It just felt wrong
to start off
a marriage with a lie.
Was the first one
at least in from of a minister?
of course
Yes, let's go.
Hey, baby, I hear
the blues a-calling
Tossed salads
and scrambled eggs
on, my
And maybe I seem
a bit confused
Well, maybe,
but I got you pegged
(laughs)
But I don't know what to do
With those tossed salad
and scrambled eggs
They're calling again
Good night!