Well, Roz, I think we have just
enough time for one more call.
Okay, we have Andy
from Bremerton on line three.
Hello, Andy, I'm listening.
MAN: Am I on?
- Yes, go ahead.
Can you hear me?
Yes, you're on the air.
- Hello?
- You're on.
- Am I on?
- Not anymore.
This is Dr. Frasier Crane on KACL
wishing you good mental health.
- Gather around, everyone.
FRASIER: Oh, Kenny, what's all this?
I'm here to officially announce
this year's SeaBea nominations.
- Ooh!
- Oh, well.
He made us wait until your show
was over. It was interminable.
First of all, KACL has been nominated
for a total of nine SeaBeas.
- Isn't that great?
WOMAN: Oh, that's great.
Which ties us with KPX,
the mighty PIXY
- for most nominations.
- The mighty PIXY, they do well.
All the nominees were chosen
by a panel of experts...
- Give me that.
- Good girl, Roz.
Oh, oh, here's one.
Best restaurant critic, Gil Chesterton.
Oh, congratulations, Gil.
Thank God I'm nominated.
And I won't have to attend
the Chestertons.
The Chestertons?
It's an elaborate awards show
my wife and the dogs put on
when I'm overlooked
by the SeaBeas.
Roz, I don't see our names
anywhere.
No, nothing.
We've been shut out. I can't believe it.
Well, what do I have here?
- There are more awards?
KENNY: Maybe.
I guess you'll just have to listen
and find out.
"Since 1962,
the Seattle Broadcasting Community..."
Give me that.
Oh, my God, Frasier, you're getting
the Lifetime Achievement Award.
What? Are you serious?
Give me that.
Hurts, doesn't it?
When I was a boy, my parents
told me to reach for the stars.
Sadly, I later learned that stars
are just massive, fiery balls of gas,
which, were I to reach one,
would vaporise me instantly.
But tonight,
with the Stephen R. Shafer
Lifetime Achievement Award,
you tell me
that I have reached you, and you,
ladies and gentlemen, are my stars.
And that's where
you would applaud.
I gotta say, Fras, it's really something,
you getting this award.
Yes, Dad,
it's actually quite an honour.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
You know, customarily they
give them out to much older people.
Oh, Niles. Flowers,
how very thoughtful of you.
- They're not from me.
- Well, thank you for bringing them up.
They were just outside the door.
Thanks for bending over
to pick them up.
- It wasn't that far. The handle sticks...
- Just give them to me.
"Congratulations, Frasier,
you must be very proud.
William Tewksbury."
- Who's that?
- It's my old mentor from Harvard, Dad.
Gosh, you know,
I read in the Alumni Newsletter
that he was taking his sabbatical here
at the University of Washington.
- I've been meaning to call him.
- Niles, there's something here for you.
For me? What for?
Well, this may be Frasier's night,
but I just want you to know
that I have two special sons.
Oh, well...
Dad, how considerate.
"World's Greatest Psychiatrist."
See, your brother's not the only one
getting a prize tonight.
Thanks, Dad.
Oh, there's my little rosebud.
Hello.
Is it my imagination, or has she
gained weight since breakfast?
Which seating, 8, 9 or 10?
Oh, darling, you're undone.
I know.
This dress used to fit perfectly.
Now I can't even get it zipped
halfway up.
Those bloody cleaners
must have shrunk it.
NILES:
Let me give it a try.
[NILES GROANS]
Oh, my.
Well, maybe if I put a jacket on.
Will you come help me pick one out?
Sure, sure.
You should switch dry cleaners.
That's the third dress
they've shrunk this week.
Dad, what do you make of this?
"Congratulations, Frasier,
you must be very proud."
Well, I'd say he's happy for you.
Of course, I was a detective,
so it comes easy to me.
He doesn't say he's proud of me.
He says that I should be proud
of myself.
- Doesn't that seem a bit odd to you?
- No, you're splitting hairs.
You don't know Dr. Tewksbury
like I do.
He wouldn't say something like this
unless he meant
to say something else.
You're gonna let this ruin
the night for you, aren't you?
No, no, of course not, Dad.
I just think it's interesting, that's all.
I'm gonna head over
the SeaBeas a little early.
- I'll see you there.
- Why?
Well, I thought I should familiarise
myself with the dais.
- Frasier, it's just a note.
- I know, Dad.
- It doesn't mean anything.
- Say hi to Dr. Tewksbury for me.
- I will, Dad.
Dr. Tewksbury?
Frasier Crane.
Of course.
- Frasier. Oh, it's good to see you.
- Likewise.
- How long has it been?
- Oh, gosh, l... Gee, perhaps 20 years.
- That long?
- Yes.
Actually, I was on my way
to the awards ceremony,
and I thought I'd drop by
and thank you for the flowers.
- And the card.
- You're welcome.
- It was very thoughtful of you.
- I was happy to do it.
- Particularly the card.
- I'm glad you liked it.
All right, let's cut the bull.
"You must be very proud."
Why not "I'm proud of you"?
Why speculation
rather than declaration?
- What?
- We both know there are no mistakes.
There must have been some reason,
either conscious or subconscious,
that you chose these words.
Frasier,
I have a confession to make.
- Ah.
- My assistant wrote the card.
Oh.
When I heard
you were getting an award,
I asked her to send flowers
with a note of congratulations.
I'm afraid you've been
over-analysing.
I see.
Then again, perhaps
in that order to your assistant,
you subconsciously
communicated an emotion
that you couldn't
or didn't want to acknowledge.
Or perhaps your subconscious
assigned new meaning
to the words to reflect
your own self-doubt.
But all art is self-portraiture,
and that includes the written word.
However, we can only view art
through the lens of our own psyches.
Then there is no pure art.
How would you know?
God, I've missed you.
Oh, Frasier.
Of course I'm proud of you.
Oh, thank you.
It's so nice to know that.
It really is. Thank you.
I really wish
we had more time to talk,
but I'm taking my wife out
to dinner tonight.
I wanna pick up some flowers
before the shops close.
Yes, yes, of course.
This time,
I think I'll write the card myself.
Yes, that's a good idea.
Gosh, it was great to see you again.
Yes.
- Let's get together some evening.
- Oh, I'd like that.
It's not often I get to dine
with the recipient
of a lifetime achievement award.
Please, it's just a trinket
for a little radio show I do.
Oh, not that by "little"
I mean to minimise my achievement.
- I know.
- I know you know.
I just wanna be clear,
so that you don't infer any meanings
that aren't actually there.
What might I infer?
Oh, that I'm somehow dissatisfied
with my work, something like that.
You also called the award a "trinket."
Can you imagine
what I might have done with that?
FRASIER:
Yes, exactly.
A lesser therapist might say
that I didn't think much of an award
that they're willing to give
to the likes of me.
Mm. I suppose if one
were looking hard enough,
one could even say
your coming down here
was a desperate quest for approval.
Oh, well, that one's
a little out there. Yes.
Frasier, you don't have to worry.
I'm not inferring anything.
Enjoy yourself this evening.
I will.
- Because tonight is my night.
- Yes.
- So long, professor.
- Goodbye.
Oh, Frasier.
[CHUCKLES]
Frasier?
What the hell is wrong with me?
Yes, dear,
I know we have reservations,
but one of my former students
is having a minor crisis.
I'll be there in half an hour.
What does it all mean?
Make it an hour.
- Hello, everybody.
MARTIN: Oh, hey, Roz. Whoa!
- You look great, Roz.
- Yeah. That's a beautiful dress.
Thank you,
and after two weeks of eating
delicious fat-burning cabbage soup,
it finally fits.
Niles made me cabbage
with me Osso Buco last night.
If I knew it burned fat,
I would have had a fourth helping.
- Well, we do have leftovers.
- No, we don't.
I haven't seen Daphne in a while.
Is it my imagination?
No. Six squares a day.
That's not like her.
Maybe she's depressed.
That's when I eat.
Have you said anything to her?
No. Timing is very delicate
in something like this, Roz.
I thought I'd wait until after she gets
too big to catch me,
but before she needs
the motorised scooter.
Hey, has anyone seen Frasier?
No, not yet.
What's the matter? You look pale.
Well, I hate public speaking,
and they roped me
into giving Frasier's introduction.
I just wanna make sure it's okay.
Why don't you run it by Niles?
He's a psychiatrist too.
And he's just as smart
and successful as Frasier.
- Dad.
- It's true. You are.
He is.
Hey, Gil.
So where is that elusive wife of yours?
If you must know, Deb's
on manoeuvres with her reserve unit.
WOMAN:
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to this year's
Seattle Broadcasting Awards.
Let's get right to our first category,
Outstanding Restaurant Critic.
And the nominees are:
Merrill George for Café Chat,
Sheldon Hastings
for Here's Looking at Food
and Gil Chesterton
for Restaurant Beat.
[CHEERING]
And we have a tie.
They expect me to share?
What is this, dim sum?
And the SeaBeas go to Merrill George
and Sheldon Hastings.
This can't be happening.
Oh, come on, Gil,
isn't it enough just to be nominated?
You tell me, Miss Three-Time-Loser.
MAN:
To all my listeners...
FRASIER: I know I should be happy,
but I feel so dissatisfied.
Well, Frasier, it's no accident
that you're going through this
on the day
that you receive
your lifetime achievement award.
Well, duh. I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm just acting out.
Please, please. Continue, please.
As you know,
men in our society commonly
define themselves by their careers.
Yes, I'll cop to that. Yeah.
In fact, there's nothing
I'm more proud of than my career.
It's because I love to help people.
I always have.
Right. Refresh my memory.
Wasn't it your mother
who first sparked
your interest in psychiatry?
Yes, it was.
I remember the exact day.
I was 8.
I had come home crying because one
of the older boys had thrown my copy
of The Fountainhead under a bus.
My mother explained to me
it wasn't because he didn't like
the way I walked,
or because
I wore an ascot to school.
It was because
he didn't like himself.
And at that very moment,
I became a student
of human behaviour.
It was as if someone had given me
an instruction manual
explaining why people
acted the way they did.
Not to mention a way to distance
yourself from painful emotions.
Oh, totally.
I took a lot of grief for that ascot.
So you were drawn to psychiatry
not because you like to help people,
but because you feared them.
I feared them?
Psychiatry gives you objectivity.
Objectivity gives you
emotional distance.
Distance makes you feel safe.
Yes, yes, granted.
But what has that got to do with me?
How's your practise?
I don't have a practise.
I have a radio show.
Distance. Any children?
Yes, I have a wonderful son
with whom I'm very close.
- You live with him?
- He lives in Boston.
Distance. With your wife.
My ex-wife. Yes, I know, distance.
Wasn't she a psychiatrist?
Yes, she happened
to be a good one too.
That's a handy choice
for someone
who'd rather share ideas
than emotions.
Have you ever met Lilith?
No.
Well, she happens to be a very warm
and loving woman.
Have you had any other meaningful
relationships since then?
As a matter of fact, l...
Well, what is your point?
My point is that at the age of 8, at 8,
you began to use psychiatry
as a way to deal with a world
that scared you to death.
And this lifetime achievement award
has made your realise
that your career is finite.
And once it's gone, all you'll have left
is that frightened 8-year-old boy.
Well...
Would you like to hear my theory?
You have no idea
what you're talking about.
I am not an 8-year-old.
And you know something else?
You're not my mentor anymore.
Roz, you gonna eat your quiche?
Are you kidding?
This would be like pulling
the ripcord on my thighs.
It's nothing but cheese
and butter and pastry...
And bacon.
Are you sure you don't mind?
I have good news.
I just spoke to Frasier.
He's on his way.
Oh, thank goodness.
Oh, not that I'm not having
a good time with you, Niles.
Dad, I know what you're doing.
You don't have to overcompensate.
I'm not some green-eyed monster
burning with envy for Frasier.
All right, but if you were,
I bet you'd be a great one.
Daphne?
I haven't seen you in a while.
How have you been? Are you okay?
I'm better than okay.
I'm in love with a man who loves me.
He showers me with attention.
Every morning I wake up wondering
what treasures this day will bring.
It really is the happiest time
of my life.
And how are you?
Good.
Really good.
Could you pass me
Frasier's quiche?
And the butter.
Thank you.
All right, I hate to be the one
to break it to you,
but I'm afraid you've lost your touch.
- Where's your DSM?
- There.
Emotionally stunted 8-year-old,
my eye.
Ah. Here's what I'm going through.
Phase-of-life issue.
"A problem associated
with a particular developmental phase
or other life circumstances."
- Please, a mid-life crisis?
- It's obvious, really.
I'm surprised
it didn't occur to me sooner.
If someone had called with
this problem, I'd have diagnosed it.
- Then what would you have done?
- Depends on the caller.
All right.
The caller is you.
Fine.
On line one,
we have Frasier Crane
from Seattle.
Hello, Dr. Crane.
I love your show. I'm a big fan.
I won't bore you with all the details
of my life because you know them.
Suffice to say,
I'm a successful psychiatrist.
My problem is that,
in spite of the life I've built,
I feel...
...empty.
Ah. Emptiness.
The eternal void.
If I'm not mistaken,
it was John Keats who wrote...
Stalling. Deal with the feelings.
All right, fair enough.
Perhaps, caller,
if we re-frame the issue, we can...
Redefining the problem.
Deal with the feelings.
Uh...
Let's run down
the Beck Depression Inventory...
Re-diagnosing.
You know what the problem is.
- The caller feels empty. Go on.
- Okay.
Last month,
in the New England Journal...
- He's already read it.
- How do you know?
The caller is Frasier Crane.
If you did, he did.
I can suggest certain
visualisation techniques...
He knows them already.
Look, if he knows all this,
then why is he calling?
He told you.
Because he's empty. Keep going.
Well, sometimes it helps
to write yourself a letter.
He's already got himself
on the phone.
But I don't know what he wants.
Then why do you keep trying
to bury him in psychiatric exercises?
Because that's all I have.
I'm sorry, caller.
I can't help you.
Frasier's up next,
and he's not here yet.
- What the hell am I gonna do?
- He'll be here in a minute.
- Just go up there and stall.
- Stall?
Stall?
Yes, like that.
WOMAN: Ladies and gentlemen,
our next presenter,
KACL General Manager
Kenny Daly.
I think I'm gonna be sick.
Oh, all right, relax.
I'll go up there for you.
No, no, Niles, let me do it.
This night's been hard enough
on you already.
You are such a weenie.
Yeah, weenie like a fox.
Actually, ladies and gentlemen,
I'm Martin Crane.
Kenny very kindly
let me do the honours.
You see, I'm Frasier's dad.
Oh, no, no, more than that,
I'm the father of two special guys.
So if it's okay with you,
I'd like you to give a big SeaBea
welcome to my other son, Niles.
Come on, Niles, stand up.
Let them see you.
Oh, here's Frasier.
[PEOPLE CHEERING]
Ladies and gentlemen,
I give you the winner
of the Stephen R. Shafer
Lifetime Achievement Award,
my son Frasier Crane.
Uh...
Thank you for honouring my life.
I just wish I knew what to do
with the rest of it.
[CHUCKLING]
What the hell was that?