Oh, don't you look nice?
Yeah, Frasier wanted me dressed up
for this mystery lunch of his.
He hasn't told you what
the occasion is, either?
No, but I'm sure
it's something very important.
I'm sure he
wants to unveil
his new antique
Elizabethan egg timer.
Yeah, or debut
his Precolumbian spoon rest.
Hello, all.
MARTIN:
Hey.
Well, Dad,
I see you're ready to roll.
Yeah. Can you
at least tell us
what kind of restaurant
you're taking us to?
Patience, Dad.
Roz'll be here in a few minutes,
then we'll be off
and all will be revealed.
So, how did it go
with the doctor?
Judging by that smile
on your face,
I'm guessing
your cholesterol's down.
Well, after several weeks
of watching my diet
and taking my medication
and race walking every Tuesday,
it hasn't budged.
The good news is, though,
that I've developed bursitis
to help take my mind off of it.
The doctor says it's all
just a matter of aging.
Well, no reason to let it
ruin our festive lunch.
Yeah... Boy,
you don't forget
that trip to the
doctor, do you?
That day he says, "There's
nothing I can do for you.
You're just getting old, sport."
In my case, it was "slugger,"
but that was the gist.
You know what I realize?
When people reach
our stage of life...
Dad, please,
with all due respect,
when it comes
to life's journeys,
you and I do not share a stage.
We're not even
in the same theater.
You're taking this all
very cheerfully, Dr. Crane.
(doorbell rings)
Well, why shouldn't I?
In many ways,
my life couldn't be better.
I mean, by and large,
I'm in good health.
There's a promising new
relationship on the horizon--
the lovely Rachel.
My career is thriving.
Did you say "thriving"
or "diving"?
What?
Look at these ratings.
Oh, Roz, that's nothing
to worry about.
For God's sakes,
they're just leveling off.
Yeah, that's what tends
to happen when you hit bottom.
There's no cause
for alarm here, Roz.
The important thing is that
we go on doing a quality show.
Hey, how about
some quality lunch?
Splendid idea, Dad.
Off we go, then.
Oh, uh, Niles will be
joining us there.
(cell phone rings)
Excuse me.
Hello?
Ah, Rachel, yes, uh...
momentito.
So, is Donny going
to be joining us?
No, he's got wedding business
this afternoon.
He's composing our vows.
Oh, isn't that romantic?
He's not exactly Wordsworth
strolling through a shady glen.
When I left, he was lying
on the couch in his underwear
with a tin of Vienna sausages
and a rhyming dictionary
on his chest.
Remember that new promising
relationship on the horizon?
Yeah.
It just got married
in Vegas last night.
(groans)
Great, then you don't have a
date for Daphne's wedding?
Oh, I'll find a date,
don't worry, Roz. Lunch awaits.
Hey, great.
Why don't we
go together?
No, Roz, I assure you.
My dance card
will be punched.
By who?
Well, I don't know
right now.
It's just that I will be
"Crane plus one."
Uh-huh.
Just in case
you don't get a date,
what time would you pick me up?
I'm getting a date.
Well, just in case.
What time are you
picking her up?
3:00.
Can you make it 3:30?
I'm getting a date!
(indistinct chatter)
DAPHNE:
So, what's the big occasion?
Wait for it, Daphne,
let the moment build.
Besides, Niles
hasn't arrived yet.
I'd be surprised
if he came.
He's terrified
of this place.
Still?
My God, it's been 30 years.
What happened?
Oh, Esther and I
brought the boys here
when they were kids, and
Niles was running around,
and he bumped into
the dessert trolley,
and Stefano got hot
and yelled at him,
and Niles got terrified
and he... well...
He vomited.
Right.
All over Stefano's shoes.
Then he ran out,
hid behind the car,
and he hasn't been
back in here since.
Poor little weenie.
Hey, Dr. Crane!
Buon giorno, buon giorno,
buon giorno!
Oh, good to see you,
Stefano. How are you?
Allow me to introduce
you to Daphne Moon...
STEFANO:
Yes, yes.
And my father, Martin,
you remember, of course.
Yes, hi, how are you?
This is...
Hey, we all know Roz.
All right.
For today, we've got
some special dishes.
For you, Dr. Crane--
porcini,
fresh from Napoli.
Oh.
And for me?
Giorgio, fresh from Sicily.
Can I get him to go?
You bet.
Okay, now, I'm going to be
waiting on you myself today.
You just give me a minute,
I come back.
Grazie.
(cell phone ringing)
Excuse me.
Hello?
Yes, hello, Niles.
Oh, really?
Oh, what a shame.
Told ya.
No, that's all right.
If your patient
is having a crisis,
you'd better address it...
before it turns into
a crippling, immature,
lifelong problem!
You're not really
mad at him, are you?
Well, of course,
I'm mad at him.
I'm certainly
going to give him
a piece of my mind
at dinner tonight.
Tonight?
Oh, I was hoping you could come
to Alice's birthday party.
My balloon animal guy canceled,
and I could really
use your help.
I'm sorry, Niles made
the reservations a month ago.
It's at Quelque Chose.
Fine.
Listen, if Niles
isn't coming,
maybe you can tell us
what the big surprise is.
Oh, all right,
I'll spill.
For over 60 years,
Stefano's has immortalized
Seattle's famous faces
on its walls,
as you can see.
With one notable exception.
It's me!
Stefano's unveiling
the portrait today.
Oh, how wonderful.
Hey, that's what I'll do
for Alice's party--
I'll get a cartoonist
to draw the kids.
That's an excellent idea, Roz,
but let's not forget
why we're here.
Does anybody have a toast?
Okay, Dr. Crane,
here it is.
My portrait?
No, it's today's specials.
Of course,
it's your portrait.
Would you like to say
a few words or something?
Well, uh, if you insist.
Before we unveil
this picture,
permit me to paint
one of my own.
A picture
of a young Frasier Crane,
wide-eyed, gazing at the walls
of Stefano's and wondering...
"Who's that?"
Well, little did I suspect
that one day my picture
would be on the wall,
and perhaps now
other children will come in,
gaze at it, and wonder...
"Who's that?"
I'm betting that's
going to happen a lot.
So, thank you, Stefano,
for this honor.
Thank you
for suggesting it.
And now...
may I present Il Dottore!
Dr. Frasier Crane!
(gasping)
Fras, will you let it go?
It's a perfectly
nice picture.
Oh?
So, nothing about it
jumped out at you
as, oh, I don't know...
encephalitic?
So they gave you a big
forehead. Who cares?
It makes you look smart.
It makes me look
like I discovered fire.
Frasier, I was just
leaving you a note
apologizing for
that flimsy excuse.
I'm sorry, just the thought
of going back to that place
got my stomach
doing flip-flops.
Yeah, yeah.
Come on in, Niles.
Oh, by the way, Daphne,
the doorman gave me this.
It's for you.
No, it's for Donny.
No, it's for
"Mrs. Donny Douglas."
Oh, funny, that's the first time
I've seen my name like that.
Well, get used to it.
That's you
in a couple of weeks.
So, how was lunch?
What was
the surprise?
Don't ask.
The less said, the better.
They put his picture
on the wall,
and he thinks his forehead
looks a touch too big.
A touch?!
I look like a fugitive
from Easter Island.
Frasier,
you always think
you look bad in pictures.
Niles, this is not
some photo I can
just throw away.
This is a picture of me
in a famous restaurant.
God, I dreamed my entire life
of being on that wall.
And now you are.
Are you really so vain
that that's not honor enough?
Vanity has nothing
to do with it.
It's about misrepresentation.
And you know, if I were you,
I would be careful
about bandying about
the word "vain,"
Mr. $250 Haircut!
I have problem follicles.
Frasier,
it's a caricature.
They exaggerate stuff.
Now, if it were me,
they would have drawn
maybe a big cane.
If it were Niles,
they'd draw a barber
cutting the hair
off a giant sucker.
I know you're sensitive
about your big forehead,
but we all have
stuff like that.
With me, it's my eyes.
I've always fancied
sparkling blue ones
instead of dull old brown.
Your eyes?
Your eyes are not dull.
Thank you, Dr. Crane.
That's very nice.
They're... they're...
warm and, uh...
...full of life.
You have beautiful
eyes, too.
Oh, goodness.
I can't be lolly gagging
around here, I have to...
to get Dr. Crane his oat bran.
Oat bran? Now?
You'll need it for the morning.
You've got to have
something to sop up
all that nasty cholesterol
gumming up your heart.
If not, I'm liable to come home
and find you face down
on the floor
with the dog
gnawing off your foot,
and I'm not making that up,
either. That happened.
Cheerio.
I wish she'd move that fast
when I'm out of beer.
Well, I should be off, too.
Are we still on
for dinner at Quelque Chose?
Oh, yes, yes,
of course, Niles.
You might want to call
and confirm.
Yes, I'll make a mental note.
Well, be careful
you don't lose it
inside that giant
puppet head of yours.
Good-bye, Niles!
Giant puppet head, indeed.
Oh, let it go, Frasier--
what are you going to do,
go down there
and make him change it?
Just accept it
for the honor it is,
that's all.
You know,
I don't get you.
A doctor gives you bad news,
you take it in stride
but one bad picture...
Yes, thank you, Dad.
Hello.
Yes, I'm calling
about a reservation tonight.
For two. Crane.
Well, what can I say,
but I just love
your food, Stefano.
I'm in the mood
for Italian.
Will you come along, Niles?
I'd really
rather not.
I'm feeling queasy
just standing here.
You can hardly see
the picture from there.
All right, let's just
be quick about this.
Hello, do you have
a reservation?
Uh, yes. For Crane.
One moment.
You tricked me.
We'll just be here long enough
for me to talk to Stefano,
convince him to change
the picture
so it doesn't mock me
for the rest of my life.
Frasier, the man
has a violent temper.
He's already made me
humiliate myself once.
Niles, I can't believe
you're letting a minor
childhood trauma
like this plague you.
I have a feeling this may be
the root of your fear
of authority figures.
Listen, a nice,
relaxing
dinner here may
go a long way
toward helping you
resolve this problem.
Dottore,
Dottore,how nice
to see you again.
Stefano, good to see you.
And who is
this gentleman?
He looks
familiar to me.
This is my
brother, Niles.
Of course, you have
the family forehead.
Come on.
Follow me.
Hey, Antonio, slow down!
(yelling in Italian)
What's the
matter with you?
Come on
sit down, we got
a nice table.
Oh, thank you.
Right under
your picture.
Okay, tonight,
no menus.
I'm going to take care
of everything.
Except the bill, of course.
(laughs)
Well, there it is.
Frasier Cranium.
Well, it does have
a certain under-nuanced
over-contoured...
Macy's parade
kind of quality, but...
even so, you cannot
ask him to change it.
The man will explode.
Not if I do it
with the utmost tact.
Okay...
here we are,
antipasto.
Oh...
Wonderful, Stefano.
You know, you certainly
do have a way
of making people
feel comfortable.
I suspect that it would
actually physically pain you
to think that someone
wasn't totally pleased.
What's wrong?
Mm-mmm.
Well, actually...
well, there is a...
a tiny, tiny problem.
It's really about
my picture, you see.
There is a small faction
that thinks the forehead
is too large.
What, this one?
No, I love it.
As do I.
It's just that, well, I...
I feel I might be
more recognizable
if the forehead
were a tad smaller.
So you don't like it?
It's not that.
It's not good enough for you?
Yes, it is.
You want me to have it changed?
Could you?
How long is this
going to take?
Now, Niles, I was
fortunate enough
that the artist is
actually here tonight.
I'm certainly not
going to rush him.
Now, you better
finish your lasagna.
You don't want
to offend Stefano.
Offend him?
So far tonight I have had
the prosciutto di Parma,
the pesto Genovese
and the Venetian sea bass.
One more bite,
and we'll conclude
our little tour of Italy
with my impression of Pompeii.
Hey, hey,
look who it is.
They'll let anyone
in this joint.
Hello, Kenny.
So what are you celebrating?
Not your ratings, huh?
I'm kidding!
You got to kid.
If you don't laugh,
you cry, right?
So, did I hear a rumor
you're going up
on the wall of fame?
Oh, yes.
As a matter of fact,
they're putting
the finishing touches
on the picture right now.
Isn't that
something?
Hey, hey, hey, you
better save some room.
Stefano goes crazy
if you pass
on his dessert.
My mother found that out
the hard way
on her 80th birthday.
He went off on her.
Called her a...
skoonja-boonja or something.
The kids had it memorized
for a while.
Well, enjoy.
STEFANO:
Okay, Dr. Crane.
Hot off the easel.
Is this one more
to your liking?
Oh, my.
Is it better?
Well, it's like
looking in a mirror.
Okay, that's what
I want to hear.
You know, this is the first time
that anybody's ever
asked for a change.
Beautiful.
You make me so happy.
I'm going to see how
the steaks are coming.
Thank you.
Frasier, I hate
to burst your bubble,
but that picture looks
absolutely nothing like you.
Well, well...
I was wondering when Mr. Envy
would pull up a chair.
Ah, Kenny, Kenny.
If I may, can I direct your
attention to this caricature?
Wow, look at that.
I am impressed.
I thought you might be.
James Garner eats here?
James Garner?
Well, I guess
I can go sit down now.
My father-in-law
just picked up the check.
I don't believe this.
I've waited
my entire life
to have my picture
on this wall.
Now that it is,
it's unrecognizable.
Well, not for long.
No. Frasier,
you are not
going to ask him
to change it again.
Niles...
if this means
so much to you,
my girlfriend
is a plastic surgeon.
She can have you looking
like this picture
in six procedures or less.
All right,
here we are, boys, here we are.
Mangia bene.
Whoa!
Thank you.Grazie.
You know, there's
been something
that's been bugging
me all night.
Hey, shove over, will you?
I know you
from someplace,
and I can't
figure out where.
And it's driving me
pazzo.
So, we got to figure
this out together, okay?
You and me, all right?
You know,
while you two
are strolling down
memory lane,
I have a quick errand
I have to run.
I tell you what.
Save some dessert
for me.
Frasier, Frasier...
Uh, Roz...
Frasier, I knew you'd show up.
Yes, well, of course.
You knew how much it would
mean to me and Alice.
Oh, gosh, am I
that transparent?
Come on in.
Everybody, this is Frasier.
Hello, hello. Hi.
Can I get you something?
Jell-O? Lunchables?
Pokemon punch?
Do you have any coffee made?
No.
That's perfect.
I mean, while you're making
coffee, it'll give me some
quality time
with Alice.
Hey, no cuts.
I need
a picture right away.
I'll tell.
Do you know
who this is?
This is the birthday girl.
If she wants a picture
right away,
she's gonna get a picture
right away.
Now why don't you run along?
All right, I think
you're finished.
Here we are.
But I don't have any eyes.
Yes, well,
neither did
Little Orphan Annie
and she's got her own
Broadway show. Now, go on, shoo.
Okay, fine.
I'm looking for something manly.
Go easy on the forehead
and leave the kid out.
Niles.
Where the hell
have you been?
Stefano's been
trying to place me
for the last 40 minutes.
Was I ever in Panama?
Did I sell him
his first Lincoln?
Do I have a box
at the dog track?
Why don't you
just say "yes"
and let that be
the end of it?
Oh, that's a good idea.
What's that?
I went by Alice's
birthday party.
I had the artist there
draw me some new sketches.
Here. What do you think?
(gasps):
I think you're insane.
No, Niles,
it's not so crazy,
really, just imagine.
Suppose that picture there
should accidentally
drop to the floor
and tear.
You see, I could come
back here tomorrow
tell Stefano
that I didn't want
to put his artist
to any more trouble
and I had a new
caricature done myself.
You see, I'm actually
partial to this one here.
But there is one in here
of me playing soccer
which is very good.
Frasier...
we'll put these away,
and we'll pay the bill
and we'll find a bed
to strap you into.
No, no, no, Niles.
This can work. It really can.
I promise you,
it can work.
What is this?
The pictures?
It's nothing, it's no business
of yours. Off you go.
Stefano.
Shh.
Stefano!
Mama, what is it?
(speaks Italian)
Dr. Crane,
what is this?
Oh, all right.
I may as well just
tell you the truth.
The fact is, I don't really
care for this picture, either.
It's just that
I'm afraid
your artist has
lost his touch.
To be honest, I think
he's robbing you blind.
I mean, my God, how much
is this hack charging you?
(cries)
Mama, Mama.
Mama's the hack, isn't she?
That's right.
(yelling in Italian)
Son of a gun,
get out of here!
And don't ever
come back!
(yells in Italian)
You, hold on one second.
Now... I remember you.
Oh...
Bridgeport, Connecticut.
Yes. Yes.
Right.
Yes.
My car got stuck in the rain
and you saved my ass.
Yes, well, it was nothing.
Glad you remembered.
Let me show you
how we thank you
where I come from.
Well, suffice it to say,
that the entire
Crane family
is now banned
from Stefano's.
Just 'cause of
that dumb picture?
No, no, actually
there was a little incident
involving Niles, too.
He was doing just fine
until Stefano took him
in some sort of a bear hug
and shook him
a little too vigorously.
On the shoes again?
No, this time there was
a conveniently placed
lobster tank.
Poor Niles.
Yeah.
Wasn't any picnic
for the lobsters either.
What the hell is wrong
with me, Dad?
I became so obsessed
with that damn picture
I completely lost my head.
Well, I think I know
what's really going on here.
Really?
Well, enlighten us.
Well, I think there's
some stuff in your life
that you can't control.
Your doctor tells you
you're getting old.
Your ratings are low.
You're not happy
with your love life.
And so I think you obsessed
about this picture
because you figured it was
something in your life
that you could control.
Well, Dad, you do raise a point.
Oh, what the hell,
you're dead on.
Where'd you learn so much
about psychology?
Oh, I listen to radio.
Gosh, it's so obvious, isn't it?
You know, when a person
is confronted
with some deeply troubling issue
that they're not
ready to face yet
they usually avoid the problem
by obsessing
about something else--
something completely trivial.
Got it.
Got what?
Dr. Crane's oat bran.
God, you left for that
eight hours ago.
Well, it wasn't easy.
They were out of it
at the regular market
so I went
to another one.
But they
were out of it
so I looked into it
and it turns out
they don't sell it
in Washington anymore.
Well, for some reason,
I just couldn't let it go.
So I went for a little drive.
It wouldn't kill you
to do something like
that once in a while.
Get off that big, round
duff of yours.
Anyway... hop, skip
and a jump later...
here it is.
Fresh from Portland.
Well, off to bed.
Good night.
What the hell was that?
I don't know,
what did she mean
about that "big,
round duff" comment?
Now, Dad...
You know, the sands of time
don't exactly flow up
the hourglass.
It's not easy for a guy our age.
Dad, for the last time,
we are not the same age.
I mean, I've seen your
hips start to spread...
For Pete's sake, my hips
have nothing to do with this...
♪ Hey, baby,
I hear the blues a'callin' ♪
♪ Tossed salads
and scrambled eggs ♪
♪ Mercy ♪
♪ And maybe
I seem a bit confused ♪
♪ Well, maybe,
but I got you pegged ♪
(laughing)
♪ But I don't know what to do ♪
♪ With those tossed salads
and scrambled eggs ♪
♪ They're callin' again. ♪
Thank you!