- You could live here.
- Are you asking me?
- Would you like to?
- Would you like me to?
- Yeah.
- Then I will.
I gave the greatest speech
of my condo-board career,
which lead to a vote, which lead
to the ruling that Cam Winston
must now park that SUV monstrosity
of his in the sub-basement.
You think that's smart, ticking off
the guy who lives right above us?
- Well, the move's off.
- What?
Just temporarily.
My parents are coming for a visit.
Just to clarify,
you're going to stay here,
but your parents
are going to stay with me.
I'm so glad you understand.
If she thinks you're a virgin,
how are you going to explain
our plan to live together?
I wonder how important it is
that she ever finds out.
- Dad scarpered.
- He left?
SIMON: Yeah.
- It's true.
Thank goodness I have my children
to lean upon.
Oh, don't cry, Mum.
I really thought this junket to America
would cheer you up.
It still can.
Get out there and see the country.
Yes, immerse yourself in the spectacle
and the grandeur
that are these United States,
this America.
How did you do that?
Cam Winston!
It was a good idea,
taking Mum out today.
- Helped take her mind off Dad.
- Yeah.
Though I'm not sure the zoo
was the best idea.
The sight of those amorous wolverines
seemed to set her back a bit.
Amorous? I thought
they were trying to kill each other.
Well, either way,
it seemed to remind her of something.
Hello, Mrs. Moon.
Would you care for a bite to eat?
Oh, that would be lovely, if I thought
I could keep anything down.
How could your father do this to me?
You sleep down the hall from someone
for 40 years,
you think you know them...
I know you're upset, Mum,
but it's not like you and Dad
had a perfect marriage.
That's because
there's no such thing.
You young, modern people
think marriage is some sort of
promenade through paradise,
Yeah, obviously this is
a very upsetting time for all of us.
But remember,
tomorrow is another day.
You're right, dear.
And the sooner you get home to bed,
the sooner it'll be here.
But it's only 9:30.
And with every tick of the clock,
your womanly resistance weakens.
And before you know it,
he'll be on top of you
like one of those bloody badgers
at the zoo.
Actually, those were wolverines,
and there's a chance
they may have been fighting.
It has been a long day.
Maybe it's best if I leave.
- All right.
- Yeah.
I'll see you tomorrow, Mum.
- Good night, Niles.
- Good night.
Well, hey, you still up?
Can't sleep.
Every time I look outside,
I feel like I'm living inside
a giant clown's pocket.
I tell you, Cam Winston
has not heard the last of this.
I am calling an emergency meeting
of the condo board tomorrow morning.
You can't fight this, Fras. It'll just
look like you're attacking the flag.
I'm not attacking the flag.
Cam is using the flag to attack me.
You're right,
but you're still gonna lose.
But the building has bylaws
about this sort of thing.
If this was anything
but the American flag,
people would demand
that it be taken down.
Face it, Fras,
Cam's got you on this one.
- Boy, I have to say, that guy is smart.
- Oh, really?
If he's so smart and you're so smart,
why don't you two live together?
At least he's got a view.
What on earth
do you think you're doing?
Oh, sorry.
I didn't know you was here.
Oh, Frasier, this is Loretta.
Loretta...
Well, you know who you are.
[LAUGHING]
[GASPS]
I love your curtains.
I'm sorry, but we are not
entertaining guests this evening.
You'll have to leave.
Wait. You told me
this was your place.
You're probably
not even the duke of England.
Oh, yeah?
Then why do I talk this way?
Well, you're just a big contraceptive,
aren't you?
I've just about had it
with you, Simon.
You have blown my speakers,
you have clogged my Jacuzzi
and you have ingested
half of my bath products.
You are no longer welcome
in my home.
- What exactly are you implying?
- Get out!
Fras, you can't throw him out.
Where's he gonna go?
Oh, he'll land on his feet.
Probably end up shacking up
with some two-bit floozy.
Simon.
- What are you doing here?
- Hello, love.
It appears that the front door
to the building is locked.
Yeah, that's how we keep drunks
from wandering in.
Well, I seem to be without appropriate
accommodation at the moment.
I just thought I'd take you up
on your kind and generous offer.
I never said you could stay here.
Well, Frasier's thrown me out.
All right, well,
sleep in Martin's Winnebago.
Well, wouldn't I love to do that,
but when I got down there,
there was this gigantic Humvee
blocking the door.
Simon, this isn't my problem.
- Well...
- You have got to go.
Look, Roz, I'll level with you.
I know that we've had
a chequered history,
and I'm probably not the sort of person
that you'd want in your house.
But I'm asking for your help.
As a friend. As Daphne's brother.
Please, just let me stay one night.
You won't even notice me.
Just the tiniest spot on the floor
would be a gift.
Look, I'll be gone in the morning.
I'll never darken your doorstep again.
Please, Roz,
I've got nowhere else to go.
All right.
I'll make up the couch for you.
Oh, thank you, Roz.
You have got a good heart.
Yeah.
Climb on up, Suzy. We're golden.
[SIMON LAUGHS]
She can swing on a pole
for two hours,
but she can't climb up a drainpipe
to save her life.
Hey, what...?
Heads up, Suzy!
Two, please.
Thank you.
[LAUGHS]
Well, show us what you got.
I've got a king, a jack,
a ten and two sixes.
- Two sixes, then.
- And a king.
I'm sorry, love.
I've got aces over deuces.
Well, that's the last of
my mad money.
I guess I'll have to win it back
some other night.
You better make it soon.
I won't be around much longer.
Not if you keep biting those filters off,
you won't.
No. I mean I'll be going back
to England soon.
Well, it's nice enough here.
But you and Daphne aren't
the most exciting people, are you?
No, as soon as I've sorted myself out,
Simon and I are back on the plane.
Really? You are?
Uh, can I do anything to help sort?
Thank you, no.
Oh, the shock's worn off, really.
And I've come to realise
I've spent most of my life
taking care of a layabout husband.
Well, now it's my turn
to be taken care of.
Thank God I've got Simon.
- Simon's gonna be taking care of you?
- Oh, of course he will.
I know he plays the fool sometimes,
but he'd never let me down.
Well, you've made a lot of progress
in a short amount of time,
and I can't tell you how happy I am.
Oh. Heh.
You good for a few more hands?
Why not? Oh, I'm out of money.
Oh, not to worry.
We can play for rubs.
Oh! I'll get my coin collection.
[BLOWING]
Still awake, Dr. Crane?
Yes.
It's almost dawn's early light,
and our flag is still there.
Daphne,
as a subject of the British realm,
does it make you feel uncomfortable
to have your residence draped
in the American flag?
And, if so, would you be willing
to say that at a condo-board meeting?
Personally, I find it a cosy reminder
of the land I dreamed of living in
as a child.
Off I go.
Simon, I thought
Dr. Crane kicked you out.
- He did. You don't see me.
- What are you doing here?
Well, I'm just getting
some provisions for my trip.
What trip?
Well, I just thought I'd go
meet some mates in California.
You can't run out on Mum.
She's counting on you.
She's got the other boys back home.
They've all sided with Dad.
You know that.
You're all she's got.
I'm not cut out to take care of Mum.
She's too demanding.
She turned Dad
into a shiftless drinker.
I can't have her doing that to me.
So you're gonna leave in the middle
of the night and not even tell her?
Look, if you wanna take care of Mum,
that's your choice,
but I've got to live my life.
You are so selfish.
For once in your life,
you have a chance to be responsible.
Be a man. Do right by your family.
Why don't you think about that
before you go flitting off to California?
I'm sorry, Daphne.
Maybe it makes me a bad person,
but I don't have it in me.
It's not who I am.
I'll see you.
[KNOCKING]
Wait, wait, wait, quiet, quiet.
Don't wake your mother.
I just got her down.
What are you doing here?
Something terrible has happened.
Simon's left.
- What do you mean, left?
- He's gone.
He's left me to take care of Mum.
I don't know what I'm gonna do,
but I may have to go back
to Manchester with her for a while.
- No, you can't. You have a life here.
- Well, what am I supposed to do?
I can't have her stay at Dr. Crane's.
There's no room.
Well, you can both live here.
Oh, Niles, you know she'll never
go for that arrangement.
NILES:
Mm...
A bit late at night for a single lady
to be in a man's home, isn't it?
I'm here because Simon's left.
Off to California,
to do God knows what.
Oh.
Well, that's courageous.
Good to see him
finally taking charge of his life.
He's not taking charge.
He left because he doesn't
wanna take care of you.
That is not so. Simon is a special boy.
He wasn't meant to be kept at home.
He has dreams.
You wouldn't understand that.
Now, you listen to me, Mum.
In case you haven't noticed,
I've got dreams too.
I even moved halfway across the world
to make a life for myself.
Do you admire that?
No, you don't even acknowledge it.
Oh, and by the way, I'm no virgin.
Haven't been for years.
You remember that boy with
the lazy eye you hated so much?
Yeah, he was my first.
Did it right in the parlour
where you take your tea.
Then there was the German
who fixed Dad's car.
Oh, yeah,
and that Irish chap I fancied
who was twice my age
and had his own van and a band.
Then I came to America.
Shall I go on?
Well, I am a grown woman
who's made her own life
and her own decisions.
Now, I plan to shack up
with Niles here,
and damned if we aren't gonna do it
every night of the week.
Now, that's the way
it's gonna be, Mum,
and if you don't like it,
that's just tough.
Is that so?
Well, if that's how you repay me
for all my sacrifice...
- Oh, don't even start.
- Fine.
Just for that, I'm not spending
another night under this roof.
I intend to fetch my things,
find a hotel
and be on the first flight
home tomorrow.
Excuse me.
Oh, my God, look at me.
I'm shaking.
It just came gushing out.
- Once I started, I couldn't stop.
- I know, it's all right.
You were great. You were great.
I have never been prouder of you.
I can't believe I talked
to my mother that way.
You must have been pretty outraged to
have invented all those former lovers.
- What? Oh, yes, right, of course.
- All those former lovers... Yeah.
I'm actually surprised
she's leaving so easily.
I thought she'd milk it a bit more.
Just so you know,
I won't be needing a lift to the hotel.
- I shall call a taxi.
- Whatever you want.
You'll see.
I don't need any of you rotten ingrates.
- I can take care of myself.
- Glad to hear it.
Ow. Ow...
DAPHNE: What happened?
- Ow.
NILES: Oh, oh, oh, are you hurt?
- Oh, of course I'm hurt.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, get me ice.
- All right, all right, all right. Okay.
- And whisky.
Not that cheap stuff.
- I don't know how I'm gonna fly now.
- Sit down.
The pain is unbearable.
Though I know I'm not welcome here.
Oh, I can't say I blame you.
No sense burdening yourself
with an old woman.
Who can't take care of herself.
And has nowhere else to go.
Oh, don't be silly.
You can stay here
as long as you like.
Well, move along.
The whisky's not pouring itself.
Are we fiercely patriotic? Yes.
But how do we best
demonstrate that?
Not by infringing on the rights
and balconies of others,
but as most good Americans do,
in our hearts, with generous spirit
and quiet reverence.
I respectfully submit
that when we display the flag
as Mr. Winston has,
it flies in the face of the very freedoms
for which it stands.
Thank you.
Cam, rebuttal?
Uh, the last thing I wanted
was to create conflict.
I was merely trying to boost
the morale of the community.
And so you have.
[CHATTERING]
I move that the flag stays.
All right, all right, very well, then.
But perhaps we could display it
on the north side of the building
for the benefit
of our Canadian neighbours.
That was my first instinct,
but it can't be illuminated at night
from that side.
- Lighting is a must.
- Absolutely.
MRS. RICHMAN:
Then it's settled.
All right, just hold on a second!
You people are being hoodwinked.
The only reason Cam hung that flag
was to get the better of me.
He knows I bought the apartment
for its view.
No, you bought that apartment
because you're free.
Maybe you can have a view
from your balcony in Iraq.
Yes, move to Iraq.
[IN UNISON]
Move to Iraq. Move to Iraq.
- Move to Iraq.
- Wait. Wait!
I am just as much an American
as every one of you.
Perhaps Cam could just tell us
how long he intends
to display our beautiful flag.
CAM:
Hmm.
How about until there's world peace?
Oh, that's a good idea.
Oh, come on.
There's never gonna be world peace.
[CROWD SHOUTING]
Maybe there would be world peace
if there were more people like Cam
and fewer people like you.
Oh, now, just a second...
[SINGING]
O beautiful, for spacious skies
For amber waves of grain
For purple mountain majesties
Above the fruited plain!
America...
- All right, what do you want?
- Your parking spot.
You'll make all this stop?
Well, there is the matter of the flag.
I can't just take it down now.
All right, suggest the roof.
I'll even spring for the flagpole.
[SINGING]
From sea to shining sea
Everyone. Hey, everyone. Everyone.
The America we love
is one of good neighbours.
In order to foster that,
I have decided to move my flag
to the roof.
[CHATTERING]
This will not only serve
to mend fences,
but it will provide all of Seattle
a view of our precious
Stars and Stripes.
[CHATTERING]
- You've done it again, Cam.
- He certainly has.
And in the spirit of reciprocity,
I will provide the flagpole. Ha-ha-ha.
And any necessary lighting.
Ha-ha-ha.
Credit grabber.
Oh, come on,
we're all in agreement here.
[SINGING]
O beautiful, for spacious skies
Come on, everybody.
For amber waves of grain
Oh, all right, I'll see you next week.
Ah. How'd things go at the doctor?
Couldn't find anything wrong
with the knee. Big surprise.
Then why did they give me
sedatives, smarty?
Because I begged him.
- Oh, fetch me my water.
- Oh, I'll get it.
I know how she likes it.
Oh, but I know
where the glasses are.
- I am so sorry about this.
- It's all right. We'll manage.
I can live with anything,
as long as I can live with you.
GERTRUDE:
I'm still waiting out here.
It's coming. Pipe down.
Why?
Am I interrupting your dirty sex?
It's gonna be interesting,
the three of us living together.
Daphne, this is stupid.
We should just wait till she's gone.
No, I said I was moving in,
and I'm going to.
It took your whole life to assert
your independence from this woman.
I can't ask you to live
under the same roof.
- I can't ask you to live with her either.
- Oh, well, it's just temporary.
And you know what? She bothers you
a lot more than she bothers me.
GERTRUDE: Don't empty the sink,
I'm soaking my smalls.
Well, ahem, we waited this long.
- I love you, Niles.
- Mm. I love you too.
And I promise, as soon as she's
on a plane for England, I'm here.
Mrs. Moon, did the doctor
mention anything
about when you'd be able to fly?
No, didn't say a word about flying.
That's probably a bad sign, eh?
Yeah.