Good morning  ..
Good morning
I'd like a bagel, too .
And schmear it with cream cheese
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Excuse me!
Did it occur to you
that some of us might
still be trying to sleep?
Oh, lighten up, Fras.
Ronee was just showing me
how she can change the lyrics
to any song to suit the occasion.
Yes, very impressive.
Does she take requests?
Sure.
Stop it.
You know what you need, Grumpy?
A nice hot breakfast.
Marty, why don't you get
Grump here some breakfast?
I don't want any breakfast.
And please stop calling me that.
?? Got me some ham and
some cake on the griddle??
?? whoo! Good God, he's a grumpy boy.??
(laughing)
You see what she just did?
Yes, it's mind-boggling.
Listen, Dad, do you mind
giving me a ride to work today?
My car is in the shop.
Again?
Yes, my seat warmer's stuck on high.
So I tried to offset it by
blasting the air conditioner,
which resulted in sort of
a fog bank on my dashboard.
I can give you a ride, Fras.
It's just an old Caddy,
so there's nothing fancy like
butt warmers or seat belts.
Fine. Let me just make
sure my will is in order,
and I'll be back in a minute.
well, I'm going to take a shower.
Don't use all the hot water.
I know. Gotta leave
enough for milady's tub.
That's okay. I can take a shower, too.
I wasn't talking about you.
(phone rings)
Hello?
Oh, Richard, hi.
Listen, this really isn't a good time.
I was just heading into a yoga class.
Yeah. No. I would love to have dinner.
That sounds fun.
Okay, I'll see you then, sweetie.
You know, I got two steps in my room
and realized I forgot my...
Ah, there it is.
(to the tune of "There
She Is, Miss America ")
?? There it is??
?? Frasier's coffee cup...??
You are a national treasure.
Niles, thank God you're here.
Listen, there's something
I need to discuss.
wait, wait, wait.
I'm in the middle of composing a plea
to Alfred Antin in
the meter of Dr. Seuss.
who?
Theodor Geisel, the children's author.
You know, "I do not
like green eggs and ham,
I do not like them, Sam I Am. "
Yes, I know who Dr. Seuss is, you ninny.
who's the other guy?
Oh, oh. Alfred Antin.
He's Seattle's premier scenic painter
specializing in children's rooms.
His billowing clouds can be seen
scudding across the ceilings
of the finest nurseries in town,
but he's booked solid,
.. so I thought if I wrote this.
Oh, you've lost interest , haven't you?
I was feigning interest to begin with.
Niles, I need your advice on something.
This morning I heard Ronee on the phone
make a date with another man.
Are you sure?
well, I'm positive
she was talking to a man,
yes, and in honeyed tones.
Mm.
Here's my predicament.
I don't want to meddle,
but I also don't want
to see Dad get hurt.
So how do you suggest we tell him?
"we"? Yes, "we. "
Don't drag me into this. I
don't know a thing about it.
You know as much as I
do. I just briefed you.
I didn't want to be briefed.
Then you should have said something.
Now you're in as deep as I am.
You can't unscramble an egg, Niles.
what are you talking about?!
Oh, boys, boys, boys.
I'm glad I caught you.
Did you see this?
"Doo-wop-alooza
"?
Yeah, one night only.
All the greats of doo-wop:
The Coasters, The platters,
and that guy from The Teenagers
is back from his hip replacement.
wow.
Yes.
Oh, I know you guys aren't
interested in modern music,
but Ronee would really love it.
I was hoping maybe you
could use your connections
to maybe score us a couple of seats.
I'm afraid I'm not
that well-connected to
the doo-wop world, Dad.
If there's ever a Mahler
- palooza, I'm your man.
Dad, I'll ask around.
win I'm off to try to
the heart and mind of A. Antin.
I'll go and meet him with my Daphne
and hope that things
don't go ker-phaphne.
Sorry again about this morning
me and Ronee waking you up.
we were just having a little fun.
It's all right. It's great t
have a fling once in a while.
Hey, let me tell you something:
you don't go to
Doo-wop-alooza with a fling.
I see.
You got something you want to say, son?
No.
Fine.
well, all right,
if you insist on dragging it out of me.
Something happened this morning, Dad.
what?
well, I was
walking down the hall
to retrieve my coffee
and Ronee was on the phone,
and I didn't want to
interrupt so I waited.
And I heard her make a...
a date with another man.
So you eavesdropped, huh?
No.
A person's having a
private conversation,
you stop and listen--
that's eavesdropping.
Dad, it was completely by accident.
I understand why you'd be upset,
but please don't shoot the messenger.
well, the messenger's got it coming
if he's a dirty little eavesdropper.
You walk into a private conversation,
you make your presence
known by some subtle way.
You can clear your
throat. (clears throat)
You can make a noise.
Dad, please!
You know, just because people call in
for your precious pearls
of wisdom on the radio,
doesn't give you a free pass
to get into everybody's business.
Now I know why you 're always
saying, "I'm listening. "
Because you always are.
(laughing)
Oh, well, I'm glad the two
of you found that so amusing,
but as you've just heard,
it is rude to listen in
on other people's conversations.
(doorbell rings)
Oh, Niles, come on i n. Hey, Frasier.
Hi. I'm just here to drop off
these Doo-wop-alooza
tickets for Dad.
Oh, well, that's good
luck. How did you manage it?
well, actually,
Alfred Antin and his
wife are big doo-wop fans,
and the, uh, the couple
that was going with them canceled,
so-so they let...
they let me have the tickets.
what are we looking for?
well, my money clip. Have you seen it?
Rarely.
I've misplaced it,
and it's-it's distracting me no end.
well, anyway, Dad was thrilled
when I told him I found the tickets.
Oh, well, I'm glad to hear that.
He was just a bit vexed
when he left me earlier this morning.
Over what?
Frasier,
you told him about Ronee's date.
As we agreed.
"we"?
Yes, "we. "
" . There's no "we. "
There's never been a "we
Oh, give it up, Niles.
There's blood on both our hands.
Oh, gosh, I better go eat something.
I've got my reading in 20 minutes.
Reading? Yes.
Yes. I'm, uh, reciting "Annabelle Lee"
for the poe Society this evening.
I-I don't mind telling you
, I'm just a bit nervous.
Oh, don't worry.
po' folk don't'spect much.
(laughing)
I had to say that.
well, I'm off.
Yes.
(door opening)
(door closing)
It's this amazing doo-wop show.
All the greats, one
night only, this Sunday.
RONEE: Sunday? I...
God, I'm sorry. I-I... I made plans.
Oh, plans, huh?
Uh... what kind of plans?
Look, Marty, I like you
too much to lie to you. I...
I have a date.
Oh, oh.
well, that's no problem. Yeah.
Uh, you want a drink?
Oh, no, I better not.
I'm working. Just a beer.
You're not upset, are you?
I mean, you know, we never really talked
about not seeing other people.
Oh, no, that's fine. No, no.
I'm seeing other people, too.
Maybe I'll ask, uh...
Sheila.
Yeah. She'll be all over this one.
(Ronee laughs)
So, uh...
how about another night?
Yeah, sure. How's... what about Tuesday?
Great. Great.
RONEE: wow, I had no
idea it was this late.
So I'll call you about Tuesday.
Great.
(sighs)
Frasier, what are you doing?
I didn't know you two were home.
Uh...
I was just, uh, cleaning the oven.
I must have dozed off.
Cool.
well, got to run. Good night, you two.
Yeah. See ya.
You have a disease!
please.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Let me explain, all right?
There's nothing to explain.
I told you not to eavesdrop,
and you did it again.
You are a very sick person.
I tried to announce myself,
but I had a mouth full of apple,
rendering me speechless.
Oh. I was a cop. You think I
haven't heard that one before?
You're just angry
because I heard you lying to Ronee.
You really expect to win Ronee's heart
by inventing fictitious girlfriends?
Sheila indeed.
well, that's none of your business,
and you weren't supposed to hear it.
well, I did hear it.
No, you overheard it.
It's like an illegal
wiretap. It's inadmissible.
. Dad, you cannot build
a relationship on lies
Inadmissible. Dad...
Inadmissible!
Oh, fine.
(door slams)
why can't your father
just go to the concert by himself?
Because Alfred Antin will be offended
if we don't us e his tickets
and then he won't paint our nursery.
Don't you want to be
the one to go with him?
Forget it, Niles.
we flipped a coin and you
were the doo-wop-a-loser.
Hey, Niles.
Ready to
bop-bop- she-bop?
Oh, dear God. Is it a dance?
Am I going to have to move about?
No, you don't have to,
but you're going to want to
Daphne?
I'm pregnant.
what does that have to do with it?
It's my blanket excuse
until the baby is born.
After that it'll be, "I
can't leave the baby. "
Get used to it.
Oh, Marty, hi.
Ronee, hey.
Oh, this is Richard.
Martin, Daphne, Niles.
Hello, Richard. Hi.
Hello.
So how do you all know each other?
well, uh...
Ronee was my baby-sitter.
I was a little monster.
And you?
Um...
Sheila! where have you been?
This is my date, Sheila.
Got stuck at work, huh?
Uh, yeah?
Yeah.
Sheila's a model.
She does all those
big auto and R V shows.
point to something.
wow, impressive. Nice meeting you.
Let's get ours to go.
But I thought...
Roll with the punches, Dick.
what are you doing?
I'm trying to make her jealous.
Just go with it.
But I'm meeting my own date here.
Dad, the concert starts in 1 5 minutes,
and Alfred Antin will be
very angry if we're late.
well, I can't leave unless
Sheila comes with me.
Hello? Sheila has a date.
Here are the tickets.
You and I are going.
Oh, do we have to?
Yes.
Do we really need clouds on the ceiling?
Couldn't we just push the
crib closer to the window?
why even use a crib?
Let's just put it in a pizza box.
(laughing loudly)
Stop it.
Oh, you! work with me here.
Okay, okay.
Roz?
Larry. Hi.
This is my dad.
How you doing?
Hello.
You brought your dad on our date?
Oh, of course not.
He was just leaving. Aren't you, Dad?
Yeah, but not until I finish my coffee.
You don't have any coffee.
Get me one, would you, Larry?
Dad, what are you doing here?
Hi, Roz. Hello.
Hi.
Is your brother joining us, too?
He's not my brother.
Oh, now, that' s no way to be.
Still waiting on that coffee, Lar.
Okay, what the hell is going on?
Nothing.
Hi, Frasier.
Hi, Ronee.
Nice to see you, Marty.
Sheila.
Take care. Bye.
So you've been pressed
into service as Sheila, hmm?
pressed is right. He
nearly bit my lip off.
Here you go, Mr. Doyle.
Ah, thanks.
Come on, Larry. we 're leaving.
It's nice meeting you, Mr. Doyle.
And you can owe me on that coffee.
It was $3. 75 and I flipped
a quarter in the tip jar.
I'll be home early, Dad.
Dad, when are you going
to stop playing games
and tell her how you feel?
It's too soon.
we've only been seeing
each other a few weeks.
I don't want to scare her off.
How do you know you 're
going to scare her off?
well, look at her, Fras.
She's young. She's got
all these guys after her.
I'm lucky she even
gave me a second glance.
I don't want to blow i t by looking
Like some desperate
old guy with no options.
It's not desperate
to tell somebody how
you feel about them.
what if she doesn't feel the same way?
what if she does and you never find out?
Dad...
just give her a call
and tell her you want to talk to her.
(grunts)
was that a "leave me alone" grunt,
or a "you've bested me again, son,
with your unassailable logic" grunt?
(grunts)
I thought so.
Hey, Dad.
what you watching?
Sports wrap-up.
That sounds like fun. Oof. (chuckles)
Oh, gosh, that's not very sportsmanlike.
I called her, okay.
Not that it's any of your business.
So...?
I left a message.
I'm glad she wasn't there.
I don't know what I'll
say if she calls back.
well, you did the right thing, Dad.
I am proud of you.
I don't know.
The whole thing's making me nervous.
You know, I know why
she's not calling me back.
e She doesn't know how to tell m
she's dropping me for
Richard. (doorbell rings)
well, who said anything
about dropping you?
. No one, apparently, or
you would've overheard it
Oh, hi, Ronee.
Hi, Frasier.
Ronee, I didn't expect
to see you tonight.
well, I got your message and
I was in the neighborhood.
So, what's up?
Oh, uh...
I was just heading out.
what, at this hour?
I never thought you
were such a night owl.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I love clubbin '.
I-I thought you'd just call.
well, you know, I was going
to, but it sounded like
maybe we needed to
talk face-to-face.
Yeah.
Marty, is this about that woman
I saw you with tonight?
well... kind of.
Yeah, I thought so.
Look, whatever it is,
why don't you just come out and say it.
Yeah, all right.
.. well, um... I'm not
the kind of guy who.
Hey, you want a beer?
Oh, boy, do I need one?
No, I think we could both use one.
(doorbell rings)
would you get that?
Frasier probably forgot his key.
Yeah, sure.
Oh, Sheila.
I kind of thought your date was over.
well... maybe it is...
and maybe it isn't.
Gotcha.
Uh, just tell Marty, message received.
Okay.
Hey, Roz, what are you doing here?
I found Frasier's
money clip . Is he home?
No, uh-uh.
where's Ronee?
Oh, don't worry.
Sheila showed Ronee the door.
what?!
what the hell did you do that for?!
Hey, I have no control
over what Sheila does.
Oh, good, Niles, you're
back . How was the concert?
well, you're the one who
wanted that cloud mural.
I'm sure pope Julius had to
jump through similar hoops
to get Michelangelo
to paint his ceiling.
Dear God, I think I just realized
where I must've dropped my money clip.
Ronee's car.
She gave me a ride in
it the day I lost it.
well, that's irresponsible of her.
She just left it open.
Excuse me.
Oh, yes, of course.
There we are.
Thank you.
Anyway, I thought I'd swing by
and take us both out for a
nightcap. (engine starting)
All right, great.
By the way, Niles, I,
uh, I spoke with Dad
and he has taken our advice
about talking things over..
Mine and yours, that's
what I mean by "our. "
Oh, take some responsibility
for once in your life, man.
You could've at least warned m
that Sheila was on her way up.
Ronee, it's all a misunderstanding.
Marty, I really don't want to hear it.
well, you're going to hear
it 'cause I'm not leaving.
Fine, just get in the
car if you want to.
we're going to sit right
here until you hear it all.
Okay, go ahead.
But you better make it good
because I have a finely
tuned crap-ometer.
There is no Sheila. Her name's Roz.
She's Frasier's secretary.
I just pretended we were together.
Forget it, Marty.
I know how this sounds, but it's true.
why would you do that?
Because I'd gotten these
concert tickets to impress you.
And then when you said
you had a date, I got...
well, I got jealous, so I
said I was getting a date, too.
And then there you were in Nervosa,
and when Roz came in, I made her Sheila.
Do you believe me?
. You know, it's actually a little hot
Really?
Look, Ronee, uh, maybe
I'm old-fashioned,
but I know when something feels right.
I don't want to see anybody else.
I want to be exclusive.
Go steady, whatever they call it now.
well, that's my story.
what about you?
(sighs) : well...
. God, it's freezing in here
I had a blanket.
Okay.
Since we're being honest, uh,
well, I-I've done my share of dating,
and I haven't always
made the best choices.
I've dated the bad guys,
the guys who can't commit,
, the guys who won't grow up
the creeps with the nice
suit, the pathological liars...
Okay, I got it.
Anyway, and then I started
dating this really good guy--
you...
... and I guess I-I just wanted
to keep my options open with Richard
because I wasn't sure
how you felt about me.
But now I am.
Now would be the time.
to put your class ring
on a chain around my neck.
I got one upstairs.
You want to come get it?
wait, wait.
. I've got a better idea
I know this secluded beach
that's miles away from anything.
You want to go there
and steam up the windows?
Oh, yeah.