It's official.
Dr. Lee says we're pregnant.
Oh, I'm so excited .
Hello in there .
It's your pater .
Oh, stop it.
So, how do you want to
make the announcement?
Uh... Well, Frasier's on
his way over. We could...
No.
He's a blabber mouth.
Let's have him and your
dad over for dinner tonight
and we can tell them at the same time.
If you already had a plan,
why did you ask me
how I wanted to do it?
Well, because if you'd
have had the same idea,
then I could have agreed with it,
which would have given you
the illusion of control.
The waiting room had Cosmo.
Oh.
All right.
I have just the quotation
for the beginning of the announcement.
It's from Robert Burns .
"Beneath the shelter of an aged tree;
"Th' expectant wee-things,
toddlin', stacher through
To meet their dad, wi'
- filchterin' noise and glee
Moving, eh?
Yes, but not just because of the poem.
I'm late for a hair appointment.
Oh.
Hi, you two. Hello.
Hi, Daph. Good to see you.
Hello, Niles.
Hey.
Uh, my usual, please.
Well, I've ruined another relationship.
I suppose you'll want to
hear the whole sorry tale.
No, thank you.
Last night, Julia came over
and, as usual, I made a mess of things.
Did you say no?
I said, "No, thank you. "
But I wish to unburden myself.
And I wish to remain in my good mood.
Therefore, I demur.
You demur? I demur.
Besides, I'm sure I've
heard it all before .
But this time was
different-- I really thought
BOTH: ...she could have been the one.
Well.
Silly me.
To think that I could
count on my only brother
for a shoulder on which to lean.
What you need isn't a shoulder.
It's a swift boot
to break you out of this pattern.
What pattern?
Your pattern of ruining things
before they've even begun.
And when have I done that?
Let me see.
Fay. Cassandra.
Chelsea, Claire,
Lana, Abby, Mia, Marie.
Oh, all right. I knew I had a pattern.
I just didn't think
you'd remember the names.
The minute you develop
feelings for someone
you get scared and find
some way to sabotage things.
I'd like to strike you, of course,
but you speak the truth.
I tell you what, I will never
find a happy relationship
un-unless I can break out
of this maddening cycle.
Well, all right, all right.
The next time you find
yourself doing it again--
fixating, say, on some
tiny fault of the woman--
recognize what that is,
you're feeling vulnerable,
ear. but don't give in to the f
Commit to commitment .
Commit to commitment.
Yes.
It's a bit glib, but
nonetheless inspiring.
Thank you, Niles.
I'm going to call Julia
and I will not take "no" for an answer.
I may have walked in here
the old fault-finding,
flaw-fleeing Flasier,
but I leave a man
committed to commitment.
You said "Flasier. "
id. I did not. Yes, you d
I most certainly did not.
No, I heard you say "Flasier. "
I've been saying my own name
for the last 40-some odd years.
I know, but your tongue...
Oh.
Hi, Dad.
Before you say anything,
if you know the score
to the Mariners game,
don't tell me-- I'm
taping it to watch later.
Dad, the odds of my knowing the score
to the Mariners game are about the same
as you knowing the score
to Pacific Overtures.
Did, uh, Julia call? No. Sorry.
Oh, damn.
Well, at least this little
delivery will cheer me up.
My new Frette hand towels have arrived.
(gloating laughter)
Direct from Italy, I give
you the spugna con frangia
with the tulle lace insert, huh?
Sounds fancy.
Am I allowed to dry my hands on them?
Well, you may miss the luxurious feel
of your trouser fronts, but yes.
You know, if you're really
down about this Julia thing,
you can come with me
and Eddie to the circus.
We're really going
to the v-E- T,
but if I say that, he
won't get in the car.
Thanks anyway, Dad.
I'll just see you at Nile's and Daphne'?
for dinner, all right?
Maybe I'll take in a movie
Oh, what are you going
to go see? Well, there's
this new Russian film in t
own about a Crimean war vet.
No, Eddie!
Would it have killed you
to say "Crimean War circus"?
Oh, for heaven's sake.
I'm so sorry, Dad. I...
Oh, well...
Julia.
You got my message.
What message? I actually came
because I think I dropped
an earring here last night.
Oh. I'm... I'm sorry. Please, come in.
So, what did it look like?
Oh, it was just a small diamond stud.
Right. Okay, yea h, you check there.
So, uh, what was this message?
Um... Oh, I just said that
I found you bright and, uh,
beautiful and engaging,
and then...
There was a sonnet.
"Fair love's ship ne'er
sa ilo'er unstorm'd seas."
The fickle stars, her
compass, bright and cruel... "
It's pretty sappy stuff, huh ?
No, it's sweet.
Especially the end.
So you did hear it.
Yes, but, Frasier...
I'm not looking for
just some office romance.
I don't see the point
in getting involved
unless it's heading somewhere.
That's exactly where
I am in my life, too.
After you walked out last night,
I realized how badly I want
to be in a real relationship,
how ready I am to...
well, for want of a better phrase,
to commit to commitment.
You're not just saying this
to get in my pants, are you?
No.
And if I did... get in your pants,
well... I'd want t o stay there forever.
I-I-I said that much more
elegantly in the sonnet.
You know, I just remembered
where I may have lost my earring.
Really? Where? In your bedroom.
Do you care to help me look?
In my bed... Well, we were
never in my bedroom. I don 't...
Oh.
I see.
Let's hope Frasier's ove n
is more reliable than ours.
MARTIN: Well, it serves you right
for getting such a fancy one.
Oh, it's just temperamental.
My Gaggenau is German-engineered.
It probably needs more power
than my building's
old wiring can give it.
Yeah, well, leave
it to the Germans--
even their appliances crave power.
So, when do you want to
make the big announcement?
I think a toast before dinner.
Let's hope Frasier checks
his messages after the movie,
or he'll be heading over to our place.
Yes, well, I'm sure he will.
It's just as well
not to have him here
while we're cooking.
I can't stand his backseat basting.
I was just dreaming about us.
We were in a boat,
floating down the Arno River.
Have you ever been to fair Firenze?
Oh, it's maybe my favorite city.
Oh. Mine, too.
Oh, I knew we'd be a good couple.
Have you ever gone there for Christmas?
No. I've always wanted to.
Me, too.
Well, then, let's go.
Do you mean it?
It sounds perfect.
I'll tell you what.
Let's toast this decision
with a glass of Chianti.
Ooh, that sounds good.
Oh, shoot.
What?
I just remembered-- I'm
supposed to have dinner
at my brother and his
wife's house tonight.
Uh... I'm just going to call and cancel.
(phone ringing)
Hello.
Niles, it-it's Frasier. Listen . .
I just got out of the movie,
and it was so cold in the theater
that I-I think I've...
(with a hoarse voice)
: I think I've come down
with a little something,
and, uh, I just... I just...
I'm afraid I'm begging
out of tonight, all right?
Oh, I hardly think
a little dinner will make you worse.
And besides, we've
had a change of plans.
Niles, for God sakes,
I just want to go home
and get into bed.
But Daphne and I have
put a lot of effort
into making a very nice dinner.
I can't help it if I'm sick.
What if I catch pneumonia?
If that's what you wear to the movies,
it's your own damn fault.
What the hell are you doing here?
My oven's on the fritz.
We left you a message hours ago.
Oh, I'm sorry, Niles.
Um, you remember Julia, of course.
Well, if he didn't before,
he certainly will now.
Excuse me.
You lied to me.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Would you have rather I told you
that I was inflagrante delicto?
No, no.
But you're still not
excused from dinner.
Julia and I will delighted to attend.
We weren't planning on including Julia.
Well, what do you want me to do,
give her 50 bucks and
tell her to beat it?
Oh.
Ten years?
I... If I still needed
a cane after that long,
I'd dump my physical therapist
and find one who knows
what they're doing.
Hello.
Well, actually, this is her.
She's also my
daughter-in-law.
Daphne, this is Julia.
Sorry about that. I...
That's all right.
And just so you know,
more. he wouldn't need the
can e so much if he'd stretch
I would have thought
that part of your job
was making sure he stretched.
Yes, but...
I can't be her e day and night.
Oh.
I'm sorry. For some reason
I thought you lived here.
Well, I don't.
How about some Mozart to
makes things festive, hmm?
(music plays)
Ah.
Well, I'm not sure
I'd call that festive.
Well, then, you'd be wrong,
as it is from the
Salzburg Music Festival.
How about something a
little more contemporary?
Well, all right. I believe I have...
Oh, Michael's Nyman's
The Contemporary Trumpet.
What are you, a hundred?
All right.
Nothing then, my little wasp.
(laughs)
Oh, thank you, Niles.
Thank you very much.
go. There you
Oh, perfect. Thank you.
NILES: Oh, uh...
Here you go. There you are.
She took my... Just take it.
Just take it. She took my...
I don't care. Just take it.
She, uh...
shoots from the hip, this one.
(laughs): Yes.
You should hear what
she says about my show.
Oh, I just have to
remind Mr. Pompous here
that what we do on the
radio is entertainment.
Well... NILES: Yes, Frasier
and I have had many a
chat about the difference
between what he does
and genuine psychiatry.
Yeah, big difference.
I mean, at least his advice is free,
not like those quacks
who charge people 200 bucks an hour
to whine about their childhoods.
I mean, what a racket that is.
Frasier, may I see you in the kitchen?
Frasier. What are you
doing in the kitchen?
You just asked to see me.
Ah. So you haven't gone deaf.
Why would I have gone deaf?
Because that's the only good reason
you sat there silently while
our profession was assaulted
Like  a drag queen at a tractor pull.
Niles, don't be so sensitive.
That is one of the
qualities I admire most
about Julia-- her
bracing frankness.
Now, listen, listen. What?
It is partially because of your advice
that I have chosen to
commit myself to this woman,
so please, at least give her a chance.
You're right. If
you're happy, I'm happy.
Ah, thanks.
Help me serve. Right. Right. Okay.
Dinner is served, everyone.
If you'd come and take a seat.
Here we are. Daph,
why don't you sit here
Julia, have a seat there,
and I'll sit right next to you
NILES: Thanks, Dad.
And before we begin,
I would like to share
some words of Robert Burns
which have recently become
quite meaningful to me.
"Beneath the shelter
of an aged tree... "
(cell phone ringing) Whoops. That's me.
Hello?
Hey. What's up?
No, no, I can talk.
Well, what kind of crap is that?
Nail their asses to the wall.
Is that chicken?
No, partridge.
Yes, in a champagne and orange sauce.
'Cause he's a pissy
little bitch, that's why.
I'm sorry. I don't eat birds
They live in their own feces.
More for me.
I'll just get some cereal.
Well, let him sue.
got I'm starting to think you've
a little pair of panties
on under that suit.
You know, she really does work too hard.
Back to what I was saying.
"Beneath the shelter
of an aged tree... "
JULIA: Okay,
I give up-- where do
you keep your cereal?
(chuckles) : Please, Julia, sit.
We'll find you something.
Oh, are you sure?
"Beneath the shelter of an aged... "
Niles.
Let's not do this
tonight-- not with her here.
I want it to be perfect.
You're right. We'll just...
We'll just pick a better moment.
I'll still be pregnant tomorrow.
Exactly.
Well, congratulations, Niles.
Frasier didn't tell me
that Daphne was pregnant.
What?
She is?
Oh, no, don't tell me
she's just paunchy.
She's not paunchy. She's pregnant!
Niles!
How could you do that?
JULIA: I'm sorry.
It's my fault. I heard
you in the kitchen.
I didn't realize it was a big deal.
Well, what does it matter
how we came to know this glorious news?
Niles! It's just wonderful !
Two words: C-section.
My sister's about your size,
and when she had her kid,
it blew out the whole region.
Can I have cereal, too?
So, the more pregnantshegets,
the more the husband hits on me .
And by the way, she was a model.
(phone rings)
Whoops.
That's me.
Hello? Hey, how you doing?
No, I'm just... meeting
my boyfriend's family.
Isn't this fun?
I'm having a good time.
It's fun, isn't it?
She certainly takes a lot
of calls at dinnertime.
You know, that's exactly
the kind of... flaw
that the old Frasier would have...
seized upon as pretext
to end the relationship,
but I-I know now that...
that impulse to run
is-is really an indication
that my feelings for her
are just deepening, and, um...
Gone are the days
when I would have said something like...
(exhales sharply)
"How rude. "
Or "She's horrible.
I've made a ghastly, ghastly mistake. "
Hey, Marty, you're a Mariners fan.
They won in the tenth on a grand slam.
Who's ready to play
that game of Pictionary we talked about?
I know I am.
(forced laughter)
Let me... just get that.
Dad, I'll tell you what.
I know how much you like to keep time,
so you'll be the timer,
and then, it'll be me and Julia
versus Niles and Daphne. How about that?
Oh, that sounds good to me.
FRASIER: Daphne, what do
you say you draw first?
Okay.
Mm-hmm. All right.
Oh, boy.
(chuckles)
Okay.
Ready, set... go.
The Ring of the Nibelungen.
Right! Damn!
Wow!
Well... congratulations, you two.
(forced laughter)
Great.
All right, enough of that.
Get your head in the game.
We're starting from behind.
Right, right. Okay, here we go.
Now...
Yeah.
All right.
Okay, Dad.
Go.
JULIA: A ball, a balloon.
Oh, an apple!
Uh, the circle of life.
Uh, I don't know.
Yeah, I'm looking at it.
Maybe if you point
at it harder, I'll get it
Give me something to work with, dummy.
Oh, a hat!
Oh, the Cat in the Hat!
Uh, Abraham Lincoln!
Time.
(screeching): Oh,From Here to Eternity!
I got that in!
No, that's, that'? not it. Uh...
What the hell is it?
It's a cherry with a mustache,
and, uh, wearing a sombrero.
It's "Cherry Garcia. "
Oh, my God, that is the
worst drawing I've ever seen.
I mean, even these cheaters
wouldn't have gotten that one.
Cheaters?
I saw you guys mouthing at each other.
And I think Father Time here
cut us off a little early, too.
Here, give me that pen.
I'll show you how it's done.
Sit down.
Oh, my God, I mean,
this painting is j...
(choking)
(continues choking and coughing)
Oh, dear God!
Are you all right?
Oh... yes, I just...
(coughs)
I think I need to splash a
little cold water on my face.
Let me just, uh, walk
you to the powder room.
I'm sorry.
Well, that's, uh, that's okay.
You just take as long as you need.
Shame on you!
That woman couldn'tbreathe,
and the three of you just sat there!
You didn't exactly jump in yourself.
That's because I mistook her choking
for a sarcastic comment
on my Pictionary play!
You, on the other hand,
were content to let the woman
I love die before your eyes.
That's right! I said I love her !
Oh, knock it off, Frasier.
You don't love her
You're just trying to talk yourself
into honoring your
ill-advised commitment.
How dare you presume to know
the workings of my heart?
You can't understand
the kind of feelings
Julia and I have for one another.
You may as well ask me
to describe the essence
of music or the, the
col or of starlight!
Nice towels, Frasier.
You'd think a couple of
old ladies lived here.
Get out.
Excuse me?
I said get out!
I'm sorry. Have you just lost your mind?
No. That happened earlier
when we slept together.
Are you breaking up with me?
You're damn right I am!
I want my purse.
And I, my hand towel.
I can't believe this.
You're actually kicking me out ?
Do you want me to draw you a picture?
We'd be here all night!
Get out!
(pouring)
With this bottle, I would like to both
commemorate and apologize
for this evening.
Daphne, Niles,
this should have been your evening,
and I selfishly monopolized
every moment of it.
Frasier... Not yet, Niles.
Anyway,
I handled things badly...
both with Julia and with you,
and I just hope that you can forgive me.
Of course we will.
Oh, look on the bright side.
You could've let her choke to death,
but you didn't
Well, then, uh, to life,
both the old and the new.
(all chuckling)
Ah.
Niles, I'm so proud of you.
Thank you.
I'm excited for you , Daphne .
Takes me back to when I had my kids.
What are you hoping for, boy or girl?
Oh, I don't know.
Be sort of nice to have a boy.
Niles,
just look at the edging on this.
Have you ever? Have you ever?
And look at... this
is all hand-stitched.
Mm-hmm.