You're on KACL
with Dr Frasier Crane.
We have time for one more call.
Hello, Gretchen. l'm listening.
(Gretchen) 'Well, you see, Dr Crane,
my husband is a fencing instructor
'and lately he spends all his time
with his wealthy new student
'and l'm afraid
there's some bumsen going on.'
- Do you have any evidence?
- 'No, it's just a feeling.'
Well, in these matters, there's
no simple way to know for sure.
Yes, there is.
Well, Gretchen, you're in luck.
lt just so happens
we have in our studio today
one of the world's
five leading bumsen experts.
lf you want to know if a man is cheating,
you offer him two choices for dinner,
one that's fattening and one that's light.
lf he picks the calorie packed one,
he doesn't mind turning into a pig,
which means he's happily married.
Hearing advice like that,
l wish there was a law against
women gathering at a water cooler.
- Now, Gretchen...
- 'Does it really work, Roz?'
- Oh, trust me.
- 'l'm going to do it.
'Thank you for your help, Roz.
- 'Oh, and you too, Dr Crane.'
- Don't mention it.
Well, Dr Crane
and friends will be back tomorrow.
Thanks for listening, Seattle.
- l know you hate it when l butt in.
- And yet...
You'll forgive me when you find out
what l'm doing for you.
There's this woman
who lives in my building.
- She's beautiful and funny.
- Stop. l do not go out on blind dates.
They're demeaning and a waste of time.
- No, thank you. No.
- lt's for your father.
What time should he pick her up?
Wait a minute. They are OK
for your father, but not for you?
Yes. And games with balls, beer and
giant trucks that roll over small ones.
''So you want to build
a three-masted schooner.
''Before assembly,
take inventory of all parts.''
- We don't need to read that.
- We do.
lt says here, in bold,
''Read all instructions''.
Pass me the right side of the hull.
You'll get that piece at Step 1 6
and not a moment sooner.
- Can we get started here?
- All right, Dad.
''So you want to build
a three-masted schooner.''
Give me that! You'll put your eye out.
Look at that! What a beautiful ship!
- l bet you'll have fun building that.
- Not as much fun as reading about it.
Did l ever mention one of my ancestors
was a mutineer on HMS Bounty.
(Martin) No kidding.
He made it safely to Pitcairn lsland
where he was fruitful and multiplied.
For all l know, there's some girl
who looks exactly like me
in the South Seas,
frolicking in the surf,
brown-skinned and bare breasted.
So you want to build
a two-masted schooner?
Schooner? l thought it was a frigate.
A frigate has a fore-and-aft mainsail.
- That's a brigantine.
- Well, what's a frigate?
That's when you just don't give a damn.
- Hello.
- Hello there.
Are you spending
the evening with us?
Yes. Maris misses me,
but feels family comes first.
She saw this model
and felt l should share it with Dad.
- She wanted you out of the house?
- Like a musty smell.
Dad, l have a proposal for you.
There's a woman in Roz's building
that would like to go out with you.
Roz says she's got
a wonderful personality.
Oh, l guess that means
l'm the pretty one.
- Tell Roz thanks but no thanks.
- You're making a mistake.
Trying new things is what keeps us
all young and vibrant.
You're right. For weeks Maris floated
in a sensory deprivation tank,
but she's taken up fencing
and l've never seen her more vital.
She stays up late into the evening,
working with her instructor.
- Maris has a fencing instructor?
- Yes.
Gunnar was the Bavarian champion
three years running.
He's Bavarian?
You're full of questions
l've already answered.
Am l?
He speaks no English. Maris practises
German while she parries and thrusts.
Maris is learning German, huh?
Just when you thought
she couldn't get any cuddlier.
- Dad, did you take the spanking aft?
- Yeah, l pre-glued it for you.
- Good job!
- Not to worry.
This used to happen
to my brothers all the time.
l can get it off with nail polish remover.
Come with me.
- So your brothers built models?
- No, l suspect they just sniffed glue.
- That can cause brain damage.
- Well, then, that confirms it.
Dad. Dad.
l have to talk to you about Niles.
l got a call from a German woman
whose husband is a fencing instructor
that she suspects is having
an affair with his wealthy new client.
- And?
- Don't you find it incriminating?
lt's a coincidence. Seattle's a big city.
l'm sure German fencing instructors
have dozens of students.
But are they wealthy?
No. They're working their way out
of the ghetto with a foil and a dream (!)
ln the midst
of that slag heap of sarcasm,
there may be a kernel of truth.
l could be letting my imagination
run away with me.
Forget it.
Help me put this model together.
Oh, my God. l remember how
Niles used to love these models.
Remember that Christmas Mum got him
''The Visible Man And Woman''?
- He had to glue the internal organs.
- l remember you two fighting.
He got on my nerves,
so l stole his ovaries.
There's a conversation
l'm glad l missed the beginning of.
- Sorry l'm late.
- Did you ask your dad about the date?
- He's not interested.
- Darn it.
l got her hopes up.
Would you consider going out with her?
Sorry. l've had my quota of pity dates.
But this time you wouldn't be
the one being pitied.
We have a great call
to start the show off with.
The guy on line three
found out his girlfriend is his sister!
Wow!
- That German woman called back.
- Gretchen?
- Yeah.
- l want her first.
What do l say
to the guy dating his sister?
Tell him to hang on.
We've all been there.
Hello, Seattle.
This is Dr Frasier Crane on KACL.
Roz?
Gretchen's calling
about her husband's affair.
She thinks she has more evidence.
- l'm listening.
- (Gretchen) 'l took Roz's advice.
'l gave my husband
two choices for dinner
'and he picked the diet plate!'
That is no proof he's having an affair.
- 'But Gunnar has a healthy appetite.'
- No, no, no.
The proof is...phone bills,
credit card receipts... Gunnar?
l also found a love letter.
How long were you
going to keep that secret?
What does it say?
(Gretchen speaks German)
- l'm sorry. l don't speak German.
- 'lt's means my little liver dumpling.
- 'That used to be his pet name for me.'
- Maybe he's writing to you.
'lt can't be me. He says he loves
her beautiful, little body,
'as thin as his sword
and her skin as white as bratwurst,
'and that she's
his nicht eine menschliche Frau. '
- What is that?
- 'l don't know if there's an English word.
'The closest translation
is ''not quite human woman''.'
- Dear God. lt is her.
- 'What should l do?'
l don't know. l need time to think.
Let's go to commercial.
Hello. Gretchen,
l have considered your problem.
You must confront your husband
and insist that he end this affair.
- (Gretchen) 'What if he won't?'
- But innocent people are being hurt.
Tell him how much he means to you.
Are there children?
- 'No.'
- Damn!
Still, it must be a clean break.
He must never see this woman again.
'We never had
these problems back home.'
Maybe you should return
to the loving bosom of Bavaria.
'How did you know
we were from Bavaria?'
Well, l'm a master of dialect.
l noticed there was a glottal quality
to the occlusion of your diphthongs.
'l'm originally from Austria.'
Do you want to split hairs
or get your husband back?
lt's time for another commercial.
- Another commercial?
- Yes, another commercial!
What is going on?
Why do you think something's going on?
When the person giving advice
sounds crazier than the caller,
l think something's going on.
Nothing's going on.
You know who the liver dumpling is,
don't you?
Yes. But it's nobody you know.
Her husband's a friend of mine.
- How can l tell him?
- Don't tell the person being cheated on.
Confront the person who's cheating.
Didn't Harvard teach you anything?
l can't do that.
You tell her you know
she's been mattress surfing
and if she won't stop, you'll tell.
lt's not that easy. You don't know her.
She can't deal with confrontation.
l once questioned her for serving veal
and we found her in the garage
with the engine running on a golf cart.
Whoa, it's Maris!
(Woman speaks Spanish)
Mrs Crane is in the box?
Maris! This is Frasier.
l'm tired of waiting for you
to come out of this ridiculous tank.
We've got to talk about Niles.
Will you come out of there?
Look, Maris...
l know you're having an affair.
l care for you both and l want to help
you do what's best for your marriage.
Will you stop this?
Just come... Come out of this box!
All right, l'm going to open the door.
l'm going to count to three.
l don't care if you're naked.
l'm going to count to ten.
To hell with this! All right!
Niles, l'm so sorry.
Marta, you said
Mrs Crane was in the box?
- Si, Missy Crane.
- That's Mr Crane!
Marta has trouble with her pronouns.
- l'm worried. He's sensitive.
- You're right.
Maybe we shouldn't let on how worried
we are. lt will add to his anxiety.
lf we coddle him,
he'll think the world's ended.
(Doorbell)
- Hello, Niles.
- Hi, Son.
lt's OK. lt's OK, Niles. Come on.
lt's all right.
- We're all here for you, son.
- My little brother.
Frasier, pour him a glass of brandy.
Yes. Oh, God. l'm all out of brandy.
l have a marvellous sherry,
some fine ports and a lovely bottle
of 1 2-year-old unblended Scotch.
- lt's a bit peaty...
- Just pour him a drink!
- What happened, son?
- Nothing.
Nothing?
When l left, you were about to
storm up to her room
and have it out with her?
l thought of questions to fire at her,
but when l reached her door l froze.
l turned and walked out of the house,
got in the car and started driving.
l'm glad you ended up here.
Actually, l ended up
at the Oregon border check.
l had fruit in the car,
so l had to turn back.
What will l do? She's my whole life.
She may have temporarily succumbed
to Gunnar's Teutonic charms,
but in the end l'm sure she'll choose
the man who's intelligent and sensitive.
Frasier, that's just something
we used to tell ourselves in chess club.
The truth is
women don't want men of intellect.
They want men of action, like Gunnar.
lt has nothing to do with Gunnar.
lt's about you and Maris.
Remember your advice
when l had problems with Lilith?
You said l should talk to her
and find out why she did what she did.
lt's one thing to give advice,
another to take it.
Frase, didn't you and Lilith write articles
on the keys to a successful marriage?
- Yes.
- lt might help Niles to read them.
Well, all right.
l've only got half. Lilith got the rest
in the divorce settlement.
Now that we got rid of the foghorn,
here's the way to handle it.
Remember this happened
between your mother and l?
- Right.
- Well, l took it up with the other man.
l told him if it ever happened again,
he'd be the other woman.
There was a lot more that we had to do
to keep our marriage together,
but at least she knew how much l cared.
Should l grab Gunnar by the scruff
of the neck and throw him out?
- Why not?
- l've been fantasising about it.
lt's just not me, though.
Although maybe it should be me.
No, l've got to speak to Maris eventually.
Although, if l do it your way,
l'm going at it from a position of strength.
l'll do it, Dad. Tonight it's Gunnar
who will be taught a lesson.
- That's my boy. Sure you're up to it?
- Yes, l am.
l'm pumped, l'm psyched and l just
swallowed an entire twist of lemon.
- Did l just hear Niles leave?
- He went to straighten out Gunnar.
God, Dad, how could you let him go?
What if Gunnar wants to fight?
lt's still better this way.
He's found his manhood.
l'll be happy if he traded in
some teeth for his cojones.
l've got to stop walking in
on the middle of conversations.
There you are.
Yes, l'm talking to you, strudel boy!
No one gets away
with seducing my wife.
You probably thought, because of my
swimmer's build, l wouldn't fight for her,
but you're wrong, because real men
have a thing called honour.
Yow!
You wouldn't know about that.
- Niles.
- You don't know how to behave.
You don't know
the meaning of rectitude.
He doesn't know the meaning of dog.
He doesn't speak English!
(Speaking in German)
Marta?
You speak German?
(Speaking Spanish)
She worked for a German family
that turned up in Guatemala...
just after the war.
Good. She can translate.
Tell her to tell him...
Niles, just wait!
lf he knew you were calling him strudel
boy, he'd wipe his feet on your face.
lf there are scuffs,
they'll be scuffs of honour.
How dare you steal my wife!
Translate.
All right.
(Frasier speaks Spanish)
(Marta translates in German)
All right, fine,
you want to challenge me?
En garde!
That's just what we need,
a fourth language!
You can't possibly fight this man.
You forget.
l've been fencing since prep school.
So what?
He was born with a sword in his hand.
He probably performed
his own Caesarean.
My God. He's going to kill me.
Oh, very nice, very nice. Thank you.
Niles!
Are you all right?
(Speaking German)
ls he giving up?
He wants you to apologise.
He didn't steal...your shoes.
- My shoes?
- Yes, l'm sorry.
Apparently, l mistranslated.
He didn't mean... Not shoes, wife.
(Speaks Spanish)
(Translation in German)
Frau?
(Speaks German)
(Marta translates in Spanish)
He couldn't help it.
Maris is irresistible... lrresistible?!
(Marta translates)
OK.
- But she refused him.
- Really?
What did Maris say?
(Marta translates)
''l love Niles.''
Oh, she loves me.
My Maris is home.
ln five seconds,
tell him he's fired. Maris!
lf only l could help
Gunnar and Gretchen.
Tell him his wife loves him very much.
(Frasier translates in Spanish)
(Marta translates in German)
No, no, not me, you! You!
Marta, damn your pronoun problems!
All right, you hapless wretch!
# Hey baby, l hear the blues are calling
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# Oh, my!
# And maybe l seem a bit confused
Well, maybe...but l got you pegged!
# But l don't know what to do with those
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# They're calling again #
Frasier has left the building.