That's all for today.
Bob Bulldog Briscoe is up next.
Oh, yes! This is KACL cash call week.
$5,000 if you answer your phone
with the phrase that pays.
So don't say ''Hello''. Say...
Well, blow me down!
No. Say, ''KACL is the talk of the town,
talk of Seattle.'' Whatever. Bye-bye.
Sam! Oh, my God!
- What are you doing in town?
- l'm here interviewing for a job.
The Mariners need a pitching coach
and called me.
They did?
l mean, that's great. Come on in.
- You're off the air?
- Yes.
Frase, l got to go. Your messages...
Whoa. Who is this?
l'm Sam Malone.
l was a buddy of Frasier's in Boston.
Roz Doyle.
This is the Sam who has no respect
for women and treats them like dirt?
Need anyone
to show you around Seattle?
l'm all right with the city,
but l get real lost in my hotel room.
Look at the two of you, face to face.
Wild animals everywhere are
lifting their heads, alerted to the scent.
Bye, Roz.
lf you need any company, give me a call.
- Snazzy card.
- lt glows in the dark.
So do l.
So how's everybody at Cheers?
Well, let's see...
Rebecca married that plumber.
She tries so hard to land a rich guy
and ends up with an ordinary plumber.
He struck gold. He's got a patent
on some low-flow toilet thing.
He's rich beyond her wildest dreams.
- l'm happy for her.
- Don't be. He dumped her.
- She's back at the bar.
- Working at Cheers again?
No, she's just back at the bar.
Here's some good news.
Woody and Kelly had a baby boy.
That is wonderful!
ls he...?
No, he's smart.
Genetics takes a holiday, huh?
- Want to continue this over lunch?
- l'd like that.
- Norm and Cliff still holding up the bar?
- Norm is, but Cliff isn't.
He read about that flesh-eating bug
and hasn't left his mum's house since.
lt's good cos a lot of people
who haven't been around
are starting to come back.
Sam was a Major League ballplayer.
Put out the good china.
And don't forget the Limoges spittoon.
Sam's the most important person
ever to set foot in this apartment.
This American obsession with
superficial sports figures beats me.
Yeah. They don't do anything important
like sit on a throne or christen ships.
Niles, why didn't you bring Maris?
Ask Maris to spend an evening
with a baseball player?
Why don't l just ask her
to rub my shoulders?
- Here we are.
- Wow, look at this.
You got quite a babe magnet here.
Sam Malone! l'm Marty Crane!
l'm one of your biggest fans!
l was at the Kingdome the night you
gave up four consecutive home runs.
- l bet you remember that.
- No, that was during my drinking phase.
- Did l hit anybody? Did l hurt them?
- No.
Hey, that was a good game then.
- This is my chair. You want to sit in it?
- Oh, yeah. Well, maybe later.
l'll keep it warm for you.
- This is my brother, Dr Niles Crane.
- Pleasure to meet you.
Man, this is freaky. He looks
just like you did when l met you.
What happened?
lt wasn't exactly a health club
you were running there, Sam.
This is strange.
l didn't know he had a brother.
ln all the time you spent swapping
bon mots with the beer-nut set,
you never mentioned
you had a brother?
l bet he said something, but when
he gets going, you have to tune him out.
Good slogan for his show: ''When he
gets going, you have to tune him out.''
What did he say about me?
The father, the old cop?
He told me you were dead.
- Dead?
- We had had an argument.
You called me
a stuffed shirt and hung up on me.
You're a cop? You told me
he was a research scientist.
You were dead! What did it matter?
Daphne, this is Sam Malone. Daphne
Moon, Dad's physical therapist.
Pleasure to meet you.
- Daphne's from England.
- l'm a sucker for the accent.
No matter what you say, it always
sounds so classy and sophisticated.
(Gushes effusively)
See what l mean?
That kills me every time.
Let me get that. You shouldn't spend
your whole evening in the kitchen.
ls Sam flirting with Daphne?
Of course he is.
He flirts with everybody.
He's a sexual compulsive. But
he's getting help in a support group.
(Laughter in the kitchen)
Did he miss a meeting?
(Telephone rings)
Hello? You'd like to speak to Sam?
- Who is it?
- Who's calling, please? Sheila.
He's not here,
but l'm expecting him soon.
- No! Number two!
- l'm sorry. l was mistaken.
He was here, but he left.
l'll give him the message. Thank you.
l'm sorry, Sam.
l'm a little out of practice.
So...who's Sheila?
Just the woman l'm supposed to marry.
Marry? When?
Oh, boy. Yesterday.
- Yesterday.
- l don't want to talk about it.
- But, Sam...
- Frase, please?
Something smells yummy here.
Wait a second. l think it's me.
The smell... And l thought...
Come on, Sam, one more.
1 949, Yankees, initials VR.
- Vic Raschi.
- You're great!
You just have to give him
the city, the date and the initials.
That's similar to a game
Frasier and l play. l'll go first.
1 962, Prague Philharmonic,
viola section, initials CM.
- Czeslaw Milovicz.
- Wrong!
No, Milovicz was first viola
the year before,
but by '62, he'd developed rosin
poisoning and couldn't pluck.
That's a trick question!
Well, l'm off to bed.
Thanks, Sam. The chair's all yours.
Come on!
Oh, yeah. That's very nice.
Night, all.
- l'm turning in.
- Pleasant dreams.
No problem there.
l'm off to my Maris.
lf the clock strikes twelve
and she hasn't felt my kiss upon
her forehead, she gets nervous.
- lt's been a pleasure meeting you.
- You, too.
You want to put a smile on Maris's face?
Let me tell you what you do.
Where would l find whipped cream
and a car battery at this hour?
You got neighbours, don't you?
Now that everybody's gone, there
was something l wanted to bring up.
What is it? Oh, yes!
You were about to get married?
l met this girl six months ago
and we were supposed to get married.
Yesterday, l was standing in this
church and l hear this minister say,
''Will you take this woman
to be your wife?'' And l said,
''Who, me?''
l ran down the aisle
and didn't stop running till l got here.
You're not here for the Mariners?
No ballplayer is in Seattle
for the Mariners!
All right. Let's have a seat here and
start this thing from the very beginning.
- Who is this woman?
- She's terrific. Smart, funny, horny.
The kind of chick you want
to stick up on a pedestal.
lt's always amazed me
how you can elevate and demean
in the same sentence.
- What?
- Forget it, just...
How do you think she found me here?
l guess you left a lot of clues
because you wanted her to find you.
l have a feeling you actually...
want to marry this girl.
Yeah, l don't know...
You just panicked. lt's perfectly natural.
The wedding ceremony
represents the end of your old life.
l tell you, man, she's one in a million.
For most guys,
that's just an expression.
l have a feeling that you're finally
ready for a commitment like this.
- Get on that phone and call her.
- What would l say though?
Tell her the truth.
Honesty is the cornerstone
of a healthy relationship.
Thank you.
lt's time l stepped up to the plate
and stopped acting like a kid.
The only question now is:
will she still take you back?
- She forgave him?
- Yes. She's on her way here.
They're getting married in Hawaii.
Same old story.
Love triumphs over Roz.
Don't be a sore loser. l invited them
here on their way in from the airport.
l remember my wedding day,
feeling faint, shaking, sweating.
Maris was so distraught,
thinking l had cold feet.
She was relieved to learn it was
just a congenital heart murmur.
- Hey, everybody.
- Oh, Sam!
Here she is,
the future Mrs Sam Malone.
- Sheila, Frasier.
- Nice to finally meet you.
Likewise. This is Roz and Niles.
- Congratulations.
- You want to sit down?
Actually, it was a long flight.
l was hoping to go
to the hotel and freshen up.
All right. Will you join us
for dinner about eight?
Sure.
Well, l guess we're off
to freshen up a little.
- Oh, my God!
- She's not an ''Oh, my God!''
No. Not that ''Oh, my God''.
Oh, my God, l slept
with her three months ago.
- You slept with her?
- Yes.
On what desert island
with no hope of rescue was this?
l was in Boston for a long weekend.
l was feeling a little depressed
so l took solace in the arms
of a beautiful
and remarkably welcoming
young woman at a hotel bar.
- And that was she?
- No, Niles.
l told you that
for no reason whatsoever(!)
Did you see the way she ran out of here
the minute she saw me?
The trademark of all your bed mates.
Three months ago? Sam said
they'd been together for six months.
lt looks like
this horse race is on again.
Oh, put the weapon down!
Stop it, Roz! Have you no scruples?
- You slept with your friend's fiancée!
- l didn't know!
- You have to tell Sam about this.
- And ruin our relationship and theirs?
l've got to speak to her first.
Hear her side of this story.
There are many reasons
why people have affairs.
Roz, want to get us started?
Maybe they stopped seeing each other
for a couple of weeks.
Or he cheated on her
and she was getting even.
Maybe she just found me irresistible.
Oh, yeah, that's it!
You struck gold there.
(Door knocks)
- Hello, Frasier.
- Hello, Sheila. Good to see you again.
Sam, you are one lucky guy!
- He's out getting our plane tickets.
- You have some explaining to do.
- OK. Wine?
- No, thank you.
l know this doesn't excuse what l did,
but l had no idea that
you were a friend of Sam's.
l'm a sexual compulsive.
That's how Sam and l met, in group.
That night l spent with you,
l guess l just fell off the wagon.
l felt awful afterwards.
lt ended up being a turning point for me.
That's how it is with addiction.
Before you get better,
you have to hit rock bottom.
Yes. Well...
l'm glad
l could be down there for you.
Listen, Frasier, l'm human.
l made a mistake.
Can you understand that?
Of course l can understand.
l've had many patients
that share your affliction,
although only you can hit
the emergency button of an elevator
with a stiletto heel.
l love Sam. l'll do everything l can
to make this marriage work.
You seem sincere about this.
l think l can support this marriage.
But if you start to feel yourself slipping,
here's my number.
No, no. So l can help you
as a psychiatrist!
Thank you.
l think it's probably best if we
don't tell Sam about the two of us.
Not that l have a guilty conscience.
l'm back.
You all right?
Got a little charley horse.
- Did you get the tickets?
- Yeah, l did. They're right here.
l'm so happy. By this time tomorrow,
we'll be Mr and Mrs Sam Malone.
l want to talk to you about that.
Frasier said something the other day
that really stuck in my mind.
What did l say?
That thing about honesty
being something of something...
lt was pro-honesty.
Being the cornerstone
of a good relationship?
Right. That really stuck in my mind.
- l haven't been honest with you.
- What do you mean?
When we get married, l want us
to have a clean slate, sweetheart.
l hope you can forgive me for this,
but a few months ago, l had a slip.
lt was two slips, but they were
simultaneous, so l'm counting it as one.
Was this after you were engaged?
Actually, it was that night.
l'm so sorry.
lt has not happened since
and l swear it will not happen again.
- l forgive you.
- You do?
l'm relieved. l have something
l need to confess to you.
You're not the only one
who...slipped.
You should have a little privacy.
No, you're responsible for getting
us this far. We have no secrets.
All right. Who?
That's what makes it so tough.
lt was someone from Cheers.
l parked in a loading zone!
Sam, l slept with Paul.
Paul?
- Short?
- Bald?
- Fat?
- Paul?
l didn't say he was good.
All right. l understand that.
You were giving Paul
a break or something.
l can forgive that.
lsn't this all about forgiveness?
OK. You told one, you told one.
We're all even. Let's go eat.
- There was someone else.
- Are we still on this?
l mean, there is honesty
and there's beating a dead horse!
- lt doesn't matter who it is.
- Yes, it does matter.
This one is really embarrassing.
l was lonely, l was desperate
and l'd just been to the eye
doctor and my pupils were dilated.
Oh, Sheila, for God's sake!
l'll tell him. She's trying to say...
lt was Cliff.
l believe she said Cliff.
Cliff?
Cliff? You slept with Cliff?
Cliff! No, that's it!
Wedding's off! Cliff! Oh, God!
Frasier, you've got to help me.
You've got to talk to him.
l slept with a woman
who slept with Cliff?
This will be a long flight home.
- You made the right decision.
- Yeah, l suppose.
Jeez! Cliff!
You're just using Cliff as the excuse.
There were more compelling reasons
for you to back out of this thing.
No, it was Cliff.
To put this thing aside
once and for all, l...
You're probably the only friend
l have who she didn't sleep with.
Cliff!
That is a tough one to swallow, huh?
But you proved yourself
ready for a commitment,
even if Sheila wasn't the one.
- l suppose so.
- ln a way, we're both in the same boat.
- What do you mean?
- We've tried, we've failed.
But we'll try again.
We're looking
for a meaningful relationship.
That's the word, ''meaningful''.
- We'll find it though, buddy.
- You bet we will.
Stewardesses usually
hang out at the airport.
That says ''meaningful'' to me.
# Baby, l hear the blues are calling
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# Mercy!
# And maybe l seem a bit confused
Well, maybe...but l got you pegged!
# But l don't know what to do with those
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# They're calling again #
Thank you!