- What the hell are you doing?
- Ironing your son's socks.
Why don't you twist them into balls
like you do mine?
He says it bruises the cashmere.
He likes them pressed, folded,
then neatly arranged in sock dividers.
I saw them in a catalogue once,
but couldn't imagine
who would buy such silly things.
Of course, I hadn't met Dr Crane yet.
We thought there'd been
a mix-up at the hospital.
When Niles came along,
it shot that theory all to hell.
Oh, Dad, please. Coaster.
Your beer is sweating.
So am I. You want to
shove one of those under my can?
(Doorbell rings)
If he could, he would.
Mrs Greenway,
what a pleasant surprise.
- That's him.
- Won't you come in?
I had to see him again,
but now I'm positive.
That is the horny little mixed breed
who got my Phoebe pregnant.
You can't just bust in here
accusing my dog.
I had to keep shooing him away
from Phoebe in the park!
Look at him. He doesn't care
whose life he's ruined!
All he cares about
is his own selfish pleasure!
You know your problem, Dorothea?
You got a bad attitude.
That's why nobody sits with you
in the park.
There's no way Eddie could be
the father. He's been neutered.
Oh, really?
Then how do you explain these?
Oh, my God!
- They're miniature Eddies!
- Aren't they adorable?
Well, I'm glad you think so,
because they're yours.
Bad dog! Look what you did!
Here, take these.
Dad, I expect an explanation.
I thought Eddie had been fixed.
All you had to do was look.
Well, I'm glad to say
I've never been that bored.
- Couldn't you just eat 'em up?
- For God's sake. Don't love them.
They'll think they're staying.
Keep them off the couch.
Why did you let him run in the park?
Haven't you seen the way
he romances my towel warmer?
He's cooped up here all day.
In the park,
I let him get some exercise.
Apparently, that's not all he got.
I've found the perfect name for this one.
Stop!
Dogs only need names
if you plan to call them to you.
Listen, you get right back in there,
you mangy little thing! My God!
I'm going to the radio station.
We'll talk when I get back.
Oh, relax, Frasier. I'll have
Eddie taken care of tomorrow.
You better.
Daphne, give me that box.
Where are you taking them?
- To unload them at the station.
- Couldn't we keep them for a while?
No. We don't want them
taking after their father.
It may be too late already.
Oh, for God's sake.
Stop staring at me!
Hello, Roz. You look lovely.
- I don't want one.
- I didn't say anything.
Betty from accounting warned me.
Where did you find them?
In my living room.
These are Eddie's mongrel seed.
Do you know anybody
that wants six puppies?
Six? All right, Eddie!
Please.
I've been in the hallway
for an hour trying to unload them.
- I haven't had any luck.
- Not everybody likes dogs.
Take me. I'm a cat person.
It's not like I'd buy a cat mug,
but I had a cat
when I was growing up.
We were almost inseparable.
Muffles or Scruffles,
something like that.
You know, Roz,
it's possible there's a dog lover
inside you just dying to get out.
Don't you think so?
Come on. Just take a look.
Come on. Take a look.
Have a look.
Oh, he's adorable!
Oh, come here, little fella!
Oh. Aren't you
the cutest little thing?
Oh, yeah.
Give me a kiss. Give me a kiss.
Oh! I love you too.
There. Happy now?
Roz,
how can you just toss him aside
after such a tender display of affection?
I can do it with men, too.
Come on.
It's time to start the show.
Phil, puppy! Puppy!
They're all on to me.
All right, you behave yourselves.
Hello, Seattle.
This is Dr Frasier Crane,
coming to you
from KACL 780 Talk Radio.
I'll be with you
for the next three hours.
Roz, who's our first caller?
Rita is on line four.
She feels overwhelmed at home.
Hello, Rita. I'm listening.
(Rita) 'Yeah, Dr Crane.
'Oh, Dr Crane,
thank you for taking my call.
'I...I tell you, I...
'I'm about to lose my mind.
'I am raising four kids by myself.
'The oldest one is not even seven
and the others are under five.
'Between cooking, cleaning, changing
diapers and tripping over toys...
'I...feel sometimes
like l am about to snap.
'What should I do?'
Have you considered getting a puppy?
(Puppies whimper)
If we can't have this one,
are there any others available?
No. We found homes for the others.
- Thanks for coming over.
- But the children. Dr Crane...
There are other dogs in the world.
Now, give me that.
Thank you for coming over.
Thank you.
I thought you might like
some wine and pâté.
I made some lemonade for the children.
Where are the Thomasons?
Why is that dog still here?
I'm sorry, but they struck me
as unfit guardians.
For God's sake. He works at the zoo!
She's a nurse! Billy's an altar
boy and Kathy is a campfire girl!
They had a dark aura.
They had a ten-acre farm!
I'd have gone with them!
I see. So you want me to
give him away to just anybody?
(Doorbell)
I'm not saying that.
It's just that he can't stay here.
- Hello, Niles. Come in.
- I hope you don't mind my stopping by.
Maris is hosting the Women's
League Senior Yoga Group.
And, well,
old money and body stockings...
Say no more.
You're welcome to hide out here.
- I see the kennel is still open.
- Yes, but that's the last one.
I'd found a home for him, but Daphne
thought the family wasn't nice enough.
- Some pâté, Niles?
- I didn't reject them. The dog did.
Canines have a very
keen sense of who's a nice person.
Many's the time
I've chosen a man based solely
on the way
my mum's spaniel took to him.
Daphne, that is preposterous,
letting a dog choose your dates.
It's true. If a dog likes a man,
it's a good bet
he's warm and sensitive.
I didn't get
a good look at this little tike.
Come here, boy.
Come to your Uncle Niles. Oh! Oh!
He's taken quite a shine to you.
Yes. Happens all the time.
Daphne, would you take the dog away?
Phone the Thomasons
and tell them we've reconsidered.
All right,
but only for a two-week trial.
- Thank you.
- Come along, Basil.
I told you not to name them!
- Hello, Dad.
- Afternoon, boys.
Dad, I seem to remember that Eddie
had a little appointment
down at the vet's.
I can't help but notice
he still has that...spring in his step.
We started heading down there,
but the traffic was a bear.
You get a sunny day
and everybody forgets how to drive.
You are going to reschedule?
(Martin)
Oh, yeah. I'll call in the morning.
This is the second time
you've cancelled. What's the problem?
'There's no problem.
What's the big deal?
'I'll call tomorrow. Relax, will you?'
- Dear God, he's licking me!
- Eddie!
Eddie, just stop.
Niles...
You have liver behind your ears.
I imagine I must have picked up
a cracker
and inadvertently
scratched behind my ear.
You had a wad of cold meat
behind your ears
and you didn't feel it?
That's the story
I'm sticking with, yes.
I want an assurance
you'll take care of it.
- You promise?
- I said I'd do it and I will!
Get off my back!
I'll be down at Duke's.
Ever notice how much faster
he moves when he's wrong?
He's got a psychological block
against taking Eddie there.
I'll have to do it. Somebody has
to be responsible. Good boy.
Come on. Let's go. Eddie?
Uh, Niles.
Oh. Now, Eddie,
it's a routine operation.
They say it's almost painless,
although I can't imagine...
No, Niles. Perhaps it's best
we don't discuss the operation.
We might spook him.
Excuse me?
Are you saying he understands me?
Well, he understands
the word B-A-T-H.
God knows how much English
he's picked up.
Fine.
(Speaking French)
What are we doing?
Eddie, come here!
This is ridiculous. Look at him!
What are you staring at?
You know why you're here,
don't you?
Listen, it's for your own good.
You'll be much happier afterwards.
Look, your day-to-day routine,
it'll be exactly the same.
You'll be able to sleep,
run around with your little buddies,
go play in the woods,
chase the birds, lick your...
Did I mention sleep?
You got a lot of nerve!
You all right, boy?
Why are you so upset?
- I'm helping you out.
- That's a load of crap!
We agreed on this.
You had a problem so l took charge.
I don't need you taking charge.
Mind your own business.
I don't need your help
and l don't want it!
It doesn't matter who brought him here.
I can do it, I feed him,
walk him and give him his bath.
- Eddie!
- No!
- See what you did?
- Me?
OK, thanks. Listen, Daphne's
here in case anybody sees him.
I got the guys at the station
circulating Eddie's picture.
- I'll look for him some more.
- You've done enough.
- Sit still and drink your tea.
- I hate tea.
In an emergency,
it's all I know how to do.
That's a real comfort,
coming from a health-care provider.
Dad, I'm sorry.
There was no luck at the pound.
They'll call if they find a dog
matching Eddie's description.
A $500 reward for Eddie?
Are you sure it's enough?
It's about 500 more
than l'd pay to get you back.
Dad, I said I was sorry.
I can't sit here.
I'm going back to the park.
What makes you think
he'll show up there?
That's his hangout. Didn't you have
a place where you met women,
a place where you got lucky?
- Well, I suppose so.
- Didn't you go back?
To the park!
This time we'll comb every inch
of it, every tree, every bush.
- Daphne, we'll need help.
- Call Niles. Tell him we'll pick him up.
Why go into the wild without
one of the great outdoors men?
Oh, this is odd.
l just got a psychic flash about Eddie.
- Well?
- It doesn't make any sense.
All I'm getting is a picture of Eddie
sitting with Dr Crane.
Dr Frasier Crane...
he listens
- Any luck?
- I couldn't find him.
- Where's Niles?
- We split up to cover more ground.
Scrunch down. If Eddie sees
you here, he'll run away again.
Let's call it a night.
You've been here three hours.
I was on a stakeout for 1 5 hours
without getting out of the car.
We had a contest to see
who'd last longest.
The winner was Canteen McHugh.
Know why we called him that?
I think I can guess.
His bladder was the size of a canteen.
Thank you for clearing that up.
You could have slung it
on your shoulder
and done a 20-mile march
through the desert.
- Big, huh?
- That's what I've been saying.
Close that window! It's freezing!
- It's like a blast furnace.
- At my age, you get cold easily.
Right.
Dad, I've just developed
a very interesting theory about you.
lf I begged you,
would you share it with me?
If that's your attitude, just forget it.
(Car phone rings)
Hello? Oh, Niles.
- Did he find him?
- Just a second.
Let me put you on speakerphone.
Hang on.
- OK. Go ahead, Niles.
- (Niles) 'I'm in the park and l'm lost.
- 'Thank God for my cellular.'
- Did you see Eddie?
'No, but I thought I saw a raccoon.
'When I stopped running,
I had no idea where I was.
- 'You've got to help me.'
- Niles, just remain calm.
Let me think back
to my Boy Scout training.
Now, we're on the northeast
corner of the park.
All right, look into the heavens
and see if you can spot the North Star.
Then you turn 12 degrees...
For God's sake!
Walk towards the horn.
(Car horn beeps)
'I hear it, Dad. I'm walking.'
All right. Just keep following it.
'I see a grove of trees and a fountain
'and a horrible hunchbacked
old man. Stay away from me!
'No. It was just a bush.
'Things are beginning
to look familiar. Keep honking.
(Car horn beeps)
'I think I'm homing in.
I'm quite sure this is the way.'
OK, you can hang up now.
That was a harrowing experience.
A shrub and a raccoon
and you live to tell about it.
Dad, I'm sorry I couldn't find Eddie.
I hope you understand.
I think I'd like to go home now
and hold my wife.
That is, if she'll let me.
I'll just hail a cab.
Call us from the curb
so we know you're safe.
You're probably tired.
If you want to go, it's OK.
That's all right, Dad.
I'll stay for a while longer.
I'm sorry I cut you off like that before.
I've just never gone in
for psychological mumbo jumbo.
Probably started on the force
when we had to see ''The Squirrel''.
Who?
Dr Bergman. The department shrink.
It was his nickname.
Guys got sent to him
when they got squirrelly.
He'd show you ink blots
and ask about your toilet habits.
I could talk about that
with Nat Dembrowski.
- We nicknamed him the Big...
- Thank you.
Look, it wasn't just Eddie
I was mad about.
Eddie was the straw
that broke the camel's back.
I'm always being told
to take my feet off the furniture,
put a coaster under my beer,
turn the TV down.
I used to make the rules
and now l follow them.
Does this make any sense to you?
Psychologically,
it makes perfect sense.
Slowly your responsibilities
have been taken away from you
and you... Well, you
feel...symbolically castrated.
Why does everything with
you shrinks start in the crotch?
All right, all right.
Well, maybe my rules are too rigid.
Maybe I should relax a little.
No, no. Hey, it's your house.
You do what you want.
I don't know what's bugging me.
I guess it's not easy for a guy
like me to not be in charge.
People confuse not being in charge
with not being respected.
I...hope you're not making that mistake.
Cos you command
a great deal of respect.
Every day I hold myself up
to the Martin Crane yardstick.
I guess a son always
wants to make his father proud.
Yeah, I guess.
So?
Yeah, yeah, you're doing fine.
Even if you are a big pain in the ass.
I don't know if I could have
made Eddie have that operation.
That's a tough thing for a guy
to do to another guy.
Amen to that.
You know, it's getting late.
What do you say
we get some sleep?
Eddie! Come here, boy!
Hey, attaboy! Hey-hey!
Good to see you, fella.
How are you doing?
- Welcome him back.
- Hello, Eddie. Good dog. Oh, wet dog!
You're shivering. Here.
We got to get you warmed up.
Dad,
that's a 100% cashmere pullover!
It's meant to be worn
with the collar up.
# Hey baby, I hear the blues are calling
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# Mercy!
# And maybe I seem a bit confused
Well, maybe, but I got you pegged
# But I don't know what to do with those
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# They're calling again #
Thank you.