Caroline, if you've had therapy
for two years without much progress,
perhaps you've reached a plateau,
or you and your therapist have done
all you can together.
(Caroline ) 'Maybe you're right.
He's kind of dry and long-winded.'
That's a long time to spend with a
psychiatrist who's dry and long-winded.
Amen to that.
'Thanks, Dr Crane.
l'll think about that.
'Would it be OK if l called back
and picked your brain?'
Just consider me your mental banjo.
That's it for this fine Friday.
This is Frasier Crane
saying we'll see you next week.
Good show, Frasier.
l've waited for this moment
for an entire week.
That's what l love about you.
You work hard and play hard.
l'm looking forward to this weekend.
Even conscientious psychiatrists
can have their fill of people's problems.
Hi. ls one of you Roz Doyle?
Yes. That's all the clues you're getting.
A little offering
from one of your suitors, perhaps?
A nice string of pearls,
a teardrop pendant...
lt's a brick of cheese!
On the right chain it should look smart.
lt's from my family. They're at
my uncle's dairy farm in Wisconsin.
- Why didn't you go?
- There wasn't time. Now l wish l had.
We have such fun.
Once there was this cheese platter
and my uncle spoke in cheese.
lnstead of saying, ''Hello. How are
you?'' He said, ''Hello, Havarti?''
Someone else would go, ''l'm Gouda.''
What would come after that?
lf l'd been there,
the sound of a gunshot.
(Sobbing) Don't make fun.
l miss those people.
There, there.
- We play games and sing songs.
- l know.
And Aunt Libby
does cannonballs into the lake.
The memories must be...
And Uncle Ned has too much to drink
and puts pants on all the cows.
lf you want family fun tonight, why
don't you come to my dad's birthday?
l forgot about it last year.
There's just one rule -
no work, just a good time.
- l wouldn't be much fun.
- l insist.
l enjoy partying with you
and l hate to see you like this.
l Camembert it.
How sweet.
All right! lt's someone's birthday.
l hope you're in the mood for a party.
l know l am.
- You're bloody impossible!
- You're a bloody nag!
Don't shake that cane at me!
For heaven's sake, not again.
l know what l want for my birthday.
Fire Daphne.
You'd have to rehire me first. l quit.
l hope l never see that hateful old
canker sore ever again.
- What is it this time?
- The usual.
l ask him to exercise
and he twists his face up like a baby.
You asked by pouring my beer away
and banging a pot with a spoon.
- l don't have to be your friend.
- Good.
l got a friend here
who isn't a yammering nag.
- Eddie, fetch!
- Stop this!
Pick your argument up tomorrow.
Tonight we're having a party.
l went to Emilio's. l got some
lemon cake, snacks, and champagne.
Can we agree to have fun this evening?
(Doorbell)
That'll be Roz. She's down
and in need of a happy environment.
l could use the same thing.
Can you just agree to a truce?
(Both mutter)
- Roz, hello!
- Hi, Frasier.
Hey, Martin. Happy birthday.
You didn't have to do this!
Thanks. l'll model it for you later.
He's already modelling one.
(Doorbell)
l have a nice evening planned.
Can we try to be civil?
You unprincipled charlatan!
You unconscionable fraud!
- Happy birthday, Dad.
- Thanks.
What are you talking about?
You spoke to a patient of mine today.
Caroline.
Due to your fast-food approach
to psychiatry, she left me.
Caroline was your patient? l...
Two years of my hard work wiped out
by your two-minute McSession.
l merely suggested
she consider a change.
Based on what diagnostic method?
One potato, two potato?
Fancy that. A member of this family
not taking the time to do something.
- Quack!
- Exactly, Dad. Quack!
- l was talking to her.
- Don't you raise your cane at her.
Wait! Roz, where are you going?
- l think l'd better leave.
- We were just talking.
l'd just rather be by myself.
Thanks, guys. l had a wonderful time.
- You've ruined her evening.
- Her evening? lt's my birthday.
Let's get that underway.
Who's ready for cake?
l don't want to keep you all here,
so let's get this over with.
Thanks for a great party!
(Niles) There's nothing wrong
with Dad's lungs.
(Daphne ) Every light in the city is out.
lt must be a blackout.
(Frasier) There's worse places to be.
(Niles) Like the elevator... Roz!
(Martin) Why couldn't it be Daphne?
(Martin yells after a crash)
Stop doing that!
(Daphne ) We need to get some light.
(Martin) Eddie, where are you?
(Daphne ) Excuse me, Dr Crane.
(Niles) Quite all right, Daphne.
(Frasier) Where are the lamps?
(Daphne ) They're in the kitchen.
(Frasier) Dad, light a fire.
(Daphne ) Excuse me, Dr Crane.
(Niles) Not your fault, Daphne.
(Martin) Where are you, Eddie?
(Eddie growls)
(Frasier) l've found him!
(Daphne ) That's better.
l'll get my radio. See what's going on.
Roz, are you all right?
l'm fine. The blackout hit as the elevator
opened on the 1 4th floor.
l stood there trying to decide
whether to come back up here,
or take my chances in the streets
with the muggers and the weirdos.
So l went down a couple of flights...
then l changed my mind.
Somebody's probably
looting my apartment.
There's a thriving black market
in badly designed Formica tables.
At least l have my own sense of style.
You won't buy a chair unless a fey
French aristocrat sat his fat fanny in it.
Louis XlV was not fey.
Everyone wore garters then.
- lf they were fey they did.
- He was a big man.
(French accent) Silence, enfants!
We can all sit in the dark and be
miserable or we can try having fun.
- l'll call Maris.
- Niles has voted. Who votes for fun?
l'm going to go get a glass of wine.
The steaks we were having are out.
l'll see what l can find.
- Sorry, Dr Crane.
- Excuse me, Daphne.
Power's out all over Seattle.
They're working on it.
Thank God l got you. Don't panic.
lt's important to stay calm.
About the blackout.
Maris, take off your slumber mask.
No, darling, don't panic. Honey.
No, honey, we're... Honey.
She's fine.
Yum scrum, pig's bum.
Here's something nice -
half-gallon tubs of vanilla fudge.
Let's have these right away
before they melt.
They'll stay cold for at least 24 hours.
Shut up!
l don't like to be nostalgic, but it
was great when you forgot my birthday.
What we need to do
is liven things up a little bit.
A game. What was it we played
at the Vanderkelins
while they costumed the servants
for the living chess match?
l remember!
lt was ''l'm the dullest person''.
Pick a game someone else
has a chance of winning.
That's got things shaking.
Come on, Dad. Come on.
The object is, we all get pennies
and we try to get
the other person's pennies.
Please, slow down!
All right, if l were going to go
l would say,
''l am the dullest because
l've never been on a roller coaster''.
Everyone who has been on
a roller coaster would give me a penny.
Now, we all have our pennies.
- Will you go first, Daphne?
- l can't think of anything.
Say whatever comes to mind.
''l'm the dullest person because... ''
Because l've never made love
in a lift or a phone booth
or on an airplane or a merry-go-round.
That's good, but it should be something
someone might have...
done.
l was in college.
l was trying to find myself.
You just needed
to look under the nearest man.
All right, Dad, get our pennies.
l'm the dullest person
because l've never been to France.
That's the spirit.
Niles? Something you've never done.
l'm dull because l've never
sabotaged my brother's career.
- Give it a rest!
- Your father could show you how.
(Arguing)
Will you stop? You are torturing
me! l could report you to Amnesty!
- l'm out of here.
- Where are you going?
To sit in the tub with a hair dryer
waiting for the power to come back on (!)
This blackout could go on all night.
l'll brave the streets and get back.
l hope it isn't like that storm.
l had to coax Maris from under the bed
by tying a Prozac to some string.
- You want to have a little cake?
- No, thanks.
This reminds me of Wisconsin -
all dark and deserted.
lsn't that on the licence plate?
What's the real reason
you didn't go? You've made it before.
Well... No.
You don't want to hear any more
problems and l don't blame you.
l think we have time
for one more caller.
Well, every year l go to my reunion
and my relatives crowd around me
and l answer the same questions.
''No, l'm not married.''
''No, l don't have kids.''
''Yes, l still have that tattoo.
No, you can't see it.''
lt'd be nice if l could at least say,
''l have a great career.''
You do have a great career.
Tell them that. They say l spend
four hours on the phone every day
with a bunch of losers and whackos
and then some tedious know-it-all
gives them pointless advice.
That's not me talking.
That's my Uncle Ned.
The cow haberdasher.
Roz, ten years ago,
KACL didn't have any women producers.
You're a pioneer. You've won awards.
You help people.
Sounds right when you say it.
There's more than your job. You should
explore other areas of your life -
interests,
or maybe a serious relationship.
Maybe you're right.
How long can l chase 25-year-olds
that are all looks and no substance?
- Exactly, Roz.
- l'm asking. Three, four years?
(Crash)
- (Daphne ) Oh, bloody hell!
- Daphne, are you all right?
l broke Martin's souvenir spoon rest
from Atlantic City.
Oh, good.
When l have my own kitchen l'll put
my spoons right on the damn counter.
l've always said,
when l save $2,000 l'll get a place.
- How much have you saved?
- 4,000.
l know what you're thinking.
What's wrong with me? Why do l stay?
l was thinking l'm overpaying you.
My friends say, ''You should be on
your own, have a place, have a life.''
Why do l stay here?
Could it be that maybe you...
you like us?
My grandmother had a cat, a mangy
old thing, kept ruining the furniture.
l asked her why she kept it
and she said she liked having
another heartbeat in the house.
lt just makes me feel
like l'm unambitious.
l could work in a hospital or a clinic.
Maybe that's not
what's important to you right now.
You like being part of a family.
What's wrong with that?
Nothing, l suppose.
Although my friends wonder how
l can live with such demanding men.
- They call me demanding?
- No, they call you a pompous ass.
- But you've learned that l'm not.
- No, l've learned to work around it.
l'm getting a beer.
l know it's bad for me, will make me
fat, and keep me from exercising.
- You have anything to add to that?
- Yes. Happy birthday, you old sod.
They try to confuse you on purpose.
Room temperature. Just like England -
another place l'll never get to.
You mentioned going to Europe
when your hip improved.
Now you say you'll never get there.
What's changed?
My hip's the same as then.
l thought l'd be better
but l'm not and probably never will be.
You're happy just sitting on your can,
doing your show, living in your head.
l'm used to being out there.
Eddie!
Listen, Dad,
you can still travel.
No, you can. lf you can't
walk around Paris, you could...
sit at a nice café
and let Paris walk past you.
Maybe buy a drink
for a beautiful mademoiselle.
Get a nice bottle of imported beer.
- l only like Ballantine's.
- ln Paris, Ballantine's is imported.
And you are the
handsome Américain...
with the adorable accent.
They like moustaches, don't they?
(Breathless) 1 9 floors down to my car.
Garage door's electric. Can't open.
20 floors back up. Lost count.
Bad lady upstairs. Big dog.
Need place to die.
- (Roz) Same to you, buddy!
- Who are you talking to?
Some rowdy guys downstairs.
Come on, l want you to introduce us.
- Keep your pants on.
- Let me take your coat.
- Haven't you taken enough from me?
- You're being irrational.
- Sticks and stones.
- You're acting like Dad.
You take that back!
You're not really mad at me.
l didn't tell her to leave you.
l merely suggested it as an option.
lt was her choice.
Could it be you're upset
because you couldn't help her?
l hate it when you take a criticism
and turn it back on me.
- l think l'm right.
- You are. That's why l hate it.
Do you know what l went through
trying to help her?
Yes, l think l do.
Niles, you're a perfectionist.
As faults go,
that's not such a bad one.
Just would've been nice if l'd been
the one to say it was time to go.
lnstead, she heard it from a glib,
albeit insightful, radio pundit.
Those guys
invited us to a blackout party.
- They got cold beer.
- And Jarlsberg.
l was feeling a bit down,
but suddenly l'm in a party mood.
- What about our party?
- There are people downstairs.
- Come on, Frasier.
- No, thank you. l'm not in the mood.
- Don't be a party-pooper.
- Let him be. He was always that way.
Maybe it's time for a lesson about
living the life of this party-pooper.
l spend the whole week
ministering to the troubled,
the neurotic
and the sometimes plain goofy.
Then l hang up my earphones
and it doesn't end there.
On the street, at the café,
even in this building...
more people come up for help.
They think it's OK. lt's what l do.
But every time l help them
it costs me a piece of myself.
A little here, a little there...
Till l feel like a zebra carcass on
the Serengeti surrounded by vultures.
This was one of those weeks.
l had my escape planned. l was coming
for an evening of fun with my family.
But l get you four going at each
other like the Borgias on a bad day.
So l roll up my sleeves,
tending to each one of you,
and you all feel better.
The minute you get the whiff
of mesquite from down below...
you are out the door
without so much as a ''thank you''.
Well, thank you for the invitation,
but l'm fed up with people's problems.
The doctor is out.
Oh, come on.
- Apologies accepted.
- Great! So you'll come?
No, no...
l love you all. l really do.
But l want to be alone, here,
where no one needs anything from me.
- Well, all right.
- l'll bring you some barbecue.
Oh, my God. lt's dark out here.
Oh, for God's sake.
No, l'm not going to do it.
# Hey baby, l hear the blues are calling
# Tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# Quite stylish!
# Maybe l seem a bit confused
# Well, maybe...but l got you pegged!
# But l don't know what to do with those
# Tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# They're calling again #
Frasier has left the building.