Look at this. My so-called
windproof umbrella. Look! Look!
l'd have fared just as well
with one of those paper ones.
l collect those. They remind me
of great evenings l can't remember.
- City College wants you to lecture.
- Fine. Just tell me the date.
OK. St Bartholomew's Hospital
wants you at their benefit.
- Pass.
- Turning down a hospital?
Yes.
Don't look at me that way.
l'm with you. l hate how whiny,
sick people are always nagging.
''l want a magazine. l want a kidney.''
Roz, l sympathise as much as you do,
which is why l said yes last year.
l bought an Armani tuxedo, wrote
a speech, put off a visit to Frederick.
Then they didn't need me.
Their first choice had become available.
The irrepressible Kathie Lee Gifford.
- Way to hold a grudge!
- This is not about spite.
This is about dignity,
a rare and fragile thing. Anything else?
- Judging the Miss Seattle Pageant?
- l'll do that.
- That's dignified.
- A scholarship is involved.
All right.
You're on in ten seconds.
Look, we have new sponsors.
Work this copy in as often as you can.
Good afternoon, Seattle.
This is Dr Frasier Crane. KACL 780.
lt's a grey, depressing day
in the Emerald City.
Let's hope we can brighten up
your afternoon.
We hold it our duty to banish
your rainy day blues.
First, a message from a new sponsor.
''Death is inevitable.
''But it's especially painful
when it claims a beloved pet.
''lf you've lost,
or are planning to lose...
''...a cherished dog, cat or bird,
''let Pet Paradise console you
with a memorial
''bearing the likeness
of your departed friend.
''Pet Paradise. Though your pet
may be small, your loss is great.''
- Who's our first caller, Roz?
- Edna.
She's a receptionist
at a pest control firm. She's depressed.
Hello, Edna. l'm listening.
(Edna) 'Hello, Dr Crane. l've worked
in pest control for 1 5 years.
'l go in every day, answer the same
calls, ask the same questions.
'''What kind of bugs?
Have you seen any droppings?''
'Then l go to the next person.
''What kind of bugs?'''
Edna, l can sense where this is going.
Even the most interesting life
can become routine.
You need to shake up your world.
Find a new boyfriend,
a new job, a new city.
- 'You mean, move?'
- Well...
There are easier places to cheer up
than this dreary, soggy city of ours.
'Dr Crane, you're right.
l don't have to stay here.
'When you think about it, there's
a whole world of vermin out there.'
Eloquently put, Edna.
Thank you.
Speaking of vermin...
''When that special rat of yours
''turns its toes up for the last time,
''don't forget your friends
at Pet Paradise.
''Pet Paradise.
When a shoe box isn't enough.''
Another radiant morning.
What do you think, Dad? Should l
drive to work or hail a gondola?
l like rain. lt gets those
squeegee guys off the street.
Now, stay put
until l can dry off your feet.
There. That ought to do it.
Daphne, get that hat off him. lsn't
it bad enough we had him neutered?
At this rate,
l don't think l'm going to have children.
Just let me dress up the dog.
l've never seen him look that stupid.
You'll change your tune when you see
his St Patrick's Day outfit.
Hey, Derek Mann mentioned you
in his column.
''l listen to Frasier Crane because
l'm trying to drop a few pounds.
''His voice is an effective
appetite suppressant.''
- How witty.
- l thought so, too.
Give me that.
''Yesterday he advised
an unhappy woman
''that she could cure her depression
by leaving Seattle.
''lt would cure my depression
if the Seattle-hating Dr Crane
''would take his own advice
and leave town.''
- Ludicrous! l never said that.
- Yes, you did.
You said Seattle was dreary
and she should leave town.
lt was one of several suggestions
taken out of context.
- Apologise.
- What for?
For insulting Seattle.
People take pride in it.
They don't want you telling them
it's rainy and depressing.
lf you hadn't noticed,
it gets a bit damp here.
For God's sake,
the state flower is mildew.
Listen, a city's like a woman.
Get one mad at you
and it doesn't matter who's right.
You apologise
or you'll be paying forever.
- l don't care for that analogy.
- l'm sorry. l was way out of line.
All right, you're forgiven.
Dad, to you,
everything is like a woman.
A fast car, a romantic song...
A good meat loaf is like a woman.
A city is not like a woman,
it's like a city. And l'm not apologising.
lf you don't understand,
Seattle does.
Seattle loves Frasier Crane.
(Thunders)
- Hello, Father Mike.
- Hello.
Dr Crane was not bashing Seattle.
He was sincerely trying
to help that woman.
Who's our sponsor?
Pet Paradise.
Go ahead and boycott them.
See how easy it is to flush
your dead dog down the toilet.
Was that a complaint
about the rain thing?
l've been on the phone all morning.
Forgive me.
l'll stick to subjects like suicide
and stay away from controversial stuff
like weather.
- Hello?
- Hey, Doc, l need some advice.
l feel a cold coming on. Should l
take vitamin C or leave Seattle?
l hope you're happy. The switchboard
has had over 50 irate calls.
50? Damn! You broke my record.
The most l got was 35
on my commentary,
''Lady umpires: finally
a chest worth protecting.''
- Frasier, think about apologising.
- l would if l'd said anything wrong.
l've got half a dozen calls
that say you did.
l don't want to talk to them.
l don't know how to break this
to you, but it's a call-in show!
(Woman) 'How can you say
Seattle is depressing?
'l've spent 40 years here, working the
graveyard shift at a salmon cannery.
'And, let me tell you,
you fatheaded moron,
'l'm the most cheerful person
you'll ever meet.'
Certainly the most cheerful
one l've met today.
Alas, we're out of time.
l'd like to say,
as l've been saying for three hours,
that it was not my intent
to cause offence.
Since it seems obvious that l have,
l would like to apologise.
l do not find Seattle depressing.
lt would take more than clouds
to obscure her beauty
and more than drizzle to dampen
the warmth and fellowship
that make Seattle the only place
l care to call home.
Till Monday, then,
this is Dr Frasier Crane, signing off.
Good grief! Have you ever heard
such whiny, provincial crybabies?
This city has lost
its rain-addled mind!
Dr Crane, we're still on the air.
Thank you, Roz.
Now, we're off.
(Niles) l believe this goes here
and that attaches there.
Are you sure
you don't want me to try?
No, you might crack a nail
or snag a cuticle.
- There. Are we getting anything?
- Does annoyed count?
Hush. lf you hadn't bashed it with
your cane when the Seahawks lost,
we wouldn't need a new set.
lsn't there a manual?
Yes, but unfortunately, Stephen
Hawking isn't here to explain it.
- l thought the winds had eased.
- They have.
- What happened to your umbrella?
- A listener recognised me.
He pulled it through a fence.
You would not believe the hostility,
even at the Café Nervosa.
l thought l heard a new cappuccino
maker, l saw three tables hissing!
(Phone )
- Don't answer it.
- l can't abide a ringing phone.
lt's another crank.
They've been calling all day.
Oh, no! They've got my number?
So, the phone rings.
We don't have to answer it.
Although it could be Frederick,
or Grammy Moon to say her hip's out.
We can't be slaves to a bell.
Just because it's going
ring...ring...ring!
or, in the case of a British phone,
ring-ring...ring-ring
ring-ring...ring-ring!
- Just answer it!
- Thank you!
Crane residence.
He can't come to the phone.
May l take a message?
Nice language, that!
l hope you don't eat with that mouth.
Daphne, excuse me.
How dare you speak to a lady that way!
Well, that's no excuse, ma'am.
Only cowards make threats by phone.
l dare you to say that to my face!
Never mind where l live.
(Door rattles)
ls anyone expecting visitors?
l suggest we all remain very quiet.
l have this image of angry villagers
wielding torches and pitchforks.
- Frasier, open up! lt's Roz.
- lt's worse than l thought.
- Why are you out in this weather?
- l called, but your line is busy.
- Hey, Roz.
- Hey, Martin. How are you?
- Good.
- New TV?
Got it hooked up yet?
No.
l let Niles take a crack at it first.
God! Martin, you're awful.
Frasier, the station manager
came by.
lf you can't smooth this over,
he may have to suspend you.
- What would he put in my time slot?
- The best of Crane.
What will they do the second day?
How can l smooth it over?
This city is out to lynch me.
A guy cancelled on me cos l work for
you. You're alienating my boyfriends.
We can't afford to lose
a demographic as large as that.
We need damage control.
lt's not too late to call St Bart's Hospital
and do their benefit.
- After the way they treated me?
- There will be lots of media.
lt's a chance to redeem yourself.
- Listen to Roz.
- Dad!
- Take my advice.
- l did. l apologised.
Oh, so sincerely!
You'll make a few jokes
and self-deprecating remarks,
help sick people
and show you can laugh at yourself.
- l think it's a brilliant suggestion.
- Niles, did you compliment me?
lndeed l did. You're very sawy, Roz.
You remind me
of those amoral PR flacks
who sell their services
to industries that pollute.
- You think it's a good idea?
- lt worked for Nancy Reagan.
She was widely criticised
for lavish spending,
so she appeared at a dinner
in thrift store clothes
and performed ''Second Hand Rose''.
- That made people like her again?
- Yes, briefly.
Tell them l'll MC. Better yet,
l'll take a table at the banquet.
l have.
Give the nuns 800 bucks.
- 800!
- Don't mess with them.
l'm in a precarious position.
l must choose my material carefully.
- l know some good jokes.
- No, Niles. You don't.
lf you need jokes, use some of mine.
Oh, yes.
l'm sure the nuns would love that.
And l'll ask call Bulldog
and ask for a couple of limericks.
l'll call Father Mike. l'm sure
he knows some inoffensive jokes.
Hello.
Yes, well, l don't care how you feel.
l want to use the phone right now.
Your grandmother's hip is out.
Just kidding!
Kidding!
l do hope you'll have
some humorous stories for us,
though, of course,
nothing too racy or risqué.
- l wouldn't dream of it.
- Good.
Last year, Kathie Lee Gifford
told a most unfortunate story
involving newlyweds and a ski lift.
Hello, all. Thank you for coming out
for such a good cause.
St Bart's did my hip surgery.
They treated me good.
l just saw Frasier. He seems nervous.
There's a lot riding on this.
Thank goodness he's got that
sweet old nun there to comfort him.
She's not sweet.
lt's Sister Joselia, the scrubbing nun.
- ''The Terror of Ward Three''.
- You still remember her?
You know the nightmare
where l scream, ''Not the sponge!''?
That's her!
- As a girl, l considered being a nun.
- What changed your mind?
l didn't want to work weekends.
- Where did Maris go?
- Mrs Crane is over there.
She's cornered Lydia Beaumont,
head of the museum board.
- Maris wants to get on the board.
- Lydia's getting away.
The ''freshen-the-drink'' ploy. Lydia
has no idea with whom she's dealing.
Chug that sherry, Maris.
On with the chase! Yes!
She's gaining!
lt's Mrs Beaumont and Maris...
And yes! They meet again.
They'll be board-mates
before the dessert.
- Evening, everyone.
- We were saying you look confident.
- Really?
- Absolutely! Forehead.
- You memorise the jokes l gave you?
- Yes. That's why l look so confident.
Shouldn't they have started?
We're waiting for the Bishop
who's introducing me.
He'll be here any minute. Break a leg.
Remember, keep smiling and look like
you're having a good time.
- Right.
- lf a joke bombs, pay no attention.
Do what Johnny Carson did,
make a joke about it.
''Bomb-o!''
Boy, l miss that guy!
Your dad's right.
Go up and be confident.
l will, after l find a men's room.
- lt's butterflies in your stomach.
- Not for long! l'll be back.
Good evening.
l'm Father Mike Mancuso
and l've just been asked
to make a very sad announcement.
Every year, our speaker has been
introduced by Bishop Cologie,
our chairman and host of the cable
TV show ''Pancakes and Parables''.
We've just heard that the Bishop
has had a terrible accident.
He was out fishing this afternoon
when his boat was hit
by a storm and capsized.
At the moment, he remains missing.
l'll keep you informed.
Why does everything happen
to Frasier?
Devastated as we are, we know what
this evening means to the Bishop
and how he'd delight in entertaining us
with his biblical hand shadows.
We also know he would be the first
to insist that we proceed without him.
So, l'm going to step in
and introduce our speaker.
Won't you extend
a cordial and gracious welcome
to my friend and colleague,
Dr Frasier Crane.
Dr Crane? Dr Crane?
Ah!
Thank you very much, Father Mike.
lt's an honour to be here.
l expected the Bishop to introduce me
but l'm sure he'll drift in soon.
lt's a real comfort to see
so many priests out in the audience.
l don't dare speak in public
without someone standing by
who can perform the last rites.
Whoa! Very religious crowd, l see.
l can tell
because of the vow of silence.
Got some holy water, Father?
l'm dying here.
And speaking of water,
that reminds me of a little story.
A rabbi, a minister and a priest
are all sitting at the bar
on the Titanic.
Dr Crane! The Bishop!
l heard the story with a priest,
but what the heck? A bishop's funnier!
Thank you, Sister. OK, then...
A rabbi, a minister and a bishop...
...are at the bar when the purser
rushes in with the news...
Frasier, the Bishop is lost at sea!
Are you telling this story or am l?
- Frasier...
- l work alone, lady, all right?
Anyway, the purser rushes in
with the horrible news about the boat.
The rabbi says, ''My people need me.''
The minister is leaving when
the priest says... Sorry, the bishop...
...says, ''Have another drink.
The rabbi can handle it.''
The minister says, ''You abandon your
flock when we've hit an iceberg?''
The bishop says, ''An iceberg?
l thought he said we hit a Weisberg!''
Hello? ls this thing on?
Bomb-o!
# Baby, l hear the blues a-calling
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# Oh, my!
# And maybe l seem a bit confused
Yeah, maybe...but l got you pegged!
# But l don't know what to do with those
tossed salads and scrambled eggs
# They're calling again
# Scrambled egg's all over my face!
# What is a boy to do? #
Thank you!