-Hello, Niles.
- Frasier, listen to this.
"Michael Hawkins
of Allentown, Pennsylvania,
has donated his right lung
to his younger brother, Clovis."
"Says Hawkins, 'l got two lungs,
but I only got one brother'."
Isn't that something? The
love one brother feels for the other.
What do you want?
I need you to come
to a dog show with me.
I would rather give you a lung.
- Latte, please.
- Frasier, I beg you.
It's at the Seattle Kennel Club
tomorrow night and Maris will be there.
In what class will Maris be showing?
She'll be showing no class.
As she has ever since
she hooked up with Dr Schenkman.
It's my first time seeing them
since we filed for divorce.
Here's an idea, Niles. Don't go.
If I don't go people will think I've
let Maris and Schenkman intimidate me.
I want to prove that I'm strong and
independent and I can't do that alone.
All right. If it's moral support
you need, I'll go with you.
I'll pick you up around eight.
And I have a patient. Thank you.
I knew I could count on you.
Some things never change.
Do you know where I can get
a cheap hotel room?
Case in point. Goodbye, Roz.
Why do you need a hotel room?
They're still painting my new place.
I can't be around those fumes.
And they've rented my old apartment.
Grande decaf latte, please.
I am on the street.
You ordered a $4 cup of coffee.
"On the street" may be a tad dramatic.
I've got to call around,
see if I can find something.
Dad is going to San Francisco for the
weekend. You could always stay with me.
That would sure make things easier. OK.
Well, then, that's settled.
That's that, then.
You didn't really
expect me to take you up on it.
No. I wouldn't have offered
if it wasn't something I wanted to do.
- All right.
- Here you go. And there's your check.
- I'll get that.
- No, let me get that.
OK, thanks.
Lucky me.
I'm getting everything I want today.
- It's about time.
- Calm down, Dad.
I was getting worried.
My plane leaves at five o'clock.
- Your blood pressure medicine.
- I don't need it.
Pack it anyway!
What's this? Earrings?
I picked them up for Daphne at the
drug store. She ran some errands for me.
- Nice. Are they sapphires?
- Yes. I always buy precious stones
at the same counter where I pick up
corn pads and Wart-Be-Gone.
- Shouldn't you be going?
- There's something I want to give you.
A token of my appreciation.
- Dr Crane, you remembered.
- Of course I did.
Can you believe it was five years ago
today that I came to work here?
I knew you wouldn't let an important
occasion like this go by unnoticed.
- But I wasn't expecting a gift.
- Well, it's a tiny gift.
Oh, my God! Sapphires.
- Actually, Daphne...
- These must have cost a fortune.
My friend Molly got a diamond bracelet
from her boss
but she worked for him for ten years
and she was sleeping with him.
I got sapphires and
I didn't even have to sleep with you.
Although now that I've got
the sapphires... What am I saying?
Is it rude if I go and try these on?
I have to see what they look like.
I've never had real jewellery.
I'm speechless.
Dear God,
she believes they're genuine sapphires.
- You think?
- I'll have to tell her the truth.
Why? Didn'tyou see how happy she was?
I can't let herthink
I gave her something I didn't.
Honesty between friends
is far more precious than any gem.
I feel like a princess.
I'm never going to take them off.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
You even remembered
that sapphires are my birthstone.
- There's no end to your thoughtfulness.
- Somebody has to keep track.
- I should be getting to the airport.
- I'll get my keys.
No, absolutely not. I'll drive Mr Crane.
You're not lifting a finger. You ring
for the elevator, I'll grab me coat.
My flight's at five. They told me
to get there an hour early.
- Did you pack your medicine?
- Yes, but I told you, I don't need it.
- Hey, guys.
- Frasier, help her with that stuff.
- Thanks for letting me use your room.
- No problem.
So you're off to San Francisco?
Duke and l
took our shore leave there in '52.
- Going to re-trace our steps.
- Sure sounds like fun.
We had a great time. No place like
'Frisco for a guy cruising the streets
Iooking for a good time.
You know, Dad, I think you'll find that
'Frisco hasn't changed all that much.
Well, I hope not. Bye.
Hey, Roz. Just off to the airport.
Back in a bit. See you later.
Come in. You're earlier than I expected.
I had to get out sooner than I thought.
I left you a message.
I didn't check my machine
all day today.
Thank you so much for this.
You won't even know I'm here.
You have 13 messages.
I had my calls forwarded.
I hope you don't mind.
Hey, Roz, it's Marco.
I'm coming to town. Are you busy
Saturday night... Iate? Call me.
Obviously Marco and I haven't talked
for a long time.
Something tells me
you never talked for a long time.
Roz? This is Paula Garrett, Rick's mom.
We just found out about the baby,
and we think it's important to meet you.
We're seeing Rick in Paris
day after tomorrow,
so any time before then would be fine.
I'm running out now.
Maybe I'll try you later.
Oh, my God. What do they want?
They want to meet you.
They are your child's grandparents.
I worked this out with Rick.
He's 20 years old, still in college
and it's best
if I raise this baby by myself.
I've got to put up with in-laws
and I don't even have a husband.
That's like posing nude for your art
teacher and still flunking the course.
Shut up, I needed the credit.
- All they want is a short meeting.
- That's what they say now.
What ifthey want another one
after that?
What if they don't think
I'm a fit mother?
What if they're nice, supportive people?
I just don't want to do this, Frasier.
It's not comfortable.
Roz...
I could go with you... ifyou like.
Better yet, we could have them here
tomorrow night.
Niles and I have that dog show at eight.
They could come before that.
I don't know.
- I'll be that's Mrs Garrett.
- I'm not here.
Hello? Yes, she is.
Yes, she did get your message.
No, I'm afraid
she won't be able to meet you.
Yes, I understand that you're upset.
I'm terribly sorry.
Goodbye.
Thank you, Frasier. Thank you.
That was Marco.
Now we're calling Mrs Garrett.
All right, give it to me straight.
How do I look?
Like Pollyanna grew up
and got herself in a little trouble.
Why am I doing this?
How did I let you talk me into this?
It will mean a lot to them.
You can learn about your baby's lineage.
A lot ofthings are inherited, you know,
like intelligence, artistic ability...
- I've got to check my make-up.
- Roz, this should be fun.
It's like a little preview
ofwho your child might be.
Hi, there. Steve Garrett.
- My wife's just... Honey?
- It was nice seeing you, too.
What a coincidence. Your neighbour
goes to my hair salon. Hi, I'm Paula.
Frasier Crane. Won't you please come in?
Roz will be out in a second.
She just went to powder her... self.
We hope this isn't too awkward for her.
She sounded anxious on the phone.
Who could blame her? She doesn't
know what kind of people we are.
A situation like this is enough
to make anyone a little nervous.
Roz isn't the nervous type.
Roz? This is Steve and Paula Garrett.
We don't blame you for being shocked.
We're used to it.
You should see the looks we get.
You were taken aback,
weren't you, Dr Crane?
- Certainly not.
- Everyone comments on it.
I must admit when I opened the door l...
Couldn't believe we were old enough
to have a 20-year-old son.
Exactly. You know, you both look
so young, don't they, Roz?
Yes, young. Very, very young.
Roz, you're uncomfortable but we have
no intention of intruding on your life.
Rick told us how wonderful you are.
We just wanted to offer any help or
support you think is appropriate.
Thanks. That's very nice.
I thought your guests
might be a little peckish.
Daphne Moon, Steve and Paula Garrett.
Hello, l...
I know, it's amazing.
They are the parents of a 20-year-old.
Amazing.
Excuse me.
Niles, you're early.
I thought you might want to grab
a bite to eat before the dog show.
I'm sorry,
I didn't realise that you had...
Company. Steve and Paula Garrett,
this is my brother Niles Crane.
The Garretts are the grandparents-to-be
of Roz's baby.
- Nice to meet you.
- Did I hear you mention a dog show?
The Seattle Kennel Club
is having its annual event.
Steve and I went to that a few years
ago. We have two giant Schnauzers.
My goodness, Paula, look at the view.
Roz, show the Garretts the view.
That would be nice.
I could use a breath of fresh air.
Just stop it, the two ofyou. You're
acting like a couple of two-year-olds.
- I'm home.
- Dad. What are you doing here?
'Frisco was a bust.
All our watering holes are gone.
The steakhouse was a sushi bar.
And Duke and I went out for a walk.
We passed City Hall
and there's this big crowd,
like a pep rally or something.
So we joined them. Some official guy
says something that we didn't hear.
Then everybody's throwing rice
and all the men are kissing each other
and all the women are kissing each other
and I'm not sure,
but I think Duke and I may be married.
The whole weekend was like that.
Just one surprising event...
- I'm sorry. Did we startle you?
- No, I didn't know we had company.
Dad, this is Steve and Paula Garrett.
They're Rick's parents.
Hi, how are you?
Nice to meet you. Marty Crane.
They're just on their way to Paris
to visit Rick.
That sounds like fun.
I'm just a little nervous. I hear
the Parisians can be kind of snooty.
Excuse me.
I've got something in the oven.
- Let me help you.
- Yeah, me, too.
We've got to stop. They'll hear us.
- Mmm, what's that I smell?
- Probably Japan.
What is the matter with you people?
Don't say you don't think this is funny?
They are two perfectly nice people
who happen to have large noses.
Sniggering like school children.
Ifyou can't get yourself under control,
you can just stay in here.
- Quiche Lorraine, anyone?
- Quiche her? I hardly know her.
- That smells wonderful.
- Does it ever.
Is this homemade or store-bought?
Honey, don't ask that. Pardon my wife.
Sometimes she gets a little nosy.
Me nosy? You're the nosy one
in the family.
Anyone who knows you knows you're nosy.
Anyone who knows you
knows you're nosier.
Something wrong, Fras?
Quiche her, I hardly know her.
I just... got that.
In spite of a shaky beginning,
this evening's turned out rather well.
Yeah. And you were
absolutely right, Frasier.
Now I can see some ofthe qualities
my baby can have.
A great sense of humour
and a sweet disposition,
a nose like an anteater.
You're making a big deal out of nothing.
Rick had a fine nose. And so do you.
I'm sure your baby will have one, too.
You're right. If Rick can beat
those genes, my baby has a chance.
How long have you been
working for Dr Crane?
Five years yesterday. He gave me
a beautiful pair of sapphire earrings
- to mark the occasion.
- Frasier gave you sapphires?
- Who's for coffee?
- I'll take some.
You must show those earrings to Steve.
He's a jeweller.
He could probably even tell you
what mine the stones came from.
Maybe coffee's a bad idea.
You've got that early flight.
Daphne, could you take this
back in the kitchen?
One of me earrings must have fallen off.
- We'll help you find it.
- What does it look like?
Once you've seen one sapphire,
you've seen them all.
That's not true.
They vary widely in quality.
Why don't you just get up
and we have to get going.
We have plenty in here
to form a search party.
- We'll just trample each other.
- We do have a big day tomorrow.
You might as well
get a little sleep before you take off.
I might be able to replace the earring.
Let me see the other one.
I found it. Here it is.
I knew I would. Bon voyage.
- Dr Crane...
- No, Daphne, just a second.
It was wonderful of you to come.
Thank you for having us.
Roz, it was great meeting you.
- Our door is always open.
- Have a great trip.
- Good night.
Can I have it then?
I'm sorry, it was just a piece of lint.
Well, the search continues.
The one precious thing anyone's ever
bought me in my whole stinking life
- and I lose it.
- Daphne, I found it.
Dr Crane, I could kiss you.
OK.
- What's this?
- Nothing.
The setting's come loose. It's only blue
on top. The bottom's all coppery.
Dr Crane.
I know what you're thinking,
and you are right. Obviously, l...
You've been swindled.
Where did you buy these?
I want to take these back and tell that
lying cheat exactly what I think of him.
- Actually, you just did.
- You knew?
- Niles, how about a cup of coffee?
- Thanks, Roz. Cream and sugar.
I'm terribly sorry, Daphne.
I actually meant to tell you eventually.
You didn't need to.
Her earlobe's turning green.
Daphne, the truth is
I didn't remember your anniversary.
I saw them and I thought they
were pretty. So I bought them for you
and you thought theywere genuine.
You seemed so happy, l...
They are pretty.
I suppose I can have them repaired.
I'll just take them back
to the jewellery store.
Actually, I bought them at Raymond's.
Raymond's Drug Store?
The good news is they'll probably
carry something for that ear infection.
I almost forgot.
Roz, I brought you something.
I thought you might get a kick out
of these pictures of Ricky as a boy.
Thank you. That is so nice ofyou.
- Where is he? I don't see him.
- There, in the middle.
- He looks so different.
- That was before his hockey accident.
The nose job changed his whole face.
The doctor did a good job, but
that's the Ricky you'll see in the baby.
- Well, thanks.
- You're welcome. And bye again.
- Take care now. Good to see you.
- Thanks.
Oh, my God!
Come on, Roz.
It can't be that bad. Let me see.
- No, I'll never hear the end of it.
- Please.
Where is the end of it?
Roz, you're not still looking
at that picture, are you?
No, this is a different one.
Look at the way the ears
on this poor little girl stick out.
It's me. Age nine.
The year before I got them fixed.
Sorry, Roz. I didn't recognise you
with those glasses.
- Why is one side blacked out?
- I had a lazy eye.
I got that fixed the next year.
Let's just say for birthdays,
I wasn't asking for ponies.
You poor thing.
What if my kid gets Rick's nose
and my ears and eyes?
With my grandfather's third nipple,
I might as well pitch a tent
and charge admission.
Nothing like that's going to happen.
I just hate the idea
of my kid being teased.
I know what that's like. As long as
my baby's in here, I can protect it.
But pretty soon this kid's
going to be out there on his own.
Every child goes through a bit of
teasing. It's part of growing up.
At least yours will have a mother
who understands what it feels like.
And you'll know what to say
to make it better.
I really hadn't thought of it that way.
I'm good at finding
the positive in things.
Look at what happened to me tonight.
I could say I worked for someone
for five years
and he forgot my anniversary and bought
me a worthless piece of blue glass.
But I'd rather say
he gave me a nice pair of earrings
just because he thought I'd like them.
Which is sweet when you think about it.
- Frasier will be relieved to hear that.
- I'm not going to tell him.
- I'm ready for bed.
- Yeah, me, too. Thanks again, Daphne.
You're welcome.
I just felt a big kick.
You sure it wasn't a sneeze?
It's the last one. I promise.