I suppose you looked
in the classifieds
under "housekeepers."
Check.
And you asked people
in your building?
Check.
And you called
the employment agencies?
Again, check.
I heard you
the first time.
Well...
Who'd have thought
it'd be so hard
to get someone
to clean your house?
Well..
.
over the years
Daphne has managed to scour
her way into our heart,
so to speak.
Just don't want to hire somebo
who's in it for only the money
.
So you want to find someone
who's in it
for the joy of cleaning?
Ah. May I?
Oh, of course, Gil.
Take a load off.
Nice outfit, Roz.
Somehow, you and a peasant
blouse just go together.
Thanks.
Haven't worn it
for years.
But how long can something
stay in the closet?
Say, uh, Gil...
uh, are you pleased
with your housekeeper?
Oh, you mean Chung?
Oh, yes, he's marvelous.
He's efficient,
he's dependable,
and he still hasn't figured out American money.
Between you and me,
I told him
when they made Lincoln's picture bigger,
it was worth more.
(chuckles)
Very funny.
Do you suppose that
your man Friday
might be available
on a Monday or Tuesday?
You want to steal my Chung?
No, no
Not-Not steal him.
Just borrow him for
a day or two a week
until I can restaff.
A dangerous notion,
Frasier.
You know how employees gossip
about their benefactors.
Well, I have nothing to hide.
Yes, but suppose
while on your premises
he lets something slip
about me and Deb
and our heart-shaped bed?
I would refuse to believe him.
Did I mention he's a drug mule
?
Oh, he is not.
You're just saying that
'cause you don't want
to help me out.
Such insight.
It's a pity more people
don't listen to your show.
several other candidates
to interview,
but I'll be sure to let you know
by the 12th.
Of never!
Honestly, I'm beginning
to wonder
if we'll ever find anyone that meets our standards.
You're being too picky.
It's just housekeeping,
not rocket science.
DAPHNE:
I beg to differ.
You don't even know half
of what I used to do
around here.
Like dusting the plant leaves
or rotating your underwear.
Excuse me?
Every month, I used
to throw out your
oldest pair
and put in two
new pairs.
Did it ever occur to you
that you never had
to buy underwear
in ten years?
I thought I got hold
of a good batch.
FRASIER:
Well, let's see.
Who is our front-runner,
thus far?
(wearily):
Oh, I don't know. I...
.
They're all the same to me
Honestly, Dad, you know,
I am starting to get
the slightest bit chapped
with your attitude.
You haven't even graded
any of the candidates.
You've simply doodled
a warplane
dropping bombs
on a soldier.
(doorbell rings)
That's not a soldier.
Well, then why is he
wearing a helmet?
That's not a helmet.
It's someone with a big head
Yes?
Hi, I'm Trish Haney.
I'm here about the housekeeper job.
I'm really sorry I'm late.
I had you down
for over an hour ago.
I know. I got stuck in line
waiting to buy tickets
for the Sonics game
this weekend.
Really? Come on in.
I should have guessed
everyone and his brother
would want to see
Vince Carter play.
Not everybody... or his brother.
Wow, this is
a beautiful place.
Here's my resume.
Ah, thank you.
Won't you be seated?
I'm Dr. Frasier Crane.
This is my father,
Martin Crane,
and this is my sister-in-law,
Daphne Crane.
Now, I'll get right
to the interview.
First question:
What is the best way
to combat rings
on a wooden table?
Um...
I've heard
you can rub mayonnaise on it.
The best way is to
provide coasters.
An ounce of prevention is worth a pound of cure.
(laughs)
Started me out with
a trick question, right?
So how do you think
the Sonics will defend Carter?
Um, you have to have someone
body up on him
and then double-team
when he gets the ball.
Thank you.
DAPHNE
: Trish...
if the washing machine
has a 25-minute cycle
and the dryer
has a 40-minute cycle
what time does the second load
have to go in the washer
to be dry by 5:00?
Uh, well, that's 65 minutes, so 3:55.
You may want to take some time
to think about these questions be...
FRASIER:
Daphne...
she's right.
Well done.
Hey, I got a question.
Can you clean a house?
Yes. And if I do say so myself,
I'm pretty good.
Next question:
Can you start Monday?
(chuckles)
You know, we're getting just a bit
ahead of ourselves
We still have
several people to meet.
Uh, thank you for coming by.
Oh, sure.
That was the interview, huh?
Two questions?
Well, it was really more
of a pre-screening.
We'll be sure
to let you know.
Okay, thanks.
Just so you know
I'll be out of town
till the first.
...
Fine. Then I'll be sure to call you the second
I lose my mind.
What? What was wrong with her?
In the first place,
she showed up late.
If she doesn't take
the interview seriously
how can we expect her
to take the job seriously?
Ah, you just don't like her
because she's not all stuffy
She did seem a bit cheeky.
Which you never were.
Well, I'm afraid so far,
our best candidate
is the young man
from Jeepers Sweepers.
I will move out if you hire
that prancing moron.
All right, fine.
Who would you hire?
This-This-This Trish, I suppose?
Well, I was right
about Daphne.
Doesn't that count
for anything?
You didn't even want to hire her.
You thought she might steal.
Did you really say that?
Of course not!
I don't remember.
MARTIN:
Well, whoever gets hired
is someone I'm going to have to
spend a lot of time with
and I don't need
a lot of quiz questions
and score sheets to get
a feel for someone's character
Did I look like a thief?
Was it my shifty eyes?
Look, if you don't trust
my judgment, Frasier,
just have the guts
to say so.
No, all right.
Fine. You can hire whoever
you want to.
You want this Trish?
Fine, call her.
Great. I'll call her right now
and tell her she's hired.
And I'll tell her
where you keep
your valuables.
FRASIER:
Oh!
Would you give it a rest?
Hey, Niles.
Have a seat.
Thank you.
I'll have my usual.
Oh, no, uh, bottled water,
room temperature.
Hey, slow down, little man.
What are we celebrating?
I can't drink anything
that's too hot.
I have a toothache.
Oh. You been to the dentist?
Yes, but he said
the tooth is perfectly healthy.
I still have
this throbbing pain.
Oh, it's probably just a sinus infection
Have you had a cold lately?
A couple of weeks ago, yes,
but I'm-I'm over it.
It's probably what it is.
A sinus infection.
It happens to me
all the time.
In all likelihood, I'm sure
you're right.
Thank you.
Of course I'm right. What else could it be?
Actually, a toothache
can be referred pain
from something else.
Referred pain?
That's right.
For example, if I had
a heart condition
I might not have pain
in my chest.
I might have pain in my tooth,
you see? Referred pain.
So, while you're
probably right about the sinus infection
let's not discount
the one-in-10,000 chance
that it might be something
more serious.
Oh, now I get it.
So the pain in my butt
might actually be coming from across the table.
Something like that, yes.
Oh, look.
I'm the winner of a fanny pack.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
You have no idea
what it is, do you?
Uh, not really, no.
Hey, look.
It says here
the odds of winning it
are one in 10,000.
Ooh... spooky.
Same odds as
that toothache
being a heart attack.
Maybe it's a sign.
It's a good sign.
By beating those odds once,
it makes it that
much more unlikely
that something so improbable
can happen to me again.
WOMAN: Niles.
Mmm.
Hello, Daphne.
Okay, that's weird.
MARTIN:
So, that's the grand tour.
Hard to know where to start.
I don't have much time
before I have to go.
What? You're leaving already?
Yeah, um,
I have this lunch thing.
I hope you don't mind.
Well, the problem is
it's this friend
that I've been putting off
because I've been too busy
but now I finally don't have any excuse.
We're going to try
that new rib place
down in Belltown.
Oh, I hear that's great.
Yeah, I can bring you back
a great big bag of them.
But enough chit-chat.
I've got dishes to do.
(chuckling)
Yeah...
Oh, hold on.
Can I offer a suggestion?
You're the boss.
What Daphne did was
put a load of laundry in first
and that way you can do
two things at once.
Okay. Although, I prefer
to do laundry
at the end of the day,
and that way I can read
when the clothes
are in the dryer.
I mean, it's about the only "me" time
I have on this job.
Hey, Dad.
Ready for breakfast?
Well, thanks for the invite,
but I can't go.
We didn't invite you.
You called us and badgered us
until we rearranged our schedule.
Yeah, well, that was before
Trish came.
I really think I should hang
around and show her the ropes.
Maybe you should show her where
the room freshener is.
It smells like
stale cigars in here.
I had some of the guys in
last night for poker.
Oh, hey, Niles!
Check this out.
Got a great new card trick.
Oh, goody.
Yeah. It's called
"The Amazing Niles"
or "The Amazing..." whoever
you're doing the trick with.
Like if I was doing it
with Daphne
it'd be "The Amazing Daphne."
If I was doing it with Frasier,
it'd be...
"The Amazing Frasier."
Yeah, I get it, Dad.
Yeah.
That's just my patter.
Okay...
Okay, Amazing Niles,
I want you to draw
the ace of spades
out of this deck.
Uh, something tells me
that it's going to be this one right here.
Ooh!
Ladies and gentlemen,
he drew the ace of spades.
Amazing, Amazing Niles.
Isn't that a great trick?
Hey, wait a minute.
How come this deck only has
aces of spades?
What? No, this is the tri...
Wait... wait a minute.
Uh...
This isn't the trick deck.
Holy cow!
Wh...
You just drew the card
I asked you for.
What are the odds?
I wonder if you could do it again.
No. No, no, no, no.
Only... only one
performance a day.
Is something wrong?
What?
No.
Oh, you know, since we're not
going to have breakfast
maybe we should go.
All right.
That way we can pick up
your car from the shop.
What happened to your car?
It got struck by lightning.
Okay, washer's running as we speak.
Anything else before I go?
You going to lunch now?
It's only 10:00.
Already?
I guess the dishes
will have to wait.
I've got a couple
of errands to run
and then I have
a hair appointment.
Trish, I'm a little surprised
that you're taking off
like this.
I'm a little surprised, too.
I thought my first day
would be more like
orientation, you know?
Show me around,
explain my duties
and then I start work
the next day.
Why would you think that?
Well, it's been that way
every other place
that I've worked,
and I've had alot of jobs.
Well, listen, Trish, I kind of
went out on a limb for you
and I'll never hear
the end of it from my son
if you let me down.
Don't worry.
You are not going
to regret hiring me.
Tomorrow morning,
I'll be like the White Tornado
Remember those commercials?
White Tornado?
That'll be me.
Ten o'clock.
So you're not coming back after lunch?
Oh, trust me. You don't want me
cleaning this place drunk.
(laughs)
Oh, and that reminds me.
I don't work Mondays.
Gosh, you know,
I better get going.
If I'm late to this lunch,
how's that going to look?
What about the laundry?
10:00 tomorrow,
along with those ribs.
Well, I hear
the washer going.
I assume that means
our new employee is hard at it.
Oh, yeah.
She's like the White Tornado
Dad, you know your basketball references
go right over my head.
You know...
she's certainly got
her work cut out for her
cleaning up this mess
you and your buddies
made last night.
Well, you don't have to worry about it.
She's all about the work.
Listen, Dad,
I think I owe
you an apology.
For what?
Well, for thinking
I was a better judge
of people than you are.
Just want you to know that I do
trust your judgment.
Maybe I don't say that
often enough.
Anyway, I hope
you can forgive me.
There's nothing to forgive, son.
Thanks, Dad.
I'll see you later.
Not now, boy.
We've got an apartment to clean.
Hi, Niles.
How's it going?
I'm as good as dead.
I've been doing research
into my family health history.
My great-uncle Timothy
keeled over from a heart attack
at my age.
Bottled water. Please.
Are you talking about that tooth again?
It's still throbbing,
thank you.
Which means my heart is probably
on its last legs.
Come on, Niles, you said it was
a one-in-a-million chance.
One in 10,000, and I've been beating
those odds all week.
I don't believe in omens,
but these are getting
harder and harder to ignore.
So are you.
I flipped a coin 17 times
last night,
and every time it came up tails.
I only stopped because
I was getting a blister.
Thank you.
How does Daphne put up with all this?
I haven't told her about it,
'cause unlike you,
she'd worry about me.
Get your heart checked
and stop obsessing about it.
I'm going to.
In all probability, there's a
there's a perfectly
reasonable ex... (gasps)
What?
I won another fanny pack.
No, I'm not mad at you, Trish.
I'm just a little disappointed
Well, yesterday it was
your neighbor's funeral
and today you got the flu.
No, I kind of believe you,
but...
You know, this apartment
doesn't clean itself, so... Huh?
Okay. Tomorrow.
9:00 sharp.
10:00? Okay.
Well, I'll see you
when you get here. Okay, bye.
(doorknob rattling)
Oh, for God... sakes...
Hey! Careful, mister!
You're going to get
water all over a clean floor
You know, maybe you can have Trish
wax this floor
tomorrow, huh?
She already did, and
it took her two hours!
And it just took you two seconds
to mess it up
and start complaining.
Well, I'm not complaining, Dad
but look at the streaks here.
It's like she never
waxed a floor before.
All you do is nag, nag, nag.
Meanwhile, she tried a new fabric
softener on your sweater
and you didn't even notice.
Well, my sweaters are supposed
to be dry cleaned.
Oh.
Oh, and remind me
to say something to her
about flipping my mattress.
What the hell are you trying
to do, kill her?!
Easy, easy, Dad.
There's no reason
to get all riled up.
My God,
you're actually perspiring.
Well, I just think
some people around here
don't realize how hard she works.
--
Well, I'll say this much
the place does smell lemony fresh.
Shows what you know.
It's country breeze.
Daphne, I...
have to go out for a while.
All right.
No place out of the ordinary--
just... out.
Okay. See you later.
I can't believe this is happening.
After all those misspent years
of frustration and yearning
I finally find the fulfillment
of my dreams...
only to have it snatched away.
Look at her.
She's so beautiful, so perfect
She deserves nothing but happiness.
I hope when I'm gone
she's able to make a life with someone else.
After a suitable period
of mourning, of course.
Niles?
Yes, my love?
When are you going
to change the paper
in the bottom
of the birdcage, hmm?
I've asked you three times already.
Soon as I get back.
Maybe when I'm gone
Her Majesty can muck out
her own birdcage.
Hey, Fras, sorry to bother you.
Uh, Trish was wondering where
you keep the silver polish.
Right.
I told her about that tarnish
on your shrimp fork.
She suggested a place you could keep it
where the air won't get to it.
Really? Perhaps she and I should
have a discussion about that.
What are you doing here?
Well, my lunch canceled.
I thought I might drop by,
see if
you'd like to join me
for a bite.
Oh, sure. Love to.
Let me get my coat.
Right. I'll just tell Trish we're leaving.
Where is she?
Oh, uh, she's in the powder room.
Let's go
Actually, I-I'd
rather wait, Dad.
You see, I wanted to discuss
a new vacuuming pattern with her.
Uh, well... actually, Fras,
this might not be a good time.
Uh, that shrimp fork thing
really set her off.
She kind of went to pieces
and locked herself in there.
She did?
I had no idea she was so fragile.
.
Well, she'll get over it
She just, uh, needs
to be alone for a while. Uh...
She'll be fine.
Uh, bye, Trish.
No, no, Dad,
you know what?
If I've hurt her feelings
then it is incumbent
upon me to apologize.
Well...
Trish, it's Dr. Crane.
Could you come out here, please?
I'd like to have
a word with you.
The old silent treatment.
Well, two can play that game.
Let's go.
No, no, Dad.
Why don't you talk to her?
Oh, I don't think so.
Please, Dad, she likes you.
Please.
Uh, Trish?
Hi. It's Marty.
Uh, listen,  I know you're upset
but I'd like to talk to you.
Yeah, um...
would you unlock the door?
That a girl.
All right, you just take
all the time you need.
Okay, well,
she accepted your apology
but she just wants to be alone
for a little while
so, uh, let's go.
Dad, I really should apologize
to her in person.
Well, uh, I don't think
this is the time.
Why not?
Well, you have been
pretty critical.
Well, you know, I also think that she's made
some real improvements around here.
Tell her that.
(sighs)
She wants an example.
How should I know?
Make something up.
Oh, no wonder she's mad,
you ungrateful son of a bitch!
MARTIN:
All right.
See you later.
Well, now I think
you've made things worse
It wouldn't surprise me
if she didn't come in tomorrow
You didn't tell me you had a sister.
Dad!
All right,
what the hell is going on?
No idea. I just came by
for my paycheck.
MARTIN:
Well, uh..
I got some bad news about that, Trish.
I'm sorry, but we're going to have to let you go.
Oh. Okay.
But you still owe me
for the days I was supposed
to be here last week.
Sure, sure, and there'll be
a check in the mail
sometime after the first..
asteroid hits Earth.
Okay, lay it on me
I'm-I'm prepared for the worst.
Is it my heart?
I'm afraid so.
Aha!
What?
There is an anomaly in your EKG.
I'm going to have
to check you into
the hospital.
Oh. Uh, well, hm.
Uh, I guess I can clear
my schedule.
Uh, how's, uh,
how's tomorrow afternoon?
No, no, no. Niles?
Hm?
You need to go right now.
♪♪ Hey, baby,
I hear the blues a-calling ♪
♪
♪♪ Tossed salads
and scrambled eggs ♪♪
♪♪ Mercy ♪♪
♪♪ And maybe I seem
a bit confused ♪♪
♪♪ Well, maybe,
but I got you pegged ♪♪
(laughs)
♪♪ But I don'’’t know what to do
♪♪
♪♪ With those tossed salad
s and scrambled eggs ♪♪
♪♪ They'’’re calling again
. ♪♪
Good night!