We'll be right back
with Julia Wilcox
and our new stock market update
after this.
That's it?
That's your big introducti
on for Julia?
What happened to the copy
I wrote for you?
Come on, "Julia" does not rhyme with "moolah."
Well, they're spelled
the same.
Oh, they are not. Stop it.
Isn't it enough that she's getting ten
minutes of my show?
Hey, hey,
we're lucky to have her.
Don't be surprised
if she ends up
boosting your
ratings a notch.
Yes, but at what cost?
The woman's credibility
is questionable.
She's credible
.
The woman was on CNBC.
She had a
syndicated column.
You can't hold one
mistake against her.
What'd she do?
She wrote a book called
Day Trade Your Way Out of Debt.
Apparently, some people
lost money.
I don't see you
writing any books.
Now, listen,
she's a little sensitive
.
So, I don't want hear anyone talking about the book
how it ruined her career
that guy who killed
himself in Pennsylva...
Hey, hey, hey!
There she is!
Our financial wizard.
This is Dr. Frasier Crane.
Hello.
And his producer
Roz Doyle.
Hi.
Nice to meet you.
So, this is my mike?
Yes, yes.
You know, I studied
finance in college.
Hey, that's great.
Do you think you could
get me some coffee, Rizzo?
It's Roz.
Super.
Two creams. Thanks.
So, um, do your intro,
we'll go to a promo
then back to you.
Got it?
Intro, promo, you.
So you don't want me
to do the intro last?
Uh, no, because
you see, intro's short...
(chuckles):
Oh, I get it.
Very good.
You got one past me.
Enjoy it, it's not
going to happen again.
And these would be
my phones.
Yes, yes, of course.
I must say that
I enjoyed your
work on CNBC.
I thought you were
an insightful analyst.
And I don't believe that you were treated fairly.
Oh, thanks.
That makes everything
all better.
Ten seconds.
Oh, thanks.
(coughs):
You call this coffee?
Most of it.
(chuckles)
Roz.
Put that over there.
Hello, Seattle
Welcome back.
If you've tuned in
for mental health advice
with an erudite twist,
But now for something new,
as finances can be the cause
.
of that old bugaboo-- stress. Here now..
Good afternoon,
I'm Julia Wilcox.
Today's market swerved
like a nervous student driver
before finally winding up
in a nice, safe neutral.
Are pharmaceutical stocks
still worth prescribing?
Now this.
Excuse me.
I was supposed to introduce you.
You were cutting into my time.
Well, I was giving you
a hospitable segue.
You see, I thought that
since you're new here
I could lend you my
equity, if you will.
It was just
a courtesy.
Some days on the market
it's black Friday,
but today
with the Nasdaq
slightly down
and the Dow slightly up,
it was more like
plaid Monday.
Analysts spoke out
of both sides...
Next time I'll get the coffee.
Julia's book.
Listen to this
"Chapter Four
How to Sell Your House
and Start a Dot-Com."
Hey, guys.
Oh, Roz, I can't believe
you shelled out three dollars
to revel in someone
else's misfortune.
I was curious.
Well, you can get the same thing on tape for $1.50.
Get this
it's read by Martha Stewart.
How's that
for your double whammy?
(laughing)
We should just get rid of her.
I mean,
if she were nice
it'd be one thing.
But she's just rude
and arrogant.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, nobody's getting rid of anybody.
She just filed suit against CNBC
for wrongful termination.
Legal wants us to treat her
with kid gloves.
Truth be told...
I actually feel sorry for her.
She has suffered
a very public fall.
She must be carrying
all kinds of guilt
about the people who lost their
savings following her advice.
You know, perhaps I shou
ld have a talk with her.
I wondered how long
it would take.
What?
For you to make your move.
I thought there were
some sparks between you two.
What are you
talking about?
Don't play innocent.
She is right up your alley.
Smart, tough...
total bitch.
You can't wait
to break through
that wall and rescue her.
Oh, Roz, you couldn't
be more off the mark.
Typical man.
You always want to get in there
and rescue us.
But the minute things get messy,
you just can'’’t handle it
Ha!
Women want to make us
think that they're tough.
And then all of a sudden,
they get needy.
Men are like, "Come on, baby,
you can lean on me.
Oops, got to go."
."
Yeah, women are like, "Get away,
get away. Don't leave me
Here's men:
(deep groan)
Here's women:
(helpless squeal)
(deep groaning)
(squeals)
All right, stop it, both of you!
Hello, all.
Hello, Niles.
How's it going?
We're just
discussing a new
rather unpleasant colleague of ours.
Be thankful that
you're self-employed.
You don't have to
deal with these headaches.
Oh, not so.
I was hoping to come here
and complain
about my office remodel.
I'm annexing
the dermatologist's
office next door.
And in a cheap irony,
my skin is breaking out.
Oh, your spackle allergy again?
I'm covered with tiny bumps.
It's worse than the summer
we added the breakfast nook
to the tree house.
Could I have my usual?
Thank you.
ROZ:
There she is.
Don't come over,
don't come over,
don't come over.
Oh, look who's
too good for us.
You know what?
I think I will
go and offer her
an olive branch.
(low groan)
Oh, stop it.
(helpless squeal)
Knock it off.
Hello, Julia.
Hello.
Listen, I, uh...
I'm sorry that
the two of us got off
to a bit of a frosty start.
But I think that in time
we will have a very long
and rewarding relationship.
Okay.
May I tell you a story?
(sighs)
Years ago, I lived in Boston.
I was in private practice then
and life was very good.
And then my wife left me.
I ended up on a ledge,
threatening to throw myself off
if she didn't return to me
Thank you.
Well...
this got on the news,
of course.
And needless to say,
after that
patients were a little
hard to come by.
So...
just wanted you to know
that I, too, have suffered
a very public setback.
Oh, I get it.
You're letting me know
I'm not alone.
Exactly.
And now we
can be friends.
.
Well, if that's how you feel
Let's see, how do I feel?
Well, it's sort of like
on your show
when you call people at home
to give them advice...
Actually, I don't call them, they call me.
Exactly.
Well.
Good day, then.
Why would you let Niles
bring all his patients
to your home?
It's only
a couple more weeks
until his office
is finished.
Well, I sure wouldn't want
to have all those crazies over.
I mean, what if one of them
starts screaming obscenities
or running through
the house naked?
Mum already did that when
England lost in the World Cup.
Hey.
Hello, all.
Hello.
How was the Wine Expo?
Horrible!
Frasier ran into a fan.
Ow, that smarts.
Yes, Dad.
You have been using
that same old joke
for the last ten years.
So anyway, I ran into
this fan...
Ouch. Are you okay?
So, this woman
complimented me
on my so-called
chemistry with that harpy Julia.
Have you ever heard anything
more preposterous?
Good lord, the woman sneezed
once and I said, "Bless you."
That has been the extent
of our byplay.
You've been complaining
about her so much lately
I'm beginning to wonder
if there's not
something deeper there.
I will not even dignify that
with a response.
Except to say that you
couldn't be more wrong.
.
I don't know, Frasier.
She's certainly attractive
And she's intelligent,
ambitious, tenacious...
Sounds like your
perfect woman.
She is a cold,
insufferable know-it-all.
And the list goes on and on.
All right, that's it.
No more talking
about Julia.
Oh
so it's "Julia" now.
(teasingly):
Oh...
It has always been Julia.
That is her name.
She does seem to have you
disproportionately upset.
You haven't been
so consumed with one subject
since Frasier Crane Day.
Listen, my outrage
is completely merited.
That woman is
deliberately trying
to undermine my show
from within.
I am sorry to disappoint
all of you
but I have absolutely
no feelings for that woman
except contempt.
There he goes again.
You know what they say about
people who protest too much?
I know what you used to say--
"They should
all be teargassed."
I still think that, you know.
Ah, here you are.
Listen...
It's time the two of us
had it out.
Ever since you arrived here
you have been nothing but
condescending and dismissive.
Whatever.
There, you did it again.
You know what this
is really about?
It's about you losing 15 minutes from your precious show.
What are you talking about?
It's ten minutes.
Sorry. Starting Monday, I do
the last 15 minutes of your show
with a half-hour recap
on Fridays.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have places to be.
No, I will not
excuse you.
I am reaching out to you here.
Yeah, will you cut that out?
It's like you're trying
to make me your special project.
Why don't you just adopt a cat or something?
As your colleague
I do not deserve
to be treated this way.
Oh, no, we are
hardly colleagues.
I deliver the news and you're a..
Magic Eight Ball
with a Harvard degree.
(gasps deeply)
I will not be belittled
by a half-educated
money-grubbing parvenu!
As opposed to some
foreign-speaking windbag!
That makes you
an insecure fraud!
You are a pompous
blowhard!
Harridan!
Know-it-all!
Shrew!
Snob!
Are you as turned on
as I am?
What? No!
Did you just
come on to me?!
What? No... No, I thought...
I thought that...
How could you think
I was turned on?
What, are you sick?!
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
let's all calm down here
Are you crazy?
No, I apologize!
I... I...
(disgusted groan)
Oh, hey, Dr. Crane.
How...
They hate me, don't they
Can you blame them?
Because of you,
they had to come in here
for this sexual harassment
seminar.
(sighing):
I know.
But I have apologized
till I'm blue in the face.
I know, but Legal wants us covered
in case Julia tries to come after us.
Maybe you've heard:
She loves suing
people's asses off.
I'm going to miss saying "asses."
After today, I guess
it's back to "patootie."
Thanks a lot, Doc.
Hi. Welcome.
Please take a workbook
Hey, Frasier.
Mmm.
Thanks for ruining my weekend.
Oh, Roz...
Come on, you know
it was just a mistake.
What do you think I am,
some sort of
disgusting Lothario?
Hey! There's my man!
Welcome. Please
take a workbook.
Got an old one.
Hey, I know you're down.
Don't sweat it.
Rookie mistake.
By the way, the chick
at the coffee table's
got her high beams on.
(barks)
(clears throat)
KENNY:
Okay, people, let's get this started.
Uh, first of all, I apologize
for bringing everyone in here today,
but to make it up to you,
everyone attending today will get a free mousepad.
How's that?
ROZ:
It sucks.
All right,
who said that?
I did.
Fair enough.
Now, I don't want
to blame anyone...
(sneezing):
Frasier!
...but Legal says that we have to do this,
so here's Van Andrews
from "Harassment Solutions."
...
Okay, guys
I'm Van,
I'll be your facilitator
and if you could go ahead and
just open up your workbooks,
we'll get started on building
a truly gender-neutral
workplace, okay?
Now, who wants to meet
my puppets?
(everyone groaning)
STEVE:
Wow, this is great!
I like coming over to your house.
It's really nice.
Thanks.
since we're doing stuff
at each other's houses now
Uh, thanks for the offer, Steve,
but this isn't a social call
We're having
our regular session.
I really
want this to feel
just like the office.
Okay. Um..
Well, I've been having
my dream again. Uh...
(knocking)
Uh, yes?
Sorry to interrupt,
Dr. Crane
but I got to run
these toilet fixtures
past you.
Your wife said you definitely
want to be consulted about that.
STEVE:
I never pictured you
having a bathroom!
Um, it isn't a good time
If you...
I'm sorry, I didn't realize your session had begun.
Why don't you just wait
in the living room?
Okay, but just
so you know
the heated seat you want's on back order.
Again, I'm sorry, Niles, but while I have you here
do you want anything
from the shops?
No. I'm good.
Okay, then I'm off.
Happy therapy.
(clears throat)
So, back to your dream.
Your wife seems nice.
She's foreign.
That's weird.
And then, I guess it shouldn't be.
I mean, it would only make sense
that you have a wife
and a bathroom and...
and you probably have
a bed and laundry
and that thing
I can't talk about.
Refrigerator.
Right.
Okay, well, we're not really here to learn about my life,
we're here to talk about you,
so... back to your dream.
Okay, um, well,
I'm in this forest...
(phone rings)
Do you want to get that, or...?
Nope, nope, it's okay.
The machine'll get it.
Uh, now, you remember,
as we discussed
the forest could be a symbol
of uncharted territory.
Um, could be...
DAPHNE (on machine):
♪♪ Nobody's home... ♪♪
NILES (on machine):
BOTH ("Beethoven'’’s Fifth"):
♪♪ Nobody's home, nobody's home,
nobody's home ♪♪
♪♪ Nobody's home,
nobody's home, nobody's home ♪♪
♪♪ We'll call you back,
if you leave your number ♪
♪
♪♪ After you hear
the (beep). ♪♪
So, uh, next week at your place.
(weak laugh)
Okay, Bulldog, in this exercise,
we're going to pretend that you have an
attraction to Roz.
Is that okay?
Well, Van, I feel
a little uncomfortable
about violating
her personal space
even for role-playing, but... okay.
Okay, Roz.
Bring it on.
Ok
Go.
Good morning, Roz.
You're looking
professional today
Thank you, Bulldog.
You're looking
professional today, also.
Why, thank you.
After work, would you care to join me for a coffee
or non-stimulating beverage?
Please note you retain the option to say no
Excellent, Bulldog.
Roz?
Thank you, Bulldog,
for you offer,
but I'm uncomfortable with it
as I would prefer to cut
my own arm off and eat it.
Can I have a turn with her?
No, sorry, buddy.
She's not your property!
It's up to Van!
I want a turn!
BULLDOG:
Sit down, Noel
Oh, oh, what are you
going to do, huh?
Oh, what are you
going to do?
Guys, guys, let's keep our dialoguing constructive, okay?
I think we're done here.
Why don't you go ahead and..
Oh, great.
...have a
seat, okay?
Um, I'd like to say something.
Okay, go ahead, Gil.
From the bottom of my heart,
I apologize for
my wandering eye
over the years.
Those whom I mentally undressed and...
you know who you are..
all I can say-- and it's a poor defense--
is that I was a product of the thoughtless
machismo of my times.
Thank you, Gil.
But know this:
Gil isn't about to stop loving the ladies.
VAN:
Uh, thank you, Gil
I think they like
to be called women now.
Ha! Do they ever!
How much longer do we have
to sit for this nonsense?!
Well, Frasier
since you're the one
who brought us here today
maybe you'd like to take a turn in the
warm seat, hmm?
Julia, would you be comfortable
in helping Frasier
learn how he could
have related to you
in a more office-
appropriate manner?
Uh... Julia?
She's playing solitaire
on her palm pilot, Van.
Oh, all right.
VAN:
Okay..
in this "no-fault" rewind
let's find out
how Frasier assaulted you.
I did not
assault her!
I simply expressed unhappiness that
she was taking 15
minutes from my show.
She responded by
belittling my profession.
And then he called me
a couple of names
and asked
if I was turned on.
VAN:
Okay, gang
where did Frasier go wrong?
(murmuring, snapping fingers)
Uh, Bulldog.
People stopped saying
"turned on" 20 years ago.
No, look, look!
I just misread
her... her signals!
I-I thought that
her hostility was
displaced attraction.
No, it was just hostility.
Well, of course it was
That's all the
re is to you.
Ever since you arrived
at this station
we have reached out to you
in friendship
and all we've gotten in return
is arrogance
and unbridled rudeness!
It's not rudeness,
it's indifference.
I'm sorry I'm not joining your bowling team
but this is just a pit stop
for me.
I do not intend on spending
the rest of my life
at a station that cuts out
whenever the janitor vacuums!
Ooh.
No offense
None taken.
And I don't even
know why we're here.
I'm not going to sue your stupid station.
I mean, how pathetic
would that look?
How dare you.
At KACL, we are a family.
Every person in this room respects one another..
No, no, no, hold on
a second, Doc.
I'll handle this.
You mentioned something about
not suing us.
Would you put that in writing?
If it gets us out of here.
Sure. That should satisfy Legal.
(happy murmuring)
Okay, wait, wait.
This course isn't about Legal, okay?
It's about making respecting
each other's
personhood fun
ROZ:
Up yours!
Who said that?
ROZ:
I did!
You know, you can act
as tough as you want
but I see through you.
Really.
You're not in the
big leagues anymore.
Blame it on the market
Blame it on bad luck.
But somewhere in the
back of your head
is that nagging voice that keeps saying
maybe you weren't good enough.
And now that you are here,
you won't form relationships
You keep everybody
at arm's length.
Anything to convince yourself
that this is just a stop
along the way.
And above it all,
I think you're terrified that
you're going to fail here, too
Then what do I know?
I'm just a magic eight ball with a Harvard...
and Oxford degree.
It's 45 past the hour
which means it's time once again for the woman who...
(clears throat)
.
...is known
as Julia Wilcox
Thank you, Frasier.
Another up day
for the markets.
But first, these words
from Patriot Credit
Consolidators.
How many times
do I have to tell you
you need to get
a comfortable chair in here.
My leg keeps falling asleep
while I'm on the air.
Who doesn't?
Frasier...
perhaps if you're
at Nervosa later,
I could join you
for a cup of coffee?
Or a non-stimulating beverage?
Please note you retain
the option to say no.
I appreciate that.
And, in time, I believe we will
be able to establish a...
a collegial relationship.
However, I think we
should both acknowledge
the feelings of hostility that remain between us...
Oh, just say no.
Honestly, do you ever shut up?
Now, see here, I..
The rich got richer
today on Wall Street.
Not news, ordinarily,
but after their recent slide,
today's rally
in large cap
does take on a certain
"man bites dog" quality.
Speaking of dogs...