Well, I think we've got time
for one last caller.
Go ahead, Mindy, I'm listening
.
(softly):
It's about my mother, Dr. Crane.
Ever since I got married
she's been...
Yes, the cashmere
turtleneck is $39.
Excuse me, what?
Sorry, I work in catalog sales
and my boss just walked past.
So anyway, my mom...
Yes, it's on sale until
the end of the month.
Mindy, we are
pressed for time.
Hold on, Frasier.
Cashmere for
under 40 bucks?
I'll take one
in black.
In medium.
Wait, is that medium-medium
or unrealistic-
anorexic-model-medium?
It sounds like you might
want to go for the large.
Oh, really?
And that's our show.
What size will Roz order?
Will she accessorize?
Tune in tomorrow for
the exciting conclusion.
Good day, Seattle.
Dynamite show, Doc,
one of your best.
Rosalinda, great work
on the control panel.
I'm going to start
calling you "Control Freak."
Well, you're probably
wondering
"Who put a quarter in him
today?"
Just got a call
from my lawyer.
My divorce: final.
I'm back
to my tomcat days.
Lock up your daughters, Seattle.
Kenny Daly's on the loose!
You might want to lose
the wedding ring, tomcat.
Oh, yeah.
Time to remove my shackle.
Well, that's weird.
Ooh, that's really stuck.
That's funny.
That's how my wife described our marriage.
"Stuck."
Well, you're not
stuck anymore, are you?!
Oh, damn it, damn it.
Kenny, Kenny,
come on, come on.
Come and sit down.
All right, here.
Take a deep breath.
I'm sorry.
This thing's hit
me like a ton of bricks.
The only good news is I'll start getting a check every month.
Kenny, um...
divorce can be one of life's most difficult transitions.
Have you considered
seeing a professional
once or twice a week?
I thought about it
but prostitutes are expensive.
He means
a psychiatrist, Kenny.
That is what
you meant, right?
A shrink?
Oh, geez Louise.
I don't think I'd be comfortable talking
to a psychiatrist.
Well, I'm a psychiatrist
You're comfortable
talking to me, aren't you?
Are you offering
to be my shrink?
No.
I could probably handle that.
I was going to refer
you to someone.
Well, can't you
help him, Frasier?
Well, I don't know, Roz.
Giving psychotherapy
to my employer?
It's a bit
of a gray area, isn't it?
Oh, come on, it's not
like he's a real boss.
Yeah, Roz is right.
Come on, Doc, I could use a little help.
Well, I suppose if you'd like to stop by my place
and discuss your feelings
informally,
there'd be no harm in that
Thanks, Doc.
And I'm paying
you for your time.
Oh, no, no,
that's hardly necessary.
No, no, no, no, no, I insist.
Now what do you get?
Kenny, don't worry about it. I'll gladly do it for free
What do you say we get together
Friday night?
Thanks, Doc.
I wish my ex-wife
was as agreeable as you.
And dead.
Okay, maybe tonight's better
And the one time I was winning
my dad "accidentally"
knocked over the checkerboard.
Ah.
He made me pick up
all the pieces, too.
Fortunately, my mom was there
with an extra piece of cake.
(cries)
I see.
A controlling,
narcissistic father
and an overprotective mother.
It has all the earmarks
of a classic
Oedipus complex.
Well, well...
old friend, we meet again.
Now let me tell you
your deep-rooted feeli
ngs of castration...
(watch timer beeping)
I'm afraid
our time is up
Wait. What?!
This has been fascinating.
I believe we are
finally on the brink
of discovering a road
into some real insights.
I can't tell you
I believe I'm as
exhilarated as you are.
Yeah.
When are we going
to talk about my divorce?
You may not know it, Kenny,
but we already are.
Now, for our next session,
I want you to write a letter
telling your father
how you feel.
Don't send it, just write it.
Homework? You never
said there was going
to be any homework.
It's all part of the process
Good night, Kenny.
But I...
Geez, I thought
that'd never end.
Dad, how long have you
been in there?
The whole damn time.
I went in for a beer
and Kenny came in and started crying
and I was trapped.
How's talking about checkers
supposed to help him
through a divorce?
Dad, the inability to maintain
adult relationships
often has its roots
in parent-child trauma.
What's your generation going to do when we're all gone
and there's no one left
to blame?
I really can't tell you
how exciting it is
to roll up my sleeves again
and delve into someone's psyche.
I don't even
know where to begin
Although, you know,
I do think it's
particularly salient
that the father never showed any interest
in the things that were
most important to his son.
Sounds good, Fras. Bye.
Oh. Hey, Martin.
Oh, hi, Kenny.
I didn't know you were here.
How's it going?
Okay, I guess.
I have an emotionally
crippled father.
You don't say.
So where are you headed?
Uh, gonna grab a beer
at McGinty's.
Really?
Well, I'm sure dehydrated after all that crying.
You mind if I tag along
with you?
(elevator bell dings)
Sure, why not?
Oh, thanks, Martin
I really appreciate it
(cries):
I bet you were a great dad.
Oh, geez.
If you want to learn yoga,
why do we need some
fancy private teacher?
There are classes we could take
together down at the Y.
Yes, and afterwards
there are anti-fungal lotions
we can use together, too.
Just give Ahmrit a chance.
If we don't achieve physical and spiritual harmony,
the second lesson's free
Oh, hello, you two.
Hey, Frasier.
Hi.
Ooh, Freud,
Bettelheim... Jung?
Someone's playing
with the big boys.
Yes, well, it's for my patient
You're seeing patients again?
Well, just this one
for the last three weeks.
Very challenging case, too.
The man has father issues,
any number of neuroses
and a phobia or two.
Sounds to me like you've hit the crackpot.
(chuckling)
I'm sorry.
I heard it at a convention.
So how did you meet
this new patient?
Well, I can't really say, Daphne.
You know, doctor-patient
confidentiality...
Hey, shrink buddy!
Hi, Niles.
Hi, Daphne.
Hello, Kenny, how are you?
Hello.
Well, if you'll excuse us,we're off to buy sticky mats
All right.
There we go.
Kenny, have a seat,
have a seat.
So, how are you feeling?
Like a new man
Last night was just what I needed.
I can't tell you how gratifying it is to hear that.
Yeah, me and your dad
shut down McGinty's.
Really? You and Dad?
Yeah, actually, I'm meeting him here for coffee.
Man, is he a hoot.
He made me completely forget
about my problems.
Well, good for you.
Of course...
the object is not to forget
about one's problems;
it's to understand them.
Of course, that can take
a lot of work.
About the work part...
your dad said something last
night that made a lot of sense.
He said I should get out more.
And I was thinking that's going to be tough to do
if I'm seeing you twice a week, plus doing all that homework.
I guess what
I'm saying is.
I want to quit.
Kenny...
I understand it must be painful
to uncover what is
a very painful past.
But I must warn you that
if you run away from this now
you will only be
repeating a pattern
that will prolong
your unhappiness.
I'm okay with that.
In these past few sessions,
we have discovered territory
that usually takes months
to reach.
I don't mean to toot my own horn, but I've been on fire.
Don't get me wrong, Doc.
You've been great.
It's just... it's not for me.
Hey, guys.
Hey-Hey, it's
Party Hearty Marty!
Hey-Hey, it's, uh...
Sir Shots-A-Lot.
Right. Hey!
Dad, can I have a word
with you for a second?
Yeah, sure.
Oh, I'll get
us some coffee.
Nice guy.
Doesn't hold his liquor like you think he would.
Did you tell him that
he should go out more?
Yeah. What's wrong with that?
Well...
he is using it as an excuse
to quit therapy.
After one night out
with you in a bar,
the man is ready to throw away
three weeks of intense analysis.
Fras, the guy's finally having a little fun.
Don't you want
him to be happy?
I am not trying
to make him happy.
I am trying to cure
his depression.
Hey, Marty, does this
remind you of anything?
Ow! Hot! Hot!
Get the man
some water, would you?
And breathe...
Daphne, that is
an amazing Downward Dog.
Thank you.
What about me, yogi?
How does my Downward Dog look?
Oh, dear.
Can we straighten
these legs?
Oh, I wish
Congenitally
shortened hamstrings
are the curse of the Cranes.
Well, let's try
a different pose then.
Slowly place your left leg
between your hands
pivot your right heel down,
straighten your legs
put your left arm on your ankle.
Raise your right arm and...
triangle pose.
Trikonasana.
Niles, just
use a block.
I don'’ need a block.
You do.
No, I really don't.
I don't like the block.
I don't want to touch...
Use a block.
And breathe...
And slowly
bring your back leg up
into Half-Moon pose.
Now feel your breath
leaving your body
like a note being blown
from a flute.
.
Yes, I feel it
Great.
I'm a flute, too, yogi.
Yes, of course you are.
Let's straighten that leg, Niles.
Straighten it,
straighten it out.
Straighten it out;
there we are.
That feels good;
yeah, okay
Let's try again, Niles.
Let's try and straighten
that leg.
You can do it.
Straighten that leg.
Marvel...
That's much better.
Okay, okay, all right.
All right, let's bend
the finger, Niles.
Let's bend the finger.
Isn't this
wonderful, Niles?
I love it.
And breathe.
And be completely
in this moment.
Shut off the outside world
entirely.
(cell phone rings)
Oh, hi, Mom.
I'm kind of in the middle of something right now.
Yes, I'm coming. I told you, I'm bringing the lentils
What do you mean again?
You love lentils.
Niles, straighten the leg,
straighten the leg.
Okay, child's pose, that's good.
So what if Jerry
brings a different
dish to every meal
d.
It doesn't make him a go
Has Jerry achieved inner peace?
I'm just asking, Mom,
has Jerry achieved inner peace?
I have to take this call.
Would you please excuse me?
(sighs):
That was fantastic
I feel so energized.
Well, you are really good.
I hope I'm not holding you back.
Oh, no, you're
doing wonderfully.
He's paying you
so much attention.
I think he sees real potential.
You don't have to soothe my ego.
Yoga isn't about competition
it's about achieving
enlightenment
and integrating your inner
and outer lives.
Hello.
Well, this
is awkward.
I believe
you know Martin.
Yes,
we've already met.
Kenny, there's no reason to feel awkward.
Believe me, I have other things
to do with my evening
than to share my expertise
with someone who could use it.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
So, we still on
for McGinty's tonight?
Yeah, sure
And Kenny, I've been thinking
about what you've been going through
and I've come
up with the answer.
A suede jacket
Did you hear that?
A suede jacket!
I must have missed that lecture
at Harvard Medical School.
You look good in it
and women love to feel it.
It's like you're a feast
for all the senses.
I used to have a suede
coat when I was single
Hester made me put it away
but I'd pull it out
whenever we'd have a fight
and in a minute,
she'd be purring like a kitten
You should break
it out again.
Oh-ho! At my age?
It would kill me.
Hey, you got time
to do a little shopping?
Sure. I think I got
my good credit card with me.
Leather won't cure
your problems, Kenny.
It's a temporary high.
MARTIN: Hi, guys.
NILES:
Hi.
DAPHNE:
Hello.
Oh, Niles, Daphne.
Hi, come join me.
Two low-fat lattes,
a hazelnut biscotti...
And one blueberry scone.
Your brother set such a brisk pace
walking over here,
I could barely
keep up with him.
Now, Daphne, you
don't need to do that.
Why not?
Shouldn't I be proud
of my husband's brisk pace?
Daphne's trying
to build up my ego
because she
out-performed me at yoga.
It's not a competition.
You see? He's already
mastered the teachings.
Spiritually,
you're way ahead of me.
Stop it.
Frasier, wasn't
that your PatientX
that was leaving
with Dad?
Yes, now my ex-Patient X.
Actually, I'd like
to discuss it with you
if you've got a few minutes.
Coincidentally, I just read
a fascinating paper
on early termination.
Yeah, the hypothesis was...
I think I'll get
something to eat.
Oh, you have
something here
Something else.
Well, here, try mine.
Please, just
let me go.
So, so, whose
decision was it
to terminate
your sessions?
Kenny.
I see. Well, uh.
early individuation
can stem from anything
from transfers to delayed
adolescent rebellion.
If only it were
that complicated, Niles.
What happened?
Well, it's Dad!
He's been taking Kenny
to McGinty's every night
He's giving him therapy
in the form of beer and fun.
Poor Kenny.
I know.
I've got to do something
I-I-I can't just stand by while Dad undermines me.
Oh, just be careful not to turn
this into a competition.
As analysts,
we have to be above that.
ROZ:
Hey, Niles
I hear Daphne kicked
your ass at yoga.
Oh, yeah? Well, Frasier
just lost a patient.
Nice Bhujangasana, Daphne.
And yours is very nice too, Niles.
You're doing so much better this week.
Thank you. I just did
what you suggested
and imagined myself having
the reptilian sinuousness
of a lizard scuttling
across the desert floor.
I thought I said
rain forest.
You did, but I
don't like the damp.
This next move is a little trickier.
ne.
I'll demonstrate on Daph
First of all, bring up
your knees, like this...
Now bring your arms back
towards your ankles.
Ooh! I don't think I can do this one.
It hurts.
Don't push.
You should be feeling
discomfort, not pain.
If you feel pain, ease yourself
gently back towards discomfort.
Is it something
like this, Yogi?
(gasps)
AHMRIT:
I'm impressed, Niles.
you might be able to
achieve Upward Bow--
Urdhbadhanurasana.
Oh, you mean
this one?
Yes.
Oh, remind me to tell Rosa
to vacuum the sisal.
I'm speechless, Niles.
I've never seen such
a rapid improvement.
How do you do that?
Oh, I think I tweaked a
muscle on that last pose.
Oh, no. We should put
some ice on that.
Good idea.
I guess we know who's
better at yoga now.
Now, Daphne,
there's no "better."
It's all about achieving
oneness of body and spirit.
Okay.
Now I need you
to take me to the hospital.
What?
I broke my body.
I dislocated my shoulder and...
I think that one of my ribs
has achieved two-ness.
What's going on?
Ahmrit and I were just going
to go out and get a chai tea.
Can we get you one?
No, thanks.
You're amazing!
You have so much energy.
Ah, well...
You know what they say..
Quickly, quickly.
Imagine the pain leaving your body
like a wisp of smoke.
If you could get the door,
I'm starting to hemorrhage.
FRASIER:
Hello.
Hey!
What are you
doing here, Fras?
Just thought maybe
the three of us
could have
a little chat.
Doc, this is Trudy.
Ah. Delighted,
I'm sure.
Hey.
I'd love to stay and chat, Doc,
but me and Trudy
have a dinner date with the Colonel
Well, if you think
you're ready for that.
Well, I'm not
hungry now,
but I probably will be when we get there.
See you guys later
Nice to meet you.
Likewise,
I'm sure.
Have a great time!
He's doomed.
What are you
talking about?
He scored and she's a cheap date.
Oh, Dad, please.
He is not ready
for a relationship.
How could you let him
do something like that?
Don't blame me for that; it was the jacket.
He wasn't here ten minutes
before she wanted to touch it.
You know what?
All you're doing
is allowing him
to wallow in his
state of denial
and what if she
rejects him, hmm?
The man already has
abandonment issues.
Oh, would you cut out the psychological mumbo-jumbo?
Let the guy have
a good time.
What did you just say?
I said let the guy have some fun.
No, before that.
You said "psychological
mumbo-jumbo."
So that's how you
characterize my life's work?
I'm just saying
that I don't think therapy is for everybody.
Like Kenny-- he just
needed to loosen up.
Oh, really?
So tell me,
Dr. Party-Hardy Marty...
Who, in your expert opinion,
does need therapy?
Well...
Hitler.
Yes, and that woman
with all the different personalities, um...
Sybil.
Hitler.
And Sybil.
Anyone else?
No.
Great!
An entire science
devoted to Hitler and Sybil.
Do you believe that...
that Niles and I have been
wasting our lives?
Do you think Mom
wasted her life?
Now, you calm down, Frasier.
I'm just saying that you overcomplicate things.
Yes, Kenny needed to
talk out some problems
but he didn't need to analyze every moment of his childhood.
That's when it gets into the mumbo-jumbo.
I'm just trying to get
to the root of his problems.
You know what? I think
you needed to give therapy
more than he needed to get it.
And you know what I think?
I think I'm finished
listening to you.
All right, fine,
maybe I did enjoy it.
Look, it's what
I was trained to do.
It's what I love to do
and I still think I was
doing Kenny some good.
Well, Frasier, you know,
Kenny's not the only one with mental problems.
And what is that
supposed to mean?
Well, it means you can start
seeing other patients.
Oh, right, right.
Well, I've, I've thought
about that.
Why not, if you love it?
You know, perhaps I could
start seeing people
a couple of nights a week.
I could even convert Daphne's
old room into an office.
Well, if you do,
while they're waiting,
they're watching
what I want to watch
Hey, guys.
Kenny!
What happened?
Are you
all right?
I don't think Trudy
and I are a fit.
When we got to the parking lot,
her boyfriend pushed me down
and took my jacket.
Aw...
MARTIN:
I'm sorry.
I feel like such a loser.
No, you're not a loser
and if you need
to talk about this-
Frasier's pretty good at this sort of thing.
Well, Kenny, I tell you what.
Whenever you're
ready, okay?
For the time being,
why don't you
let a couple of buddies
get you a beer, okay?
Thanks.
You know,
it's too bad that Trudy
was just setting me up
to get mugged
because up to that point,
we were really cooking.
Well, here's to dating!
♪♪ Hey, baby, I hear
the blues a-calling ♪♪
♪♪ Tossed salads
and scrambled eggs ♪♪
Mercy.
♪♪ And maybe I seem
a bit confused ♪♪
♪♪ Well, maybe,
but I got you pegged ♪♪
(laughs)
♪♪ But I don'’’t know what to do
♪♪
♪♪ With those tossed salad
s and scrambled eggs ♪♪
♪♪ They'’’re calling again
. ♪♪
Frasier has left the building.