Oh, uh, get a cart.
Oh, could you get it,
Niles, please?
They're so small,
they make me feel
like I'm some sort
of fairy tale giant.
Hey, any thoughts
about what to serve?
Well, I thought
we might serve
a house-cured gravlax
with crèème fraiche
and a sprig of dill.
Oh, in other words, the usual.
For your information, Niles,
people happen to like it.
Yes, people like
animated musicals.
Oh, honestly.
Frasier, look!
Caviar.
They haven't had any in ages.
This is just what we need
to make our soiree soign￩e.
(chuckles)
Good heavens.
It's $100 an ounce.
Well, it must be mismarked.
Excuse me, is the Beluga
really $100 an ounce?
(heavy French accent):
Yes.
Well, isn't that
rather a lot to pay?
To you, yes.
To the fish who gave up
her life so you could spread
her unborn children
on a cracker,
it's not so much.
You know, the reason
for such high prices is the Russian Mafia.
They control this market.
The Russian Mafia controls Robert's Gourmet Goodies?
He means the caviar market,
you ninny.
MAN:
Yes.
I have Beluga for sale.
Top quality,
fair price.
The name is Petyr.
I recently arrived
on my cousin's ship,
the Caspian Queen, with
beautiful Beluga caviar.
But because of those gangsters,
we cannot sell.
So I do it like this.
Quietly.
How much you want?
How do we know this
isn't some sort of scam?
It's no scam.
Look inside.
You taste.
You really must
try this, Niles.
It's like being kissed
by a lusty mermaid.
(chuckles)
So, you are interested, yes?
Maybe, but how can we
be sure that you are not
Russian Mafia yourself?
Because for six generations
my family
fished the Caspian
Then ten years ago, the bastards come.
They burned
my father's boat.
They steal my mother's salt so she cannot prepare the roe.
And if they know I sell Beluga
for $40 an ounce,
they would cut out my tongue
and pluck out my eyes!
Did you say
$40 an ounce?
Shouldn'’t our caviar
be here by now?
It will be here,
Niles.
I gave Roz
explicit instructions.
What if we've been swindled?
What if the tins
are filled with sand?
Niles,
I am, as you know,
an excellent judge of character.
And in Petyr, I saw an honest,
hard-working fisherman.
Why didn't you
have him deliver it here?
What? I don't want him
knowing where I live.
(doorbell rings)
The Russian bear
hunts by night.
Very funny, Roz,
come on.
Give me that.
All right, let's have a look
Oh.
Niles.
It's beautiful.
I don't get what the big
deal is about caviar.
I had it once,
it was nothing special.
Well, Roz, a lot of things can affect caviar.
Where did you have it?
On a mini-bagel
at the Tucson Doubletree.
Try this.
Hmm.
Wow.
Mm-hmm?
That's good.
Yes.
That's really good.
What's your little
party for tonight?
Invited guests.
I'm sorry, Roz.
What?
Thank you
for your help.
See you later.
Oh, hi, Roz.
Oh, hi, Dad.
Hey, hey, everybody.
Check this out
Just went to the ATM for $20,
as you can see from this
receipt, and it gave me $60.
I won 40 bucks.
You, you mean
the bank lost $40.
Uh, yeah, that big,
faceless bank that charges me
$12 a month for my checking
account lost $40.
You know,
you can't keep that.
It's bad karma.
Sorry, this is America.
A land built on the principle
"Finders Keepers."
Oh, come on.
There's a toll-free
service number
right here on the receipt.
Just call them and tell
them what happened.
Why should I?
Because otherwise,
you could end up
like my brother Nigel
and his baby teeth.
What happened with
your brother Nigel
and his baby teeth?
Well, like any child,
the first time he
had a tooth fall out,
he put in under his pillow at bedtime,
and sure enough,
the next morning,
he found that Winston Churchill
had left him a shiny, new coin.
Question.
No, Dad, we're not stopping
Go ahead,
darling.
Well, instead of being grateful,
he got greedy
and went off to school,
punching people
in their mouths
and scooping up their teeth.
Of course, it didn't work, and he got kicked out of school,
became a thief,
and eventually went to prison.
Where he...
fittingly had all
of his teeth knocked out.
No, he lost his teeth
years earlier
in a rock-eating contest.
Now that's an interesting story.
We were renting a house
next to a quarry at the time...
All right, all right, I'll call the bank!
Very kind of you
to have us here, Crane.
Yes, it's wonderful.
But then you must be used to
hosting successful parties.
Oh, not really.
Something's usually
on fire by now.
Oh, you're funny.
No, I'm serious.
Now, tell me.
How can we get our hands on some
of this fantastic caviar?
Well, I wish
I could tell you,
but it's, uh
a private source.
Well, perhaps I should
mention then,
that, uh, this is
for our yacht party,
at which there just might be
room enough for another guest.
Okay, what are we talking here?
Well, maybe five, six ounces?
Let me go see
what's in the refrigerator
That a boy, Crane.
Niles, what are you doing?
Oh, good news.
Emile Sinclair
is crazy about the caviar.
If we sell him the rest,
he distinctly implied
he would get our squash lockers
moved further from the showers.
Isn't that fantastic?
Per-son-al.
It's, well, it would be, Niles
if the Michaelses weren't
equally enamored of it,
and dangling an invitation
to a yacht party.
That is a pickle.
Check-ing.
FRASIER:
Niles?
Why don't we just call Petyr,
and order some more caviar?
That way we can satisfy both
Sinclair and the Michaels.
Cus-to-mer
Ser-vice.
Niles, this caviar connection
could really open
some doors for us.
Per-son-al!
What are you doing, Dad?
Oh, this stupid bank's
automatic voice system,
it's like a maze!
All right,
give it here.
You just push "O"
and you'll get
an operator.
It's a little trick
I learned.
Another menu.
Sometimes it's a star.
All right, maybe "1"
will get me back to a main menu.
Ah.
Here you are.
Got me to
the right department?
No, but if I remember my
high school Spanish correctly,
you just qualified
for a small business loan.
Hi, can I help you?
Yes, um, I was at one
of your ATMs yesterday,
and it gave me back more than it
should have, so I want...
Okay, for that you'’re
going to need to complete
an ATM trouble report,
and then take it
to our operations officer
at the desk over there.
You mean I have to fill this out
before I can give you 40 bucks?
Yes, sir.
But your sign says,
"Making banking simpler."
Yes, sir.
Well, this isn't simpler
it's more complicated.
Yes, sir, it is.
Oh, forget it.
I knew this was going to be more
trouble than it was worth.
A little paperwork's
a small price to pay
for a clear conscience.
Yeah, meanwhil
e, I'm out 40 bucks.
It's not your money.
Can I help you?
Yes, uh, I had some trouble
with one of your ATMs.
Oh, I can't help you.
I need a manager.
I'm proud of you.
Trust me, when this is over,
you'll feel better.
You really think so?
I'm sure of it.
Ah, maybe you're right.
Maybe I will feel better.
And if you're right
about that karma stuff
I got a good thing coming to me.
Uh-oh.
How much money did you
put in the meter?
Oh, son of a bitch
Hi, Mr. Crane, I'm Bree, Todd's manager.
I wanted t apologize for
the trouble you had with our ATM.
And make sure that you got your $40
What? Uh, oh, no, no,
you don't need
to give anything to me.
You see, the machine
accidentally gave me $60
instead of $20, so I need
to give you $40.
So, you want to
put this in your account?
No, no, no.
I want you to take it,
plus this $40,
and put it back
wherever it came from.
Well, I'm afraid I've already done the paperwork.
Now you'll have to speak
with our branch manager,
but he's out of town.
This is ridiculous.
I'm sorry.
Although, there is
one other possibility.
Let me try something.
Thank you.
Don'’’t mention it.
Per-son-al
Sandoval, four ounces.
Right.
Smoot, five ounces.
McBean, ten ounces.
Ten?
Yes, I know it's a lot,
but he promised me the use
of his Sonoma estate.
Yes, well,
for ten, he should
You know, for eight,
the Ashworths gave me
the use of their box at
the opera's opening night gala
But that's the same weeken
d as the Black and White ball.
When are we going to sleep?
Good Heavens.
Sleep is for people without social lives.
(laughs)
So, boys,
where's my cut?
Oh, what are you talking about?
I promised her a cut.
You see, I was so busy
at work taking orders
that I needed her help.
ROZ:
You know what
it's really good on?
Scrambled eggs.
And pizza.
And potato skins...
Yes, Roz, welcome to caviar.
At work, during the show,
I'm just sitting there thinking
"Two hours to caviar."
"One hour to caviar."
You don't have any on you, do you?
Uh, no, no.
We're expecting
some momentarily.
Cool.
You think it'd be good
on a cheese Danish?
I think it would.
I'm getting one.
Gentlemen.
Oh, Petyr, hello.
Yes, hello,
but I am afraid also good-bye.
Hmm? What?
What do you
mean good-bye?
All these orders
I fill for you.
It draws too much attention.
It's too risky for me.
What are you saying?
That, that there's no more caviar?
This is my last delivery.
But this isn't
nearly enough.
We've made commitments
to some very powerful people.
If we disappoint them, there's no telling what they might do.
They will break legs?
Cut off thumbs?
Worse, there'll be gossip.
Petyr, please,
just one more delivery.
I cannot, the danger
is too great.
Petyr!
Dear God.
We're ruined, Niles.
We owe people all over town.
I know.
Is some of that mine? Can I have it now?
Roz, Roz,
I'm terribly sorry.
It seems our supplier
is going out of business,
and every ounce
of this is spoken for.
Well, that's too bad.
Oh, well, whatever
I was thinking
of giving it up anyway
Too much salt.
Yes, good girl.
All right, Niles,
we can't panic.
I think I
have a plan.
I like it.
We may have to
bite the bullet
and buy retail
Petyr's stuff
is much better quality.
Our friends will
notice the difference.
Not if we cut it with what's left of the good stuff.
How much is there?
There's... Roz!
Oh, dear God!
This is going
to cost us a fortune.
What else can we do?
Uh, excuse me.
Would you happen to know
where we can get...
five pounds
of Beluga caviar?
There'’s not that much Beluga in all of Seattle.
Thank you.
What are we
going to do?
All right, just give me a chance to think, Niles.
Ah...
What was the name of the boat--
H.M.S.Bounty.
This isn't Trivial Pursuit!
Let me finish!
What was the n
ame of the boat
that Petyr
said he sailed on?
Caspian Queen.
Niles,
if we can find that boat,
perhaps we can get enough
caviar to solve our problem.
Roz.
Hey, what are
you guys doing here?
I think the question is,
what are you doing here?
You know, shopping...
for stuff.
u?
You're looking for
more caviar, aren't yo
Of course, I am,
you took all mine!
That was ours!
You know, Roz, I think
you may have a little problem.
You're the one
with the problem.
Not me.
This is all
your fault.
You made me try it.
Now I crave it!
I really hate you!
Now, Roz...
you know you don'’’t mean that
Now, come on.
Listen, it's just possible
that we may be able to get
some more from our old supplier.
Is that true?
Yes.
Is he right?
I'm sorry I said
I hate you.
Roz, Roz, it's all right.
Are you going to get it today?
I love you!
(phone ringing)
Oh, shoot.
(doorbell chimes)
(phone ringing)
Hello.
Ah, no, I'm sorry,
Frasier isn't here.
Sure, you can place an order.
Yes, let me transfer you
to that department.
Hi, Daph. Hello.
The postman gave me
your mail.
Oh, thanks.
You ready
to get stretched?
Oh, you mean we're
working out today?
We work out every day.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
Oh, postcard from the bank.
Uh, "Dear Mr. Crane, we
apologize for the inconvenience.
"We have evaluated your request
and credited your account $80"!
There's no spaces.
I parked your car
in a loading zone.
No, no, no, just pull around front and wait for me.
This won't take long.
You're sure?
Yes.
And you better
get back to the car
before Eddie
starts to panic.
Hi, how can I help you
make banking simpler?
I'll tell you how you can help me.
I'm going to talk
and you're going to listen,
and you're going to do exactly as I ask.
I think I should
go get a manager.
No, no managers.
But our policy is...
Now this is real simple,
and I know you can handle it.
Now what I want you to do is--
GUARD:
Hold it right there, Mister!
Mr. Crane, as the president of
the bank, I want to assure you
that it is not our policy
to draw firearms on customers
trying to make a deposit.
It wasn't a deposit.
Now, I'm sure that neither of us wants to turn this
into a protracted legal battle,
so if you would simply sign this non-disclosure agreement
here, here, here..
and here.
Our attorneys have authorized me
to compensate you
for your troubles
in the amount of $10,000,
which can be credited to your account.
Ten grand?
Plus, the $40
from our original mistake.
Oh, what the hell.
I just want
to get it over with.
That's wonderful.
Now, is there anything else I can do for you?
Could I open
an account?
FRASIER:
Ahoy!
Is anyone here?
Oh, hello.
I'm Dr. Frasier Crane.
And, uh, this
is my brother,
Dr. Niles Crane.
We're interested in
purchasing some Beluga caviar.
This is not a shop.
I have nothing for sale.
See?
Let's go.
No, no, no,
Niles, Niles...
This is how
the game is played.
Maybe he thinks
we're Russian Mafia.
Oh, yes.
People make that mistake
about us all the time.
Petyr gave us
this card,
and told us that this
was his cousin's boat.
Are you sure
you can't help us?
(speaking Russian)
(laughing)
How much do you need?
Five pounds.
(speaking Russian)
$80 an ounce.
Well, we were paying $40.
And now you pay $80.
$50.
$80.
$60.
I don't think you're
doing this right.
$70, that's my
final offer.
$80.
Done!
I want to taste it first.
Go ahead.
That's the stuff.
That's enough to take
care of everyone
and still go out on top!
Yes, all right,
here's your money.
Pleasure doing
business with you.
MAN (over PA):
Stop where you are!
U.S. Customs!
U.S. Customs.
Oh, my God!
Frasier, we have to get rid ofit.
Oh, dear God!
All right, all right,
we have to hide it!
No, Niles, you can't hide it!
They're U.S. Customs!
That's what they do!
They find things on ships!
I know one way
to get rid of it.
Can I get you
a toast point?
Oh, here, for God's sakes!
What the hell's
all this?
It's not ours, we found it.
What, the caviar?
Is that what this is?
Relax, we don't care about that.
We're looking for
a couple of Russians
who've been smuggling DVDs
My heart is pounding.
I was afraid we were
going to get arrested.
What have we become?
I don't know.
We got caught up
in a nefarious scheme.
And for what?
A visit to
a wine country estate?
A box at the opera?
Dinner at
the Governor's Mansion?
How much of this do you
think we can salvage?
I don't know,
just start scraping.