Roz... Roz...
(group cheering)
Roz, you just missed
the classic prank of all time.
I'll admit it,
this was my masterpiece.
Oh, who, who, who'd you get?
Way to go, Bulldog.
(barks and snickers)
There he is!
(both laughing)
I got this friend down at the impound lot
who came across a smashed-up BMW
--
same make and model and Frasier's.
You didn't!
You got Frasier!
I had his car towed from the garage
the wreck put in its place.
(laughing)
The doc totally freaked
when he saw it.
First, he started swearing
then he implored the heavens
and just when his lips
started trembling
Bulldog comes out,
tells him it's all a prank
.
Hey, Bulldog observes
the mercy rule.
Besides, I got
the whole thing on tape.
(laughing)
Admit it, Doc.
I got you good.
Come on, say it.
Bulldog's the best.
Okay, okay, how about
the bitch dance I taught you?
(snickering)
(laughing)
At least give me
one up high.
Come on... ah, come on,
don't leave me hanging, Doc.
Where's your
Halloween spirit?
Don't worry, it'll be
here waiting for you.
(snickers)
For the record, I knew
immediately it was not my car.
Mine has a bumper sticker
on it that says:
"I am pro-opera and I vote."
Frasier, you've got to admit it was clever.
I admit nothing.
That is the last
we shall discuss of it.
We have a show to do.
Good afternoon, Seattle
and welcome
to the Halloween edition
of the Dr. Frasier Crane Show.
Today, we will be discussing
the topic of fears.
Are they irrational
hindrances or...
evolutionary tools.
Hmm.
The surprising answer...
after these words.
FRASIER (on tape):
My car!
Oh, not my car!
What did they do to you?
My baby!
Whenever you're ready.
(door shuts)
(knocking)
(doorbell ringing)
Did you find something?
Do you think they'll take soy sauce packets?
Who keeps ringing the doorbell?
Mum! Shh!
(quietly):
It's trick-or-treaters.
It's okay, they're gone.
Well, why didn't you
let them in?
Because someone forgot
to get Halloween candy.
Although someone else
could've picked it up
since she was already
in the store.
Well, that would override the duty list
that someone insisted on implementing.
If this is what you two
call a fight
you're not fit
to be married.
I once held your father's head underwater and...
(doorbell rings)
Shh!
Oh, for heaven's sake!
We haven't got any candy!
Shove off!
Great. Now they know
we're here.
(doorbell rings)
That's precisely what's wrong with this country.
Everyone's afraid
to stand up to the children.
Trick or treat.
Didn't you hear?
We've got no candy!
We can offer you hotel soaps.
But it's Halloween.
I dress up, you give me candy.
That costume's
supposed to be scary?
No. Is yours?
Oh, a nice bite into an onion
is what that mouth of yours deserves.
If you don't have treats, you're going to get a trick.
Do your worst!
I'’’m not afraid of you.
Honestly!
Okay, well, maybe I'll
go pick up
some candy after all.
(loud splattering)
Okay, I'm going to need
my slicker and my squash goggles.
FRASIER:
Good morning, Roz.
May I join you?
Sure, Frasier.
Well, I'm glad to see
you're not sulking today.
Yes, well, I had a little time to think about it
and I've decided to put Bulldog's prank behind me.
That's very mature.
I'm not finished.
By visiting upon him a prank
that is ten times more dastardly
Look at this.
It looks like a car
with a balloon tied to it.
Precisely!
I will tie a red balloon
to the antenna of Bulldog's car
every time his precious Seahawks
lose a game.
Over time...
the conditioned response will
become ingrained in his psyche.
Eventually, the mere sight
of a red balloon...
will bring about in him an inexplicable sense
of loss.
Check and mate
Isn't that kind of out there?
That's the point.
Well, of course I could resort
to any of your basic pranks:
hand in warm water and whatnot--
believe me, I have an intimate
knowledge of all of them--
but what I'm looking for is
something unmistakably
me.
A signature prank, if you will, hmm?
Why don't you just
forget about revenge
and give him
his two minutes in the sun?
At my expense?
Look at his life.
You guys used to be equals
now he's stuck downstairs
that dark, musty archives room.
You must have some sympathy
for him, don't you?
Dark musty archives.
I think I can use that
Hello, all.
Hi.
Hello, Niles.
Why do we have to stop here?
I could make coffee at home.
Now, now.
It's good to get
out of the house--
get some fresh air,
exercise those lungs.
My lungs are as strong as ever.
Just yesterday, I finished
a whole cigarette in two drags.
One off me record.
What's this?
I'm devising
the ultimate prank
to get my revenge
on Bulldog.
Ah, well, just beware
the dangers
of juvenile
one-upsmanship.
Only last night, Mrs. Moon
challenged a trick-or-treater
and he responded by pelting
our door with eggs.
Yeah, but I got
the little monster back
by puttin' a big, greasy glob of
Vaseline on his doorknob.
You said you'd put
an e
Hence, the Vaseline.
Mum, he's a child.
Well, it's time he learned you don't
mess with Gertrude Moon
without incurring my wrath.
Now, excuse me.
I require cocoa.
You know, I think she
has the right attitude
If I expect Bulldog
to leave me alone
I've got to show him
he's dealing with a superior intellect.
Show them the balloon car.
I'm sure da Vinci's early no
were full of laughs, too.
Excuse me.
I have devising to do.
That'll be... $32.03.
For one drink?
Your grandson ordered
a bunch of cakes
and he said it was all on you.
Thanks for the
treats, Grandma!
Hey...!
Oh, let's see the little sod get to
school without these.
Oh, this should settle it.
(thunder crashes)
Is anybody there?
(deadpan):
Oh. Zombies.
The living dead.
Help. Help
FRASIER:
Everyone hold, please.
Zombie Number Two,
what are you doing?
I'm scaring Bulldog?
I see.
Is that what zombies do?
They scare people?
Um...
Wrong!
They eat brains,
and that's what scares people.
All right, now,
this is our dress rehearsal.
Let's please try
to get this right.
Bulldog comes in,
he hears noises
zombies go after his brain...
and his terror
is caught on videotape
for us all to enjoy
at a later date, all right?
Now, let's try this again.
First marks, please.
Oh, geez, Fras
This is the fourth time
through.
Can somebody else
play Bulldog now?
Dad, you said you'd
help me with this.
You said we were going
to do a practical joke.
I thought it'd be fun.
Whatever gave you that idea?
Todd...
I am getting "dead"
from you
but I'm not getting "undead."
Still.
Let's try this, then.
After rehearsal, I want each
of you to write a paragraph...
detailing who your character
was when he or she was alive...
how they died...
and why they are now
after Bulldog's brain.
Honestly, Roz, you know,
you haven't given me
much to work with here.
There are the worst actors
I've ever seen!
I'm sorry, but the Royal Zombie Company
just left town
with its all-zombie production
of Hamlet.
How many more times
are we going to do this?
Why is it that whenever
Bulldog pulls a practical joke
you all applaud him
as if he's won
some sort of bowl or cup
or other sports dish?
But when I ask you to give up
a single Sunday
all I get is complaints.
Because you keep
turning it into work.
This is supposed to be fun!
Like a day at the beach.
You do this kind
of thing all the time.
Like when?
Like the last time
we went to the beach.
A lot of people bring rakes!
Frasier, it's not too late to back out of this.
Now, face it
jokes just aren't your specialty.
What is that supposed to mean?
Well, what she means, son
is that we all have
our different blessings
and Bulldog's good
at jokes and fun.
You're good at...
reading and, uh...
telling people about
the things you read.
Are you saying that you think
I can't pull this off?
Oh, I wouldn't put it that way
I would.
But I worked this out
to the last detail!
Nothing can go wrong!
Everything's going to go wrong!
For one thing, Bulldog's
going to know something's up
'cause Kenny hardly ever
makes him work at night.
And then, look at all these cameras
and all these wires--
what if he spots these?
And the zombies,
as soon as he sees them
.
he's going to know it's a prank,
'cause he just pranked you
And there are no such things as zombies!
You, sir...
are released!
And you, as well!
I'll pull this
thing off by myself
proving that you don't know what
you're talking about!
I don't need any of you!
Wait, zombies, I do need you.
But no one else!
I'll show all of you!
You mark my words!
Tomorrow night,
I get my revenge!
(thunder crashes)
Ah, good, the effects
machine's working again.
All right, everyone...
back to your first marks.
(doorbell chimes)
Where have you been?!
I'm sorry. I had a hard ti
me finding this place.
I checked the directory
for "Crane"
but it had "Old Bat"
next to this apartment number.
A little obvious, but not bad.
I want you to deliver this
Baby-I-Have-To-Tinkle doll
to Jason White,
Floyd Middle School.
This is the address.
I mean, he should be
in gym class about now
I don't think I'm allowed
to just walk into the school, ma'am.
Oh, it's okay.
I'm his grandmother.
And you have to say this:
"Your mommy said
bring this to you at school
"to lift your spirits.
See, your dolly
has accidents, too."
You really want me
to say that?
Yes, and very loudly.
The poor thing's hard of hearing.
Yes!
Todd, take off
that baseball cap.
You're undead, not uncouth
All right, everyone.
Step lively,
look sharp.
It's almost show time.
Give me a final
room-tone check, please
and take your marks.
Hey, Fras.
Oh, hello.
Come to watch me fail,
I suppose.
No, we just wanted
to come join you.
We're sorry about that stuff
we said yesterday.
It's long overdue.
Maybe I don't want you here.
What do you mean?
You abandoned me
in my hour of need.
Now you're here
to revel in my success
just like in Boswell's
Life of Johnson.
What?
It was something I read.
I guess we deserve that,
whatever the hell it means.
Come on, Frasier, we're sorry.
Just let us watch.
All right.
Apology accepted.
You may observe
in silence.
Make yourselves
comfortable
and prepare to witness a man
brought to the very edge
of madness!
I think
he's already there.
Mum, we're off to the symphony.
Haven't the Germans
punished us enough?
Ooh!
Bloody hell!
Where did this come from?
Oh, you must have
crossed someone.
Mother.
Oh, my God.
I'm so sorry.
We were just coming
down the hall
and we saw you
open your door.
This is our trash can.
What was it
doing there?
Jason, get back here!
It seems our children
have been feuding.
We're very embarrassed
You're embarrassed?
Meet our daughter.
Hello.
I have a lot of homework.
Stay!
Jason, have you been
fighting with this woman?
Well, she broke my bike
and made me have to see
a counselor at school.
I think I left something
in the kitchen.
Stay!
I am an adult.
I can do anything I want!
No. While you're living
under our roof
you'll follow our rules.
You two should be
ashamed of yourselves.
What if someone got hurt?
Good.
Jason! You are
one second away
from losing
your broadband
connection.
Now, apologize
and shake hands.
Pish.
What if I told you
you couldn't smoke your pipes
in your room anymore?
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Now you two are go
ing to clean up this mess.
And Jason,
come straight home
when you're finished.
This place better be spotless
by the time we get back.
I wish I was all grown up
and I wouldn't have
to follow
their stupid rules.
Oh, nothing changes,
trust me.
You know...
my mom hates bugs.
She screams like a girl.
So does my son-in-law.
I know where
we can find some crickets.
No! Now, we should
do as we're told
and start cleaning up.
Okay.
That way they won't
be expecting it.
(both giggle)
This is so great!
I can't wait.
I'm getting goose bumps.
Feel me. Feel me.
Kenny, what was
the condition
of my letting you watch?
There he is!
Cue "creaking noise one."
(creaking noise)
Hello?
Who's there?
Cue "creaking noise two."
(different creaking noise)
Now let the horror begin.
(shrieking)
Yes!
How do you like that,
you big baby?!
(Frasier laughing)
Get back!
(gunshot)
Oh, my God!
Call 911!
Don't worry about it, Kenny.
It's just a joke.
What are you talking about?
It's a fake gun!
What?!
What about the bullets?
It's a joke.
Bulldog found out about Frasier's prank
so we set him up.
That is awesome!
I can't believe he fell for it
Come on, we got to tell
Frasier what's going on.
You guys go ahead.
I think I'm going
to stay here and puke.
Stop! Stop!
It was all a joke!
Oh, my God!
What have I done?!
What's the big deal?
He was already a zombie.
(raucous laughter)
Are you insane?!
Call an ambulance!
(yells)
(laughing)
What's going on here?
Wave to the camera, Frasier.
What?
Got you again,
all on tape.
Who's the king?
That isn't funny!
I could've had a heart attack!
Oh, sorry, Fras.
We just couldn't resist.
Well, at least
nobody was hurt.
You've bested me,
Bulldog-- again.
Dr. Crane, I think
I hurt my back.
What?
(all gasp)
Oh, my God!
Someone call
an ambulance!
Where's the phone?!
Get the first-aid kit
out of the closet!
No, no! Not the...!
(shrieks)
What the hell's going on
down here?!
Quiet, everybody!
Hello. Yes, I'd like to report
the greatest practical joke ever!
You better send a firetruck
because you guys just got burned!
(laughing)
Wait. What?
Hi, Roz.
Oh!
You should see the look
on your faces!
This is truly a classic.
This was all just a joke?
Awesome!
Nice work, Doc.
Likewise, Bulldog.
Think I can get a copy of this
for my demo reel?
Sure thing, Todd.
You've come a long way
in a short time, young man.
Well, Frasier, I'm speechless
You totally had us going.
I can't believe it!
Admit it, Roz
can I pull off a practical joke or what?
I just don't understand.
Did you guys work together?
Frasier set the whole thing up.
The other day, after you two left
I got to thinking
maybe my joke was aimed
at the wrong target.
That's when Bulldog and I joined forces.
But we joined forces with him to get you!
That's exactly what you were supposed to think.
Wow, Fras,
I got to give it to you.
This was brilliant.
Thank you, Dad.
What do you say
we all go upstairs
and watch the tape?
You guys go ahead.
Bulldog?
Yeah?
Technically, I still
owe you one.
Face it, Doc, you will never win.
Good work, Noel.
That's why you had to join forces with me.
Huh?
You're right.
All right.
♪♪ Hey, baby, I hear
the blues a-calling ♪♪
♪♪ Toss salads
and scrambled eggs ♪♪
Mercy.
♪♪ And maybe I seem
a bit confused ♪♪
Yeah, maybe,
but I got you pegged.
(laughs)
♪♪ But I don'’’t know what to do
♪♪
♪♪ With those toss salads
and scrambled eggs ♪♪
♪♪ They'’’re calling again
. ♪♪
Scrambled eggs
all over my face.
What is a boy to do?
Good night, Seattle!
We love you!