(nervous breathing)
Sorry.
I'm a... nervous flyer.
Yes, I see.
Oh, you're white as a sheet.
Actually,
I'm always this pale.
My ex-wife used to say
she could tell
when I was embarrassed
because I'd turn off-white
.
I can empathize.
Sometimes after a late night,
I've covered my undereye circles with Liquid Paper.
(chuckles)
So, are you traveling to Seattle
for business
or pleasure?
Both, hopefully.
I'm relocating for work.
How about you?
I need to ask an old friend
for a favor.
Hmm. It's a long trip
just to ask for a favor.
It's a big favor.
Well, I hope
your friend complies.
It'll take some work,
but I'll get what I want
.
Oh, dear.
You two look
awfully pale.
Can I bring you something?
Not unless you have
any extra melanin lying around.
(laughs)
You should be a comedian.
I've thought about it.
(door opening)
Dad? Dad, Dad, what,
are you hiding?
I heard the key in the door.
I thought Lilith
might be with you.
What's she coming for, anyway?
Well, I don't really know.
She... she said she was flying
across the country
to ask me about something
that was important.
She's being very mysterious
about it.
Hmm.
(doorbell rings)
Is that her?
Well, no. No, Dad.
I'm not seeing her
until tomorrow.
Well, let me know
when she's coming, will you,
so I can come up with an excuse
to clear out
because I'm not good
at winging it.
Oh... Lilith.
.
(chuckles)
: Hi... uh..
Look who's here, Dad.
Hello, Martin.
Oh! Time to go
practice my signature.
.
Please, come on in, Lilith
Uh, so, uh, I didn't think I was going to be seeing you
until tomorrow
Yes, I know that was the plan,
but I just had to stop by
on my way to the hotel.
What I'm here
to talk to you about
is not something one just
drops on another person.
Please.
(sighs):
Frasier.
(clears throat)
Recently,
a subconscious yearning
has tunneled its way
to the surface
and I now know
what it is I need
in order to make my life complete.
Well, that's wonderful news.
How can I help?
You can give me your sperm
I beg your pardon?
I want to have another baby.
Well, you certainly
don't need me for that.
Surely, someone in Boston
must have sperm.
I came to you first
so that Frederick could have a full sibling.
So, just like that,
we're going to have
another baby together?
.
No, no, no, not just like that
I mapped out our dominant and recessive traits
on a genome square,
applied Mendel's laws,
allowed for anomalies, and concluded
that you are the best biological choice.
I see.
Well, as enticed as I am
by your honeyed words...
I'm going to need some kissin'
Frasier, don't misunderstand
I'm not proposing
any change in our relationship.
Would we sleep together?
I thought we'd freeze
your sperm.
Is that a yes or a no?
Natural fertilization
isn't practical.
I'd have to fly to Seattle every time I ovulate.
Right, okay,
so then your plan is
for me to visit
some local doctor,
uh, freeze my essence
and then bring it home with you.
Correct.
I'll take mine to go.
I...
I don't know.
I'm going to have
to think about it.
Yes, of course, absolutely.
Think about it, and you can
give me your answer tomorrow.
Ok
You can come back from
around the corner now, Martin.
MARTIN:
Good night, Lilith.
Good night.
You were eavesdropping?
It was an accident,
and I only heard the part
about her wanting to have
another baby with you.
She completely threw me.
Well, I don't know why you're so surprised.
She's seen what
the Crane genes can do
and she's coming back
to the well.
How does one respond
to something like that?
Well, I bet if you say no,
she'll go to Niles.
Really, it's just
so self-centered of her.
You know, she's got this
all figured out for herself
without the slightest
consideration for my life.
And Niles will
say no for sure.
Which means only one thing:
she'll come to the source.
Me.
The fountainhead.
What?
Can you imagine?
Lilith's and my kid
would be brothers
to you and Niles and Freddy.
What are you talking about?
And if you and Lilith
got back together,
you'd be his stepfather
and his brother,
and Niles would be your son...
and his own uncle.
It's almost worth doing just so that I can tell the story.
Oh, hi, Niles.
Did Daphne and her mum
get off okay?
Uh, yes, they picked up
Roz and Alice an hour ago.
Although how they're going to get all the way to Canada
without killing each other,
I don't know.
Why did they have
to go so far?
Well, that was my idea.
I read that
Canadian Fun Country's
one of the best amusement parks
in southeastern
British Columbia.
Oh.
Well, I'm just saying
Daphne's mum should be careful, you know.
If you're here
on a temporary visa,
sometimes people have
a difficult time
getting back into the country.
That hadn't occurred to me, Frasier.
(clears throat)
Well, seeing as howyou're single,
I'd invite you
to join me for dinner,
but I'm-I'm meeting
with Lilith tonight
on a matter of some delicacy.
Uh, Dad told me.
Now listen,
don't feel obligated
because she's buying you dinner.
Truth be told, Niles,
I haven't ruled it out entirely.
It would be nice
to have another child,
and Lilith is
a wonderful mother.
It's just that, well...
is it right to create
a human being with a woman
to whom you couldn't stand being married?
Well, I'm behind you,
whatever decision you make--
the right one or the crazy one.
Well, thank you.
(both chuckling)
Excuse me.
May I have an
espresso, please?
And what have you
got here?
Oh, some snapshots
from last summer at the beach.
Daphne finally got them
developed.
(laughing):
Oh, look.
There's Dad eating that hot dog
he dropped in the sand.
Yes.
And you in your
linen beach ensemble.
Very nice, yes
Well, that's strange.
Daphne said
I'd particularly like
the last picture on the roll,
but what is it?
Well, it's hard to tell.
It's too dark and blurry.
Looks like the eye of Jupiter.
Or a slice of pepperoni.
Is it a flying saucer?
Yes, Niles,
it's a flying saucer.
Mystery solved.
Well done.
Thanks
Hey, where'd you get
the nipple shot?
Good Lord!
You are to erase that
from your mind!
Well, is it Daphne?
Nice.
You're not erasing!
Erase!
I need to stop again.
We just stopped.
I told you not to get that Big Gulp.
Punchb
Ow! Dammit!
Language.
Why does she keep doing that?
It's a game.
It hurts.
All right, Mum.
There's a gas station
right there.
I really need to stop.
I can't get over.
You'll have to wait.
But according to this,
my bladder is holding
"thirsty"-two ounces of soda.
It's only 40 miles.
Punchbuggy red.
Oh, son of a...!
Language.
Alice, honey,
stop hitting Mrs. Moon.
She can't take
the punchbuggy game.
Oh, really?
Punchbuggy white.
Ow! That was a Jeep.
I like playing with Jeeps.
And Fords.
Punchbuggy Ford.
All right, that's enough!
You stop it, or no one's going to Canadian Fun Country.
And this time I mean it.
(screams)
(others scream)
I'm sorry. I thought you were
on the wrong side of the road.
I will never get used
to the crazy way
you drive over here.
Mum, you have to stop
doing that.
Daphne, you seem stressed.
Do you want me to drive
for a while?
Maybe once we get out
of Seattle.
Frasier, I don't want to rush you,
but the suspense
is too much to bear.
Have you decided?
I'm thinking
about the linguini.
I see.
It's "no" then, isn't it?
I'm sorry, Lilith.
This was a very difficult
decision for me,
and I am touched and flattered
that you came to me,
but I'm not sure I'd be doing it for the right reasons.
You understand, don't you?
Yes, I do.
And I appreciate your taking
the time to think about it.
Well...
It's that kind of consideration
I was hoping to pass on
to our second-born.
Oh, well.
So, the pasta's good here?
Oh, the best.
♪♪
(tune of "Ode To Joy"):
♪♪ My dad is the gweatest dad
♪♪
♪♪ Because he cooks
me cweam of wheat...
Lilith, what are you singing?
Was I singing?
You were singing
"My Dad is the Gweatest Dad."
Oh, you mean that song
Frederick wrote for you
when he was four?
That video is one of
my prize possessions.
Of course I haven't
looked at it in some time.
I remember the night
we surprised you with it.
He crawled up in
your lap and said,
"Why is Daddy cwying?"
I see what you're doing,
you know.
What?
You are attempting
to manipulate me
by invoking powerful,
emotional memories.
I assure you, nothing could be
further from the truth.
Are you ready to order?
Yes.
I'd like the bisketti
with beatmalls.
Mmm, very
good, miss
That's what our son used to say when he was three.
Excellent!
And I'll have the veal.
Bravo, sir.
Lilith,
.
I'm afraid
you're idealizing parenthood
Do you remember colic? Teething?
Changing mountains of diapers?
Do you remember that
time in the bath
when he tried to
eat the bubbles?
We told him to stop,
but we kept laughing,
so he thought it was
funny and kept doing it.
You know, I'd forgotten
about that.
Oh, I wish we had that on video.
You can, Frasier.
We can have those days back again.
Please
I just need a couple
of teaspoons.
Lilith!
Just think about what Frederick has meant
in our lives.
I think about it every day.
Frasier...
we're always seeking ways we can leave a legacy.
Well, forget my research
and your work.
This is it.
What better gift can
we bestow on the world
but another person as
wonderful as Frederick?
Excuse me,
um... I've changed my mind.
,
I've decided that I, too
will have
the bisketti and beatmalls.
Thank you.
Gosh, that coffee smells so good
Mmm.
Lilith won't let me have
any caffeine
until I've made
my little donation.
Ah, yes.
So, have you heard from Daphne?
No, we keep
missing each other.
I'm just glad I have
our little pictorial memento
to keep me company.
I can't believe you're so taken
with that blurry
overexposed photo of a...
Shh.
Of what you first mistook
to be a flying saucer.
I just think it's sexy
that she even did it.
Yeah.
Imagine it-- she saw
there was one picture
left on the roll.
In a spontaneous moment
of brazen exhibitionism,
she threw open her blouse
and just didn't even bother
to adjust the f-stop.
(chuckles)
Yes, indeed. Oh.
I am married
to one spicy meatball.
Good Lord.
Don't tell me you carry
it around with you.
Well...
I didn't want
the housekeeper to find it
and think we were
pornographers.
WOMAN:
Just fill out these forms
and I can show you to
one of our donation suites
Thank you.
Will this be your first?
No, I've been doing this
since I was 12.
You mean baby.
Uh, no, no.
This is our second
We've got number four
on the way.
Oh, and we're
thrilled for you,
but perhaps we can chat
some other time
when we're not trying
to create life.
Sign and date.
Right.
This process can be hard
on a relationship,
but she'll relax
and things will get better.
We're already divorced.
Good, 'cause she'll
never change.
Up and at 'em.
Follow me, sir.
Just go ahead in and make
yourself comfortable.
You'll find everything
you need in the cabinet.
Thank you.
Uh, wait, Frasier.
It probably doesn't matter, but...
try to think
positive thoughts.
Thanks for that.
I was going to think
about the plight
of the American Indian.
I'm just saying we should put the welfare of the sample first.
Mm-hmm.
Yes?
And don't fall asleep
afterwards.
I want to get
these puppies on ice ASAP.
Good-bye now.
Just a hint.
Lilith!
If there is one thing I can
do by myself,this is it.
Now, go away.
Right this way.
(phone ringing)
What?!
I just remembered
a special method
which supposedly
increases the likelihood
of having a boy.
I see.
Is there something I can do
to increase the likelihood
that we won't have
a nettling control freak?
No, but perhaps you can use a method
which will give us a baby that
can take other people's advice.
I would settle for a method
where it won't turn out
to be a sarcastic prig!
Oh, just do it
Fine.
No, wait.
I don't want you to do it when you're mad
Why don't we just.
take a minute and
sit down and breathe?
It's your dime.
Oh, dear God.
What if this child inherits
all of our flaws
instead of our strengths?
We could create
a real nightmare.
That's not going to happen.
It's going to
be exactly the way
it was the first time.
Is that what's going on
Are we trying to create a baby
or just trying
to recreate the past?
I mean, Frederick's
almost grown now.
It's only natural
to feel a sense of loss.
Frasier, don't be simplistic.
Well, Lilith, I-I know
what you're going through.
You want to feel needed
and loved
as you were when you
were a new mother.
The past can be very seductive.
I mean,
I've fallen into it, too
I'm trying to relive
Freddy's childhood, but.
You can't use the past to fill what's missing in the present.
It's gone.
Frasier, I've
done a lot of thinking
and this feels right to me
But it's not right for me.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
You all right?
fine.
I'll be
If I can't make another
little Frederick with you,
there's always cloning.
And you still don't know when I'm joking.
I... Well, I...
Lilith, what are you
going to do now?
Well, I'm going to go home
and give Frederick a very big hug.
And maybe swab the
inside of his cheek.
Oh, stop that.
Oh, you already ate.
I was going
to take you to Bogart's.
Bogart's?
Oh, don't worry about that
I was just eating it
because it was here.
I wasn't eating it to get full
Just give me two minutes.
(phone ringing)
Hello.
Oh, Niles, darling.
Daphne!
I thought I'd never reach you.
We were booted from the park and are coming home.
It seems someone put out
a cigarette on a stuffed moose.
I didn't know it was stuffed
I was defending myself.
I love those pictures
you left for me.
More specifically, the last one.
Something
a little different, eh?
Indeed, it is.
I can't even believe
you took it.
I didn't take it.
Your father did.
No, I don't think so.
I'm talking about
the last picture on the roll.
The close-up.
Yeah.
Your father was trying
to get a picture of Eddy,
but instead he got
a picture of his own chest.
This is Dad's...
That's his nipple.
(shudders)
Can't wait to get to Bogart's.
I know just what
I'm going to get--
the barbecued
chicken breast
They have
the juiciest one in town.
Or the lamb.
They serve an enormous rack.
That's great.
You might want to get
an overcoat of Frasier's
out of there.
It's supposed to be
pretty nippy tonight.
Oh, hi, Dad.
Where you going?
Hi
Oh, Niles is here.
We're just going out for a bite.
Do you want to join us?
Sure.
So, uh...
how's Lilith?
I just dropped her off
at the airport.
She's disappointed,
but she knows
that we're doing
the right thing.
Well, for what it's worth, I think you are, too, son.
Oh, thanks, Dad.
.
Just hope she finds
what's missing in her life
Hey, Pasty
Oh, hello.
May I?
Yes, certainly.
What happened?
I thought you were
relocating to Seattle.
Uh, it wasn't a fit.
I'm going back to Boston.
I don't know,
call me neurotic.
I just can't work in a lab that's not immaculate.
You work in a lab?
Mmm, I'm a physicist.
Really?
My name's Lilith.
Ah, the demon goddess.
Are you like the, uh..
independent fireball
that was your predecessor?
I make her look
like a vacillating cream puff.
Albert
What happened
with your friend?
Did you get your favor?
It's a long story.
Well, it's, uh...
it's a long flight.