Oh, hey, Roz,
can I join you?
Sure.
Ah, may I have a
latte to go, please?
And I hope they aren't paying
you extra to wear that
No, but I was hoping
it would help with my tips.
Ah, well, as you know
my tipping policy stands firmly
on the twin pillars
of courtesy and efficiency,
but today, I shall include whimsy
.
Merry Christmas.
(chuckling)
God bless you, sir.
Well..
I'm really surprised,
Frasier.
I didn't think you'd go
for something kitschy like that.
At Christmastime,
I say let a thousand antlers
bloom.
Oh, well...
What a relief.
(laughing):
Oh, Roz.
I'm working Santa's Toy Drive
at the mall.
I'm an elf.
Roz, if you needed extra cash,
you should've come to me
.
I've got plenty of odd jobs around the house.
It's not about money.
I'm volunteering.
Oh, oh, well, good for you.
Yes.
Yeah. I mean
visiting Santa Claus
at the department store
was one of my favorite memories
as a kid.
I always found him terrifying
and inquisitorial.
When I was seven,
my mom and dad took me
to the mall to see Santa,
so they were barely talking.
Anyway, when I sat down
on Santa's lap,
I started to cry.
And he was just so nice.
He made me feel safe
and protected.
I don't know, it just made me feel special.
So if I could do that
for just one little kid,
you know, I'd like to do that.
I'm sorry I laughed at you, Roz.
You should be very proud
of yourself.
Thank you.
And I better go
before I'm late.
Oh, right,
you know what?
I'm going, too.
I'll walk with you.
Okay.
(loud jingling)
Actually, Roz,
why don't you just go ahead?
I'm going to get myself a scone.
Oh, hi, guys!
Good to see you.
Hello... hello.
Come in.
Hey, we were hoping to borrow
your wassail bowl.
Oh, I'm sorry, Niles.
I've already loaned it
to Lawrence Emerson
and his madrigal
caroling group.
Well, you can kiss that bowl
good-bye.
Frasier, the Yuletones
are the bad boys
of Renaissance Christmas music.
Have you ever seen
a church common room
after one of
their performances?
Oh.
It's just...
Why don't you just use
the punch bowl?
Well, because then it wouldn't
be wassail, it would be punch.
What's the difference?
DAPHNE:
My dad used to say
that punch makes you want
to kiss the donkey
in the manger scene
and wassail makes you want
to check it into the inn.
(laughing)
That's very funny.
Listen, Daphne,
I was just wondering,
is your mom partial
to a traditional
Cornwall dressing?
You see, I'm thinking
it would go splendidly
with the 12-pound
Hungarian goose
that I'm serving.
Mum is spending Christmas
on a cruise.
An early Christmas present
from Niles.
Yes, I didn't think
she'd go for it,
but apparently,
in international waters,
they can play
single-deck blackjack.
FRASIER:
Oh.
NILES:
Um, actually, Frasier,
Daphne and I would like
to have you over
to our place
for Christmas this year.
Yeah, we just put up our tree
and everything looks
so lovely.
And it is our first Christmas
as a married couple.
Well, as lovely as that
sounds...
Oh, come on,
why not?
Well, Niles, because
it's a little late
to be changing things, isn't it?
Besides, we've always had Christmas here.
It's a tradition!
"Wassail... A Christmas punch."
Frasier, you've had Christmas
for the past nine years.
Yes, but we agreed
when you hosted Thanksgiving
that we would have Christmas
here in its traditional setting.
Maybe it's time
to start a new tradition.
But I've had new stockings loomed for everyone.
Now, there, you see!
You made me spoil the surprise.
And did no one hear me say
I have ordered
an Hungarian goose?!
Which you are more
than welcome
to bring over to our place.
It's not my date.
It's dinner!
Honestly, Niles,
I'm really quite affronted by this.
If it means this much to him,
why don't we just let him keep it?
No... no. There is no reason
why just this once
we can't host Christmas
at the Montana.
Frasier's just being a churl
You're the churl!
You're both a couple of churls!
How about a compromise?
Say, morning at one house,
afternoon
at the other.
Well, that's
a wonderful idea.
But who gets morning
and who gets afternoon?
Morning.
I think Niles
said it first.
(gasps)
Dad, who do you think said it first?
I'm sick of everything being a
contest between you two.
All right then, Dad, you decide
where we're having Christmas
I'm fine with that.
All right, I will.
I need a few days to think about it.
In the meantime,
decision-making is thirsty work.
Sure could use a beer.
Oh, I'll get it.
No!
No, I'll get it.
A little trick
their mom taught me.
Don't worry, Margie,
you don't need a chimney
Santa always finds a way in.
You have a
Merry Christmas now.
Thank you, Santa.
Ho, ho, ho
FRASIER:
Roz...
Hello.
Oh, hi, Frasier.
Listen, when I'm
at the North Pole,
my name is Snowflake.
Anyway, here,
I was in the mall.
I thought I'd drop off
a donation for the toy drive.
Thank you very much.
Is this for us, too?
No, no.
Actually, this is another
dancing Santa for Dad.
His other one got damaged.
I thought you threw that thing
off the balcony.
Yes, which damaged it.
SANTA:
Ho, ho, ho
Well, Polly, what would you like Santa to bring you?
He wouldn't have to bring me anything.
Just show up.
Back off, Twinkle.
I saw him first.
What's this?
Do I sense a little
office romance
here at Santa's Workshop?
(chuckling)
Well, I wouldn't mind.
His name is Rick.
And he's so sweet.
Let me guess--
he's also a hunk.
Well, I wouldn't know.
I haven't seen him
without his Santa get-up yet,
but based on those eyes,
there's definite potential
Ho, ho, ho
Santa needs his favorite helper elf.
Ooh, see that, I'm his favorite.
Down, Snowflake.
I've got this one.
Okay, Twinkle, you go ahead.
Oh, no, is that a zit?
Oh... Snowflake.
oh.
Over here.
Hi.
I just got back
from the costume shop.
I had to get
my toes re-curled.
Ah, yes.
Which reminds me..
how are things with Mr. Claus?
Oh, well, I haven't had a chance to ask him out yet.
What's the matter?
Low elf-esteem?
How long have you been waiting
to say that?
Two days.
I almost called you.
What's this?
Niles with Dad
I knew it.
Oh, you guys aren't still
fighting about Christmas.
He's fighting, I'm not fighting.
Well, what is the big deal?
Why don't you let him
have Christmas?
Because it's just so unfair.
What's not fair?
Oh, you wouldn't understand.
Well, come on, Frasier,
talk to me.
Use your words.
It's just so egregious.
Smaller words.
I don't know.
Okay, look, it just seems
that Niles is systematically
emptying my home.
We used to have Thanksgiving
dinner there... gone.
Daphne... gone.
If I let him have Christmas,
I'll have nothing left.
Just end up some
doddering old bachelor
sipping tea and keeping the
apartment at a balmy 78 degrees!
And how is that different
from now?
Excuse me.
I smell skullduggery afoot
Hey, Dad.
Hey, Fras.
New thermos?
.
Niles, I never thought you'd stoop so low
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Just buying Dad some coffee
before driving him to work.
You are trying to bribe Dad
to have Christmas at your place.
Oh, and what about you
buying him the dancing Santa?
A surprising gift
considering you threw his last
one off the balcony.
(gasps):
You did what?
That Santa never did anything to hurt you.
All he ever did was dance
and try to make people happy.
Yes, yes... all right, Dad.
Why'd you do it?
All right!
Why do you have to make
everything so difficult?
Excuse me, Niles,
but I've got news for you.
Copernicus called, and you are
not the center of the universe!
All right, you two,
knock it off.
Let's just settle this now.
Sit down.
Dad, make your decision.
You know, I'm really
disappointed in you guys.
I thought if I gave you
a little time,
you'd be mature enough
to work this out on your own.
Well, you were wrong!
All right, you know what?
I just made my decision.
I'm working Christmas.
Jimmy Daley asked me
to take his shift,
and I'm going to do it
because he'll be happier
with his family
than I am with mine.
Oh, Dad, you
can't be serious.
No, no, wait...
just calm down
and discuss this rationally.
No. It's too late.
And you don't need
to drive me to work,
I'll call a cab.
I hope you two are happy.
You've ruined Christmas!
MAN:
What a jerk!
(booing and hissing)
Not nice.
Dad...
Uh, Niles and I
would like to apologize.
It was untoward of us to argue
over where to have Christmas.
Yeah. Our conduct
was self-absorbed and boorish.
Not that we deserve it, but
please accept our apologies.
Apologies accepted.
Oh, thank you, Dad
So you'll have
Christmas with us?
Oh, I'm afraid I can't.
I promised Jimmy I'd work,
and I can't go back on it.
When do you start?
6:00 a.m.,
12-hour shift.
It's double time,
so I'm not complaining.
No, that's the whole day.
JERRY:
Marty, I need you
to let maintenance
into the electrical closet
on seven.
Will do.
See you boys later
Bye, Dad.
Wow...
(sighs)
Christmas without Dad.
It just won't be
Christmas.
I know. He's always
the first one under the tree.
Mom always said
that he was her biggest kid
because he could never wait
to open his presents.
(chuckles)
Oh, he always puts on a brave face,
but I know he especially
misses Mom at Christmas.
Niles...
where is it written
that we have to have Christmas
at either of our homes?
The Thanksgiving Accord of 2002.
is,
No, no. What I'm saying
since Dad has to work, why can't
we bring the holiday to him?
You mean... just show up
and surprise him?
I like that.
We can bring all our gifts,
and food!
Oh, better yet, what if
the gifts were already here.
But...
Okay, here's what I'm thinking.
All right...
Take the gifts that are here,
put them under the tree
at my house.
Get the real gifts
and bring them here,
all unbeknownst to Dad.
Brilliant.
Can't you just see us
casually stopping by
on Christmas morning?
"Hello, Dad, Merry Christmas.
"Oh, it's such a shame
that you have to spend Chri...
"Hello?"
What's this I spy?
A present for Martin?
(imitating Martin):
"That's not for me,
those are fake."
one.
"Well, here's another
"And one for Niles.
And one for Daphne."
"Oh, geez, it's a miracle."
Oh, Niles, it'll be the best Christmas we ever had.
Look, I'm getting goose bumps.
Oh, no, Niles, that's your pine rash.
You're too close to the tree.
Hey... Hi, Roz.
It's me, Rick.
Oh, my God, Rick,
I didn't even recognize you.
Roz and I volunteer
down at the mall together.
Rick plays Santa.
Daphne, this is Rick.
Rick, Daphne.
Oh, Roz has told me
all about you.
Would you like to join us?
I'd love to, but I have
to get back to my day job.
Oh, what do you do?
I'm an investment banker
Could you excuse me
for one second?
Wow, Roz, you never told me
he was so gorgeous.
Oh, I've never seen him
out of his costume before.
He's successful
and he's got great taste.
Those shoes... Enrico Zaglionis.
Niles is teaching me.
Very nice to meet you, Daphne.
I'll see you tonight, Roz?
Maybe we can
take our break together.
I snuck a bottle of schnapps
into my locker.
Yeah... maybe.
Something wrong?
You don't like schnapps?
No! No, it's just so strange to see you
without your beard
You really should grow one
It'll make your eyes twinkle.
Ah, I tried once.
It kind of came in in tufts.
I looked like a dog on Rogaine.
(all chuckle)
(Rick laughs)
What was that?
I laughed.
That's your laugh?
Yeah.
Wow, at the mall, it's so booming.
I know, I hate that.
It really kills my throat.
Very nice to meet you.
Bye-bye.
I'll see you later.
Bye.
Why are you being so weird?
He seems perfect.
I don't know.
Just wasn't what I was expecting.
Something's missing.
Like what?
I don't know.
You know what?
At the mall,
he has all this warmth,
and he's got this jolly
sense of humor.
Oh, you should see him
when he laughs.
His whole stomach shakes.
Oh, my God, you're in love with Santa Claus.
No, I' not.
Well, it makes sense
when you think about it.
Santa's the perfect man.
He's a good listener,
he likes to travel,
gives great presents.
Give me a break.
Admit it.
You want the jelly belly.
Okay, don't be gross.
You want to bang boots
with the big boy.
(laughs)
I got to get to work.
You want to get your paws
on the Claus, is more like it.
Stop it, Daphne.
That's enough!
One more.
You're a ho, ho, ho.
Ah...
Dad! What are you doing
still sitting there?
I told you ten minutes ago
that we were going out
for some Christmas Eve
ice cream.
Oh, I changed my mind.
Eddie and I are too bloated
from the nog.
Well, then, maybe we should
take Eddie and walk it off.
Come on, mister, let's go.
No, got to be up early
tomorrow morning for work.
Could sure use something
to nibble on though.
No, no, no, no, no!
Stop pushing.
Dad's still here.
I couldn't
get rid of him
You'll have to come back in an hour.
The maintenance man
in Dad's building
was so nervous about us
taking these out of the lobby,
I promised him
we'd have our real gifts
back under his tree by 10:00.
All right, what we need
is a really good distraction.
I'll tell you what.
Knock when you've thought of one
What were you doing out there?
Nothing.
Thought I heard the door knock.
(knocking on door)
Hey, that's pretty good.
Oh. Hello, guys.
Dad, look who it is.
It's Niles and Daphne.
I see them.
So what brings you two here?
Good question, Frasier.
Daphne?
I need your father's help
with a present.
And that's what
we're doing here.
Exactly. Yes.
Come on, Martin,
we can do this in my old room.
No problem.
Okay, now.
Real presents go out in the hall
by the door.
Fake presents under the tree.
Niles, did you notice
my Christmas village?
Would you like to see smoke waft
out of the cobbler's chimney?
Maybe later.
Frasier, I have to warn you.
These prop boxes are heavy.
Some idiot weighed them down
with bricks.
Just our luck we get the only
method lobby decorator
in all of Seattle.
How much time do you think
Daphne can buy us with Dad?
Not much.
They're just putting batteries
in the digital camera
we're giving you.
Act surprised.
Right.
DAPHNE (loudly):
I said I'd get them.
You'll never find them.
How could you ask me
to put batteries in
and not bring any batteries?
(gasps):
Now, boys, you know the rules.
No shaking the presents.
You see, Niles, I told you.
Found them. Let's go.
(softly):
Daphne!
No more surprises.
Oh, you mean like
finding your father here
when the apartment's
supposed to be empty?
Well, you can blame that
on the nog.
.
Frasier, I don't think
I'm going to sleep tonight
I feel like I'm ten years old.
Only this time we had the merry task
of being Santa.
Niles, I'm so sorry
that we almost
ruined Christmas..
Stop. Stop.
What?
I just took that
from under the tree.
No, you didn't
Yes, I did.
I know, 'cause that's real.
And all the fake ones are out
in the pile by the door.
By the elevator door?
No, by the apartment door.
That's where
all the fake ones are.
Great.
Now what do we do?
Oh, here, all right.
You take these.
Yes.
Give me these.
What are we...?
Where do we go?
How the hell should I know?
MARTIN:
That's a flat head and I need a Phillips head
NILES:
See, I told you
if you rearrange them
they'd look fuller.
Yes, yes, I see
what you mean, Niles.
It's all a matter
of perspective.
Wow, looks like twice as many.
Put them back the way they were
and show me how you did that.
Got the Phillips.
Let's go.
He could be an assassin in those slippers.
Are you two going
to switch the presents
or are you going
to stand around arguing
about whose Christmas village
is bigger?
(gasps):
I knew it.
You didn't compliment mine
because you have one, too.
I didn't compliment yours
because yours
is so poorly laid out.
All right, we don't have time for this.
Now which ones are which?
I've got it all organized.
Here, take them out.
Are you sure?
Yes, absolutely.
These are the real ones.
These go to Dad,
out in the hall.
And we'll
take them together.
Fine, all right.
Good. You go. Fine
And then, here...
Now we're all set.
All the fake ones
are under the tree.
Yes, you put those in the elevator.
.
I'll tell Daphne
the coast is clear
Do you have any idea
how much I paid for that?
Well, it's not my fault.
Those little plastic hinges
snap off if you look at them.
Now what am I supposed to give as a gift now?
Oh, stop crying.
Just put a little duct tape
on, it'll be good as new.
It was new
Here, Daphne, I'll help you find the tape.
(Eddie barks)
What's the matter, boy?
Too much eggnog, huh?
Okay.
Hey, Daph... be sure and use
the silver duct tape
not the brown.
The silver will match
the camera.
Oop. I mean, uh, the present.
I'm taking Eddie for a walk.
Wait! Dad!
I'll do that.
You should just relax.
No, that's all right.
I need the fresh air.
Oh.
What's this? More presents?
Is this why you were trying
to keep me busy back there?
Yes.
(laughs)
Oh.
Well, you didn't need
to do that.
Bring them on in.
Frasier,
give your brother a hand.
Mix them all up
so it'll look fuller.
(doorbell rings)
Merry Christmas.
Niles.
Hi.
So how are you?
Well, tired
and a little poorer.
I had to bribe
the maintenance man
at Dad's building to get him to stay late.
Oh, which reminds
me, on your next show,
you have to give something called a "shout-out"
to a Steve Gomez.
Right.
DAPHNE:
This is so exciting.
I can't wait to see the look
on your father's face
when we go over there
and surprise him.
Merry Christmas!
Dad... what are you doing here?
Yeah, aren't you supposed
to be at work?
The boss called.
I don't have to go in.
Seems he was feeling guilty
about my missing Christmas
with my family.
Ooh.
Heavy.
This must be a good one.
Unless it's a book.
But who's covering
the desk?
Nobody.
She's shut down tight
till tomorrow.
Now I have just enough patience
to wait for cocoa
before I start
tearing into these.
Um... Dad...?
Don't tell me there's no cocoa.
(knocking on glass)
Hello?
Hello?!
You'd think there'd
be a custodian
or someone
in there.
Ah, I knew
it was a long shot.
Won't be anybody in
till tomorrow morning.
Sorry, Dad.
Oh, forget it.
That was a really
sweet gesture.
Would've been terrific, but...
I've already received my gift.
You know..
we could throw a brick through the glass...
but they're all wrap
ped up under our tree.