Here we are.
File A, slide sheet one,
image one
of subject
Frederick G. Crane.
Mom...
Here you are just
an hour after being
wrestled from
my grudging womb.
Gross.
You know, if you like
there's still time
to include this
in your Bar Mitzvah video.
Thanks.
But I just want to get
through this thing
with as little
humiliation as possible.
Oh, look at this.
Your hospital cap.
The very combed cotton
that swaddled your little...
(voice breaking):
...head.
Are you okay?
Of course I am.
It's only natural that
there should be
some emotional upheaval caused
by the impending shift
in our relationship.
I knew it would come--
I just wasn't expecting
such a roller coaster.
All done.
Is this your guest list?
Oh, I didn't realize
you wanted to invite
so many friends.
I don't even know
some of these people.
And why are you inviting
Jeremy Berman?
I thought you told me he's the biggest nerd in your class.
He's not so bad.
Besides, the more people you invite
the more presents you get.
Frederick...
A Bar Mitzvah is
a rite of passage,
not an opportunity
for you to collect presents.
I'm sorry. You're right.
I'll try to trim it down.
KENNY:
Hey, Doc.
Kenny.
I can't tell you
how touched I am
that Freddie invited me
to his Bar Mitzvah.
He did?
Yeah.
What a great kid.
That's your son, right?
Yes.
I wasn't aware that you two had met.
We haven't.
I guess he's probably heard
his share of Kenny stories.
(chuckling)
From whom?
You sly kidder.
It sounds like a hoot,
but if I don't find someone
to drive with me to Boston
and share a tent on the way
I probably won't
be able to afford to go.
Hmm.
Fun drive, I bet.
I guess I can just
send him something.
I think he'd like that.
Thanks, Kenny.
Hey, Dr. Crane,
Mazel Tov.
Hey, Frasier.
Hi, Roz.
Freddie's so sweet.
He sent me an invitation
to his Bar Mitzvah.
Yes.
apparently the people
of Washington State
have made
quite an impression on him.
Can you believe Freddie
is 13 years old already?
I can hardly think about it
without choking up.
This is my son, Roz.
The little bald candy man
that used to fit right here
in the crook of my arm
Little bald candy man.
That's adorable.
I had a boyfriend
who called hi...
Is it weird to have a son
brought up in a different
religion from yours?
Not at all, Roz.
It's a faith that espouses
love, compassion, duty,
education and art.
All values which I cherish.
And though I have played
a relatively small role
in his spiritual developme
nt, he has honored me
by asking that I say
a few words.
And in the spirit
of the occasion
I'm going to try
to learn it in Hebrew.
Oh...
Hi, Dr. Crane.
Hi, No
Hi, Roz.
You've never worn that sweater
on a Tuesday before.
I've asked you to take your hands
out of your pockets
when you talk to me.
So, I don't think I can make the Bar Mitzvah.
Great.
I mean that sarcastically,
of course, Noel.
Great! You're not coming! Terrific!
Yeah, sorry. Did I
overhear you say you
want to learn Hebrew?
...
Uh
Not learn it.
I'm saving that pleasure
for retirement.
But I have composed a speech
and I'd like to say it
in Hebrew.
Well, I can translate and teach
you how to say it if you want.
You can? Really?
Oh, Noel, thank you.
Of course, I'll expect a little
something quid pro quo.
Certainly.
Whatever you'd like.
Great.
The Seattle Star Trek
convention is this weekend
and all the Enterprise captains
are making an appearance.
I need Scott Bakula's autograph
to make my collection complete.
Noel, isn'’t this something you could do yourself?
Oh, I would, but
William Shatner's
restraining order against me
is still in effect.
It's so stupid.
It wasn't even a real phaser
Noel, don't you have any friends
that could
do this for you?
Trust me, there are no friends
in the world
of Star Trek autography.
I see.
Well then, consider it done.
Oh!
Thank you
so much. Now...
be sure to keep it
in this acid-free covering
until the actual signing.
And if you must handle it,
use these cotton gloves.
Okay.
You'll be the hit
of the Bar Mitzvah,
I promise.
And don't be surprised
if you get caught up
in all the fun
of the convention, too.
I'll try to pace myself.
Thanks again,
Dr. Crane.
Noel..
how did you know I would do it?
What do you mean?
Well, you must have known
I would do this for you,
or you wouldn't be
carrying around
a picture of Scott Bakula,
right?
Right.
Hey, Niles, think fast
(flashbulb pops)
Oh!
Dad!
What is that?
My good old Scheerblad-7XK.
The blindingest, noisiest,
15-pound camera
every produced
in the former Soviet Union.
MARTIN:
Can you believe it?!
Somehow it got buried
deep down in storage.
But Eddie and
I found it
just in time
for the Bar Mitzvah.
What smells like
burning plastic?
Oh, that means
the flash unit's working
I thought
the retinue-scorching flash
meant that the flash unit
was working.
Not always.
I still remember the night
of my junior prom.
Ooh... Dad wanted to get
a nice close-up
of me and Margaret Coover.
Unfortunately, he got
a little too close and the
heat from the flash
seared the gold plating
off Margaret's necklace
onto her skin.
You never mentioned
Margaret Coover before.
I didn't?
Margaret Coover.
Petite, brunette...
gilded.
(flashbulb pops)
Dear God,
the old flash-and-wind.
NILES: Yes.
Dad found it.
Yeah, good thing, too.
Hasn't failed me yet.
Oh, well, except for that one
Thanksgiving
when the flash washed Lilith out
so bad
all you could see
were her hair and eyes.
That wasn't the camera's
fault, Dad.
That bloodless skin has
confounded even the most
experienced photographer.
Hey, Daph, do you know
where the tripod is?
I might need it
for group shots.
Yeah, I think it's in
the back of your closet.
Come on, I'll help
you look for it.
Sherry, Frasier?
Please, Niles.
I have good news.
Hmm?
I have two tickets
to the Udo Fritzenheim show
at the museum tomorrow.
(gasps)
Not to mention
an invitation for lunch
with the artist afterwards.
Oh!
Are you serious?!
Niles, lunch
with a Dada master.
Oh, I'd love to come...
but I can't.
I have other plans.
m,
I promised Noel Shempsky
that I'd do a favor for him
and I've got to remain
true to my word.
Although, perhaps,
I could go to the show
leave the luncheon early and...
and still fulfill my commitment.
Oh, yes, of course you could.
Yeah, you're
right, Niles.
There...
You know...
it was at a Fritzenheim show
in Boston
where Freddie first said
the word "Dada."
I remember swelling
with pride
thinking that perhaps
he was an art history savant.
But, of course, Lilith
deflated my enthusiasm
by pointing out that he was
probably just referring to me.
Fras, good news--
found the tripod.
Oh. Splendid.
It's tough to watch your kids grow up.
Well, he's... he's
still just a boy.
He's only 13.
It goes fast.
How's Lilith taking it?
Well, I
suppose it's a bittersweet experience for her.
I can't really say for sure,
you know.
She's always been rather guard
ed with her emotions.
Not always, Frasier.
I've seen her get
quite emotional.
I'm sure you have,
Mr. Been-There-Done-That.
What does that mean?
Nothing.
What are you hiding?
Oh...
Um... some years ago..
In a complete drunken stupor.
Totally stinko.
NILES:
Yes.
I had an unplanned
and instantly regretted night
ofamore...
...with Lilith.
A one-nighter?
Ofamore.
Lilith?
Well, it w...
it was after Maris
And it was long before you.
In fact, it's pretty funny
when you think about it.
(nervous laughter)
And remember, I was drunk.
You'd have to be,
wouldn't you?
Sorry, Frasier.
No, no, drinking definitely
took the edge off.
Um, when were you planning
on sharing this interesting bit
of information with me?
Soon.
Very soon.
Never.
Well, what's
done is done.
I suppose we've all had
our romantic missteps.
But just to be clear--
are there any more
secret sweethearts
who I see on a regular basis?
No. Nobody.
Nobody?
Nobody
I certainly wouldn't count Anamari Hanratty
at the Natural History Museum.
Frasier?!
I said I wouldn't count her.
I mean... they just made out.
It was for charity.
It doesn't really matter.
I mean, the woman
makes out with everyone.
She's not really the kind
of person that you'd...
(yelling)
Hi, Dr. Crane.
Oh, hi, Noel.
Ready for Yeshiva tomorrow?
That means school.
Yes, indeed I am.
I'm looking forward to it.
Uh, listen, Noel,
I'm afraid I have some, uh..
very bad news about
the science fiction convention.
Uh-oh.
Long story short,
you see, I attended an art opening
and a luncheon on Saturday
and even though I left the luncheon early
the traffic on the way to
the convention was just awful
and by the time I got there
Mr. Bakula and all the others
had gone.
No...!
You made a promise
and you welshed on it.
Why'd you do it, Dr. Crane?
It's not really such a big deal,
is it, Noel?
It's a huge deal.
Who knows when I'll get to see Scott Bakula again?
I'll be the laughing stock of my clan.
Noel, try to rem...clan?
No, never mind,
never mind. Noel..
surely you realize that
Star Trek is just a TV show.
So was Brideshead Revisited.
You're angry.
So I'm going to ignore that
But with all due respect, Noel,
perhaps weaning yourself
off science fiction
might be the first step
toward achieving a genuine,
meaningful, grown-up person's life.
Just a friendly suggestion.
You're right.
You did your best
and that's good enough for me.
Thank you, Noel.
So, you'll still be my tutor?
Sure.
Good man.
Thanks, Noel.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Oh, yes, you will
see me tomorrow.
And by the rings
of Septaurus Five
you will pay, Dr. Crane.
You-- Oh, hi, Kenny--
will pay.
Okay, Eddie,
hit the talk button.
And you're listening
to the Best of Crane on KACL.
We'll be back
after these messages.
(station ID theme music plays)
(door opens)
Well, well, the fox and the hound working together.
How ironic
I'm just taking care of him
until Frasier gets back
from Boston.
By the way,
he left you something.
He did?
Yeah.
Whoa. A wig?
That's cruel,
even for Frasier.
Cruel? It's only the wig Joan Collins wore
in Star Trek 28.
"City on the Edge of Forever."
It's probably still got her DNA in it.
"Dear Noel, I hope
this begins to repay you
"for your great kindness to me,
"especially in light
of my negligence.
Your friend, Frasier Crane."
He called me "friend"?
That's really sweet of him
I've got to call him
before he delivers his speech.
You taught him dirty words
in Hebrew, didn't you?
Uh, not quite.
They're the same words,
but they're in Klingon.
From Star Trek?
That's not even real.
It's the fastest-growi
ng language on the planet.
This is what you people don't understand.
A man named Gene Roddenberry
had a vision...
Call him!
FREDERICK:
♪♪Yit-ba-rach shim-cha
bi'’’fi kol chai♪♪
♪♪Tamid, l'’’o-lam va-ed♪♪
♪♪Ba-ruch a-tah, A-do-nai♪♪
♪
♪♪M'’’ka-deish ha-Sha-bat♪
♪♪Amen.♪♪
.
Yasher Koach,Frederick
That was a beautiful passage
and a wonderful reading.
You honor us all by including..
(cell phone rings)
Oh.
You honor us all
by including us in
this important occasion,
but you have chosen to especially honor your parents
Lilith and Frasier
by asking them
to conclude this ceremony.
Lilith?
Thank you. Uh...
(flashbulb pops)
Excuse me.
Would the photographer
please refrain from
taking any more pictures
until after the ceremony is over?
MARTIN:
Sorry, Rabbi.
LILITH:
Thank you.
I am very proud to participate
in the coming-of-age ritual
of my son Frederic
k Gaylord Crane.
(snickering)
Oh.
Frederick, on this momentous occasion
I can only look at you
and see that innocent, chubby-legged toddler
who once danced naked at the Boston Pops
The little boy whose
favorite meal was
"buh-sghetti."
I can't count the number of bedtimes
we spent cuddled together
reading The Cat in the Hat.
"The sun did not shine,
it was too wet to play,
"so we sat in the house
"
on that cold,
cold, wet day.
(crying)
Don'’’t grow up!
Not yet!
Nice girlfriend
you've got there.
Not yet! Not yet!
If you're trying to embarrass me
it's not going to work.
(choked up):
Come here, Daddy's little peanut man.
It'll be all right.
We will conclude with a blessing
from Frederick's father Frasier,
who, though not of our faith,
has chosen to follow
his son's fine example
and deliver it in Hebrew.
Thank you.
I'll keep this short.
Thanks, Dad.
"Pookh lod wih le koo.
"Hach jahj cho-koov-moakh
"leng-lidge loo-Teb-
"jahj leng widge-vahd bel rahp
"shoave dah-nobe-poo-boagh.
Shabbot Shalom."
Oh, that was lovely.
What was that gobbledy-gook?
Well, it's-it's
a blessing for my son.
"Pookh Lod Wih Le Koo."
That means nothing.
It's gibberish.
What?
That's not gibberish,
it's Klingon.
What?
Oh, dear God.
Freddie's dad
just blessed him in Klingon.
sorry.
I'm... I'm terribly
...
I... I
Will you excuse me, please?
RABBI:
Okay, everybody...
it's better to end with laughter than tears.
I don't know how they say it
in outer space,
but here we say
"ahavaandshalom."
Love and peace
Dinner will be served in
the multi-purpose room
in 20 minutes.
Hey, that was awesome, Gaylord.
Shut up, Berman.
Seriously, your dad's Klingon is really good.
What did he say?
Well, roughly translated, it says
"My dearest son,
each day you redeem me.
"May your journey be
filled with the same joy
wisdom and purpose
you have given mine."
It's a lot more beautiful in the original Klingon.
But it's still really cool.
Which one of us do you suppose
humiliated him more?
Oh, I think I did.
I've been trying to console myself with the idea
that without embarrassing parents
there'd be no psychology.
Poor kid.
Actually, today he is a man.
He is, isn't he?
Mazel Tov.
You must be very proud--
of your son, not yourselves.
We are, thank you, Rabbi.
Frederick, uh, listen,
I-I'm... I want to apologize
Uh, there was this guy
at the radio station
he was going to teach me
Hebrew...
You don't have to
explain it, Dad.
Really?
I just wanted
to tell you how sorry I am.
Berman translated your speech
for me.
It was pretty good.
So, you liked it?
Yeah.
I don't want to get
all mushy or anything--
-
I'm a little old for that now-
but, you know...
Yeah... I know.
(chuckles)
Can you forgive me?
.
Yeah..
for everything
but naming me Gaylord.
That was lovely.
MARTIN:
Hey, everybody,
look this way.
Oh, no...!
No!
♪♪ Hey, baby,
I hear the blues a-calling ♪
♪
♪♪ Tossed salads
and scrambled eggs ♪♪
♪♪ Quite stylish ♪♪
♪♪ And maybe I seem
a bit confused ♪♪
♪♪ Well, maybe,
but I got you pegged ♪♪
(laughs)
♪♪ But I don'’’t know what to do
♪♪
♪♪ With those tossed salad
s and scrambled eggs ♪♪
♪♪ They'’’re calling again
. ♪♪
Frasier has left the building.