Ooh, Niles,
sorry I'm late.
Did you sign us up?
Frasier,
I've been thinking.
How many years
have we teamed up
for the squash tournament
only to be eliminated in the second round?
Nine.
Exactly.
Don't you think
it's time we came up
with a new strategy?
Niles, if you're talking
about taking that powder
that's made from
sheep's glands,
the answer is never again.
Well, actually, I was
thinking of something
more fundamental.
It occurs to me that
after nine years...
Shh-shh, Niles,
here comes that two-faced
braggart, Jim Blake.
Jim, looking good.
Thanks, Frasier, thanks.
So, you signed up
for the tournament?
Uh, I don't know.
Have we, partner?
Awesome, awesome.
Let's do it.
I'll see you
on the court, bro.
It's not what
it looks like.
It's exactly
what it looks like.
You've teamed up
with someone younger
and in better shape.
No, Frasier, you know I don't care
about such superficial things
You know, that Jim
is bad news.
He struts around here
in those ridiculous looking
Swedish goggles
that everybody thinks
are so cool.
Jim...
You know, I just wish
you'd told me sooner
instead of waiting
until the last minute.
Does Jim know you're
passive-aggressive?
Believe me, neither Jim nor I expected this to happen.
Our games just meshed.
We would've
teamed up sooner
but the timing
was never right.
Either Jim was with a squash partner
or I was playing with you...
Fine, go, just go, go,
go to your new partner.
I don't care.
Who needs you?
Niles...
Don't forget to wear
your wrist brace.
You know how easily you sprain.
Hi... Frasier.
Chelsea Gray.
We met a few
months ago.
Oh.. yes!
You were kicking
the Gatorade machine.
Of course,
I remember.
I had inserted my dollar bill
with Washington's face up, as per the diagram
and was vended nothing
Did you ever write that letter?
Indeed, I did.
The matter still pends
Ah.
So did you sign up
for the tournament?
Well, I was going to,
but, uh...
I just found out
my customary partner
has made other plans this year.
Well, would you
be interested in playing mixed doubles?
I'm a girls' PE teacher
so it'd be nice to play
with a guy for a change.
Thanks for the offer, but after
what I've just been through,
I'm not sure I'm ready
to partner up again.
That's too bad.
I've seen you play.
We'd make a good team.
You already resorting to playing
with the girls, Frasier?
(chuckles):
No offense, sweetie.
(clicks tongue)
Excuse me.
(screeches):
Ow!
Nice shot, partner.
Here we are.
Hello, all.
Hi.
You'll never guess who just won their squash tournament.
If only we had a big, shiny clue.
MARTIN:
Oh, hey, that's great news.
Congratulations.
Well, I owe it all
to my partner.
Oh, thank you, partner
But I think it's really due to our partnership
Aha, well...
now you know what they say,
there's no "I" in "team."
Like there is in "Niles."
FRASIER:
So here, Dad...
check it out.
Wow, would you look at that
I didn't think
I'd ever see the day
one of my boys
would win a trophy
that didn't have a book on it.
Now all that's left
on my list
is shake hands with Hank Aaron,
kiss Sally Field on the mouth
and then I can go on
and be with your mother.
You know, Jim and I may have
our own trophy soon.
We're still alive in
the men's doubles bracket.
Oh, please, Niles,
your partner couldn't
be carrying you any more
if he put you in a Snugli
and strapped you
to his stomach.
Well, I'm proud of
both of you.
And squash might not be
the toughest of sports
but it's still
technically a sport.
CHELSEA:
What?
Squash can be pretty tough.
Ha.
Oh, no, n-no, no.
I once saw a guy break his leg
in a mid-court collision.
The bone was poking
through his skin
and he still finished the point.
That's the game you guys play?
Hell, yeah.
CHELSEA:
Frasier.
do you mind if I use
your phone?
No, of course not.
Come use the one
in the other room.
That'll give you some privacy.
After you, my lady.
You know, Dad, when Jim and I
win our trophies,
I think I'm going
to give mine to you.
Thank you, son.
But I don't want you
moping around here
if your brother wins one
and you don't.
Oh, please, Dad, I'm a little
more mature than that.
No, you're not.
It still bugs you that his name
comes first alphabetically.
Well, that was your fault.
Your girlfriend seems nice.
She is nice,
but she's certainly
not my girlfriend.
I do find her attractive, but...
I'm not sure I'm anything
more than a teammate to her.
Well, from what I've seen, I'd say she likes you a lot.
Really?
She did kiss me once.
But I think that was just
in an overflow of emotion
after one of our victories.
You know, I suppose that happens
all the time on sports teams.
It doesn't.
Of course, I can't speak
for the Canadian leagues.
Well, truth be told,
now that there's not
the excitement of the tournament
to fuel the fires...
I don't think we really
have much in common
in the real world.
You have your
ostentatious trophies.
Well, it was good seeing you
all, but I have to get going.
Oh, so soon?
You just got here.
I have an early faculty meeting.
FRASIER:
I'll walk you out.
MARTIN: Come back!
DAPHNE:
Bye-bye.
Bye.
Congratulations.
Well, I, uh.
I certainly had a great
time the last few weeks.
Yeah, me, too.
Call me again, if you
want to play sometime.
I don't suppose you'd
to take this to the next level?
Oh, I gave up my
dream of professional squash years ago.
That's not what I meant.
Um... maybe I could think of
another way to put it.
Oh, hi, Daph.
Hey, I didn't expect
to see you here.
Niles said you were
going out with Chelsea.
Oh, yes, yes-- I just thought I'd stopby
for a quick pick-me-
up before I pick her up
Does she laugh
at that kind of stuff?
You know, she does
Hold on to this one.
I intend to.
Uh, espresso, please.
You know, every day I learn something new about her.
She enjoys reading
poetry in the bath
She's an excellent cook.
It's like she's
the perfect girl for me.
Well, I think you make
a lovely couple.
Even though Niles can't believe you're dating a gym teacher.
He says it's a betrayal
of your younger selves.
It's perfectly understandable
We didn't have much luck with gym
teachers when we were kids.
They were always
so derisive and
ego-crippling.
There was this one
in particular, Coach Fuller..
he was the worst.
The kind of man that would make the whole class wait
while you did your push-up
It was just so traumatizing,
I would actually lose my
lunch before gym period.
Except on those days when my lunch money was stolen.
Then I'd just dry heave.
Niles has tons
of stories like that.
You know...
perhaps getting to know Chelsea
will help Niles to exorcise his
demons and put them behind him.
He's running out of room
back there.
Hey, Roz.
Hey, Daphne.
Hey, Frasier.
Hi, Roz.
You all right?
I was fine until I saw
Julia in the parking lot.
Why does she have to come here?
For God's sakes, Roz.
I'm a little tired
of hearing you complain
about Julia all the time.
Why don't you just
give her a chance?
How about her?
and she shows me no respect.
She's mean and arrogant, but not in a funny way, like you.
Could I have
a latte, please?
The woman took
a portion of my show
to do her financial drivel.
You don't hear me complaining
about it all the time.
Now enough is enough.
Julia...
why don't you
come and join us?
Oh, all right.
Thank you.
Hello, Frasier.
Well, isn't this nice?
All right,
it's come to my attention
that there is some tension
between the two of you.
Now, as it is
entirely possible
that we will be spending
a great deal of time together,
I think it's important
that we establish
an environment
of mutual respect.
To that end,
as it is impossible
for the two of you
to communicate at all,
it's time for me to roll up
my sleeves and facilitate.
Finding some common ground
would be the first step.
Perhaps a love of plants,
the seed...
You sure love to hear
yourself talk.
And it's impossible to tune him out.
How can you stand it?
The key is to know
when to say "uh-huh."
FRASIER:
Fine, fine,
all right.
If I am your common ground,
so be it.
Please feel free
to tread upon me.
Uh-huh.
The important thing is
that you're talking.
Communication...
Just go.
Okay, he's gone.
CHELSEA:
Slowly.
Oh.
Be with you
in a minute.
You can wait in my office.
(claps):
Very nice. Nice.
All right,
concentrate.
There we go!
Good!
"Please excuse my daughter Ruby
from PE."
CHELSEA:
Concentrate!
"She has a 'delibitating' disease."
Nice try, Ruby.
(whistle blows)
Okay, who didn't climb rope yet?
Campbell, you're up.
Oh, I'd forgotten how it felt
to sneak a kiss in school.
It always
looked like fun.
So I'll be finished here in a second
and then we can go.
Great, great.
I thought we'd try
this new place I just...
(blows)
Campbell, you're not even trying.
(sighs)
Sorry. You were saying?
Yeah, I read a great review
of this new restaurant.
Apparently
the chef is from...
(bell rings, whistle blows)
No one is leaving
until Campbell climbs the rope!
(
Come on!
You can sleep
through English.
Toughen up,
you can do it.
Let's go, Campbell!
Everybody's waiting.
COACH FULLER:
Come on, Crane!
Nobody is going home
until you haul that fat bucket of lard
to the top.
(cries):
I can't.
Just give me a few minutes
and I'll be ready to go.
Oh, I just need you to do one thing.
Drop and give me 20, Crane.
I beg your pardon?
Could you just round up
the basketballs
and put them in the rack
over there?
Thanks
(whistle blows)
Frasier, Niles has
something
he needs to tell you.
Go on, tell him.
I'm sick of hearing
you complain.
I made a mistake
partnering with Jim.
Our styles never really meshed,
which wasn't my fault,
but that didn't stop him
from losing his temper
during a match,
and he yelled at me.
With you,
it was different.
You brought honor to the game.
Rejoin me, Frasier,
and together we can rekindle
the magic.
Please take him back.
I cannot listen to another draft
of this speech.
I'll see you
at home, sweetie.
Thanks, hon.
Niles, I'll gladly re-team with you
Just like that?
I expected you to gloat
and rub it in, make me suffer.
Don't you care?
Oh, my apologies, Niles.
It's just that I'm a little distracted about something
that happened yesterday
at Chelsea's school.
I'm sorry,
but that reminds me--
Chelsea sent me
the sweetest gift
after Jim and I were
eliminated from
the tournament.
It's an actual squash
with a smiley face drawn on it.
That's cute.
You know, when you
first started dating her,
I couldn't get past the fact that she was a gym teacher.
But she's proven to be
nothing like I expected.
Kudos to you.
Well, not sure I deserve
such praise.
No, no, don't be so modest, Frasier.
You truly have a gift
for seeing the inner beauty
in a person.
I do try.
Speak of the devil.
Here's Dad
and Chelsea now.
MARTIN:
Hey, guys.
Look who I ran into.
NILES:
Hello, Dad.
Hi, Chelsea.
Niles.
Hello, sweetie.
NILES:
That's a lovely
outfit.
Really?
You think so, huh?
I thought it might be
a little racy,
but then I thought,
what the hell.
What do you think, Frasier?
Oh, it's very.
.. very becoming.
CHELSEA:
Thank you.
Just let me grab a drink
and we'll be ready to go.
I usually stay out
of your love affairs, son,
but you've got
a good one here.
Definitely a keeper.
Yes, and might I add--
and excuse my gutter speak--
hubba, hubba.
Back to our best behavior.
There's a lady present.
ie.
I'm ready, sweet
"Love is a smoke raised
from the fume of sighs,
being purged, a fire
sparkling in lovers' eyes..."
You all right?
What?
I'm fine.
CHELSEA:
All right, good.
"I am a vessel,
"come tenderly
and fill me
with the nectar
of your love."
So I figure since
you're the financial guru,
you could help me out.
Now obviously, I don't want to get involved in
some get-rich-quick scheme,
but I do need to make
a lot of money really fast.
So what do you got?
I don't like to talk about work
when I'm outside the office.
Oh.
Thank you.
Right.
Me neither
Hey, there's Roz.
Hey, Roz, come join us.
I don't think so.
No, no, no, I won't take no for an answer.
Now you sit down.
Hi, Julia.
Roz.
Well, I know girl talk
when I hear it. Bye.
I'll go this time.
Thanks.
You know, maybe Frasier
was right.
Would it kill us
to make some effort to be civil?
I guess not.
Thanks
So
Your show was good today.
Yes, it was.
And...
and your producing
was top-notch.
Thanks
Sugar?
Please.
Well, this isn't so bad.
No, it's not.
Maybe we just got off
on the wrong foot.
Well, when you first started,
I just thought you were
kind of a bitch
for ordering everyone around.
That's totally my fault.
I have a tendency
to be patronizing
to entry-level
employees.
Well, you know, I was going to say something earlier,
but when I heard
your first show,
I figured you wouldn't
be here long.
Well, you certainly made
an impression on me.
I remember, I kept thinking,
"Who did she sleep with
to get this job?"
And then I found out.
Everybody.
That's a good one.
(chuckling)
You know, there's
a plunger in the bathroom.
What do you say we go look
for your career?
Great.
While we're in there,
I can get your phone number.
Don't bother.
It's 1-800-BITE ME.
Bite me?
That's the best that you've got?
Oh, I could spend half an hour
on your hair.
Well, you should have spent
a half an hour on your hair.
Oh, really?
It's closing time,
ladies.
I'm afraid
you'll have to leave.
But we're
just warming up.
You know, there's
a place down the street
that is open all night.
Just like your mouth?
Just like your legs.
Hey, wait up.
So, we're just going to go to sleep, huh?
I'm really tired.
You sure you don't want to watch TV
or get something to eat?
No.
I know someone
who's ticklish.
No, stop, stop, stop!
Okay, Frasier, you've been acting weird all day.
What's going on?
Well, it's a little
complicated.
What is?
Is there a problem?
Yes, Chelsea, there is.
It disturbed me yesterday
when I saw you yelling at
that little girl on the rope.
I couldn't believe
how harsh you were.
And you may not realize it,
but that can have
a crippling effect on a child.
What?!
I didn't think I was being excessively harsh.
I was just trying
to motivate her.
Yes, well, the way
you were shouting,
it was hard to tell.
And when you're a child,
all you know is
you're being singled out
I have no right to tell you
how to do your job.
It's, uh... it's my problem, not yours.
No, no.
You may have a point.
Maybe... I do push too hard.
Sometimes I forget
just how fragile kids can be.
Really?
You agree with me?
Yes, I do.
Thank you, Frasier
It's sweet of you to care so much.
Well, you're worth
caring about.
Now, come on.
Let's go have a nice,
romantic dinner.
Okay, all right.
Let me just
go get ready.
You know,
when I heard you shouting
at that little girl today,
I swear, it just brought back
a flood of memories
from my own childhood.
Really?
Oh, yeah.
You know,
my gym teacher
was constantly yelling at me
because I couldn't do
a single pull-up
or a lap
around the track.
Not even one?
Oh, please.
I was a
very late bloomer.
I could barely do
a jumping jack
without getting
a nosebleed.
And let's not begin
to talk about
the climbing rope.
There we go,
all done.
Well...
What do you say I get us
a table at Petite Auberge?
They do an excellent veal chop.
Okay.
After you, milady.
♪♪ Hey, baby,
I hear the blues a-calling ♪
♪
♪♪ Tossed salads
and scrambled eggs ♪♪
♪♪ Oh, my! ♪♪
♪♪ And maybe I seem
a bit confused ♪♪
♪♪ Yeah, maybe,
but I got you pegged ♪♪
(laughs)
♪♪ But I don'’’t know what to do
♪♪
♪♪ With those tossed salad
s and scrambled eggs ♪♪
♪♪ They'’’re calling again
. ♪♪
Scrambled eggs
all over my face.
What is a boy to do?
Good night, Seattle!
We love you!